[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音樂]
>> DAVID J. MALAN: All right, this is CS50.
>> DAVID J. MALAN：好吧，這是CS50。
And this is week one.
而這是一個星期。
So recall that last time in week zero, we focused on computational thinking.
所以，記得最後一次是在零一周， 我們專注於計算思維。
And we transitioned from that to Scratch, a graphical programming
而我們從轉變，要 從無到有，圖形化編程
language from our friends at MIT's Media Lab.
從我們的朋友的語言 在麻省理工學院的媒體實驗室。
>> And with Scratch, did we explore ideas like functions, and conditions,
>> 並與划痕，沒有我們探討 想法一樣的功能，和條件，
and loops, and variables, and even events, and threads, and more.
和循環，和變量，甚至 事件，以及線程，以及更多。
And today, we're going to continue using those ideas,
而今天，我們要 繼續使用這些想法，
and really taking them for granted, but translate them
真正帶他們 理所當然，但他們翻譯
to another language known as C. Now, C is a more traditional language.
被稱為現在C.另一種語言， C是一個更傳統的語言。
It's a lower level language, if you will.
這是一個較低的水平 語言，如果你願意。
>> It's purely textual.
>> 這純粹是文字。
And so at first glance, it's all going to look rather cryptic
所以乍看之下，它的 一切都將看起來相當神秘
if you've never programmed before.
如果你從來沒有編程。
We're going to have semi-colons, and parentheses,
我們將有 分號和括號，
and curly braces, and more.
和大括號，等等。
But realize that even though the syntax is
但是認識到，即使 雖然語法
about to look a little unfamiliar to most of you, see past that.
即將看起來有點陌生 大多數的你，看過去那種。
And try to see the ideas that are, indeed, familiar,
並嘗試看看的想法 這的確都是熟悉的，
because here in week one what we'll begin to do is to compare,
因為在這裡每週有什麼 我們將開始做的是比較，
initially, Scratch versus C.
最初，耐刮與C.
>> So, for instance, recall that when we implemented the first of our programs
>> 所以，舉例來說，回想一下，當我們 實現了第一個我們的節目
last time, we had a block that looked a little something like this-- when
最後一次，我們有看起來塊 有點像this--時
green flag clicked, and then we had one or more puzzle pieces below it,
綠旗點擊，然後我們有 一個或多個拼圖在它下面，
in this case, say, hello world.
在這種情況下，就是說，世界你好。
So, indeed, in Scratch, when I click that green flag
因此，事實上，在划痕， 當我點擊了綠色環保標誌
to run my program, so to speak, these are
運行我的程序，所以 可以說，這些都是
the blocks that get executed, or run.
得到執行的塊，或運行。
And, specifically, Scratch said, hello, world.
和，特別是，臨時 說，你好，世界。
>> Now, I could have specified different words here.
>> 現在，我可以指定 這裡不同的話。
But we'll see that, indeed, many of these blocks-- and indeed,
但是我們會發現，事實上，許多 這些blocks--確實的，
in C many functions-- can be parametrized or customized
用C許多functions--可 參數化或定制
to do different things.
做不同的事情。
In fact, in C if we want to convert, now,
事實上，在C，如果我們 要轉換，現在，
this Scratch program to this other language,
這耐刮劃 這個其他語言，
we're going to write a little something like this.
我們將寫一 小這樣的事情。
>> Granted, there is some unfamiliar syntax there most likely, int,
>> 當然，有一些陌生 語法有最有可能，INT，
and parentheses, and void.
和括號，和無效的。
But printf-- even though you would think it would just be print.
但是，儘管你甚至會printf-- 認為這將只是打印。
But print means print formatted, as we'll soon see.
但是打印表示打印 格式化，因為我們很快就會看到。
This literally will print to the screen whatever
這從字面上將打印 到屏幕上的任何
is inside of those parentheses, which of course in this case is, hello world.
是那些括號內，這 當然，在這種情況下，世界你好。
>> But you'll notice some other syntax, some double quotes,
>> 但你會發現一些其他的 語法，一些雙引號，
that the parentheses at the end, the semi-colon and the like.
，在結束括號， 分號等。
So there's a bit of overhead, so to speak, both cognitively
因此，有一點開銷， 可以這麼說，無論是認知
and syntactically, that we're going to have to remember before long.
和語法，我們要去 有不久記住。
But realize that with practice, this will start to jump out at you.
但要意識到聯繫實際， 這將開始在你跳出來。
>> In fact, let's focus on that one function specifically-- in this case,
>> 事實上，讓我們專注於一個 功能specifically--在這種情況下，
say hello world.
打招呼的世界。
So say is the function.
所以說是功能。
Hello world is its parameter, or argument, its customisation.
你好世界是它的參數， 或參數，它的定制。
>> And the equivalence in C is just going to be this one line here,
>> 而在C中的等價只是 要在這裡成為這一行，
where printf is equivalent to, say, the double quoted string, hello
在這裡的printf相當於，說， 雙引號字符串，你好
world is equivalent, of course, to what's in the white box there.
世界是等效的，當然， 什麼是在白框那裡。
And the backslash n, though a little strange and absent from Scratch,
和反斜線N，雖然有點 奇怪的並從頭缺席，
simply is going to have the effect we'll see in a computer, like my Mac or a PC,
簡單地說就是將有我們的影響 看到一台電腦，像我的Mac或PC，
of just moving the cursor to the next line.
只是移動 光標移到下一行。
It's like hitting Enter on your keyboard.
這就像打 鍵盤上的Enter。
>> So we'll see that again before long.
>> 因此，我們將不久再次看到這一點。
But first, let's take a look at this other example in the case of loops.
但首先，讓我們來看看這個 在循環的情況下，其他的例子。
We had this forever loop last time, which was a series of puzzle pieces
我們有這樣永遠循環最後一次， 這是一系列的拼圖
that did something literally forever-- in this case,
那做了字面上 forever--在這種情況下，
say, hello world, hello world, hello world, hello world.
說，你好世界，你好世界， 世界你好，你好世界。
So it's an infinite loop by design.
所以這是設計一個無限循環。
>> In C, if we want to implement this same idea, we might simply do this.
>> 在C中，如果我們想實現這個 同樣的想法，我們可以簡單地做到這一點。
While true, printf hello world-- now while, just semantically, kind of
雖然如此，printf的招呼現在天下 - 同時，剛剛語義，那種
conjures up the idea of doing something again, and again, and again,
聯想到做的念頭 重複的事情，又一次，又一次，
and for how long?
多長時間？
Well, true-- recall that true is just on or one.
那麼，true--回憶一下， 真正是剛上或1。
>> And true is, of course, always true.
>> 而真正的，當然，總是如此。
So it's kind of a meaningless statement just to say true.
所以這是一種毫無意義的 聲明只是說真的。
But indeed, this is deliberate, because if true is just always true,
但事實上，這是故意的， 因為如果真的僅僅是總是正確的，
than while true just implies, if a little indirectly,
而不是真正的就是意味著， 如果有點間接的，
that the following lines of code in between those curly braces
那下面的代碼行 在這些大括號
should just execute again, and again, and again, and never actually stop.
應該只是又一次，又一次執行， 又一次，從來沒有真正停止。
>> But if you do want your loop to stop, as we
>> 但是，如果你希望你的 循環停止，因為我們
did last time with something like this, repeat the following 50 times,
跟上次喜歡的東西 這種重複以下50次，
in C we can do the same with what's called a for loop-- the keyword
用C我們可以做什麼是相同的 被稱為為loop--關鍵字
not being while, but for.
不是一陣子，而是。
And then we have some new syntax here, with int i equals 0, i less than 50,
然後，我們有一些新的語法在這裡， 使用int i等於0，我不到50，
i++.
我++。
And we'll come back to that.
我們會回來這一點。
But this is simply how we would translate the set of Scratch blocks
但是，這僅僅是我們如何會 翻譯組划痕塊
to a set of C lines of code.
一組的碼C的行。
>> Meanwhile, consider variables.
>> 同時，考慮的變量。
And, in fact, we just saw one a moment ago.
而且，事實上，我們只是 看見一個人剛才。
And in the case of Scratch, if we wanted to declare a variable called i
並且在暫存的情況下，如果我們 要聲明一個叫做變量i
for i being integer, just a number, and we want to set it to some value,
因為我是整數，只是一個數字， 我們希望將它設置為某個值，
we would use this orange block here-- set i to 0.
我們將使用這個橙色 阻斷這裡 - 我設置為0。
>> And we'll see today and beyond, just like last week,
>> 而我們今天將看到和 超越，就像上週，
programmers do almost always start counting from zero, really
程序員做幾乎總是 從零開始計數，真
by convention.
按照慣例。
But also because recall from our discussion of binary,
但也因為召回 我們的二元討論，
the smallest number you can represent with any number of bits
最小的號碼，你可以 用任何數目的位表示
is just going to be 0 itself.
只是將是0本身。
And so we'll generally start initializing even our variables to 0.
所以，我們通常會開始 即使初始化我們的變量為0。
>> And in C to do the same, we're going to say int
>> 而在C ++做的一樣， 我們會說INT
for integer, i just by convention.
為整數，我只是按照慣例。
I could have called this variable anything I want, just like in Scratch.
我可以叫這個變量 任何我想要的，就像在刮。
And then equals 0 just assigns the value 0 from the right
然後等於0只是受讓人 從右側的值0
and puts it into the variable, or the storage container there, on the left.
並將其放入變量，或 儲存容器有，在左側。
And the semi-colon as we'll see-- and we've seen a few of these already--
和分號，我們會see--和 我們已經看到了一些這些already--的
just means end of thought.
只是意味著思想的終結。
Proceed to do something else on the lines that follow.
繼續做別的事情 在接下來的線。
>> Now, what about Boolean expressions?
>> 現在，關於布爾表達式？
Recall that in Scratch, these were expressions
回想一下，在刮， 這些人表情
that are either true or false-- questions,
那些是真 或false--問題，
really, that are either true or false.
真的，要么是真還是假。
So in the case of Scratch, we might ask a simple question like this,
因此，在划痕的情況下，我們可能 問一個簡單的問題，這樣，
is i less than 50?
為i小於50？
So i, again, is an integer.
所以我，再次是整數。
Maybe we're using it in a Scratch program
也許我們正在使用它 在臨時計劃
to keep track of a score or something like that.
保持比分的軌道 或類似的東西。
So this syntax here in Scratch just means, is i less than 50?
所以這個語法在這裡划痕 只是手段，是我不到50？
Well, thankfully, something is simple in C. And to translate,
好了，幸運的是，事情是 簡單的C。和翻譯，
this we would simply say i less than 50, using the familiar key
這一點，我們就簡單的說我少 50，使用熟悉的關鍵
on your keyboard.
鍵盤上。
>> Meanwhile, if you wanted to say something more general,
>> 同時，如果你想 說一些比較一般，
like, well, is x less than y where each of x and y are themselves variables?
像，很好，比y這裡每個x少 x和y的本身變量？
We can do the same thing in C, so long as we've
我們可以做同樣的事情 在C，只要我們已經
created these variables already.
創建這些變量了。
And we'll see how to do that before long.
我們將看到如何 這樣做不久。
We would simply say x less than y.
我們就簡單的說比Y X更少。
>> So you're starting to see some similarities.
>> 所以，你開始 看到一些相似之處。
And those folks who made Scratch were certainly
和誰做那些人 從無到有是肯定
inspired by some of these basic ideas.
通過其中的一些基本思想的啟發。
And you'll see this kind of syntax in many languages--
你會看到這樣的 語法在很多languages​​--
not just Scratch, not just C, but Python,
不只是劃傷， 只是C，但是Python，
and JavaScript, and other languages still.
和JavaScript，以及 其他語言依舊。
>> Let's consider another construct from C, the notion of a condition,
>> 讓我們考慮另一種結構 從C，條件的概念，
doing something conditionally.
做一些有條件。
If something is true, do this.
如果事情是真的，做到這一點。
If something else is true, do that.
如果別的東西是真實的，做到這一點。
It's sort of the programming equivalent of a fork in the road.
這有點編程的 在一個岔路口的等價物。
Maybe it's a two-way fork, a three-way fork, or more.
也許這是一個叉雙向的， 三通叉，或更多。
And in Scratch, we might have seen something like this.
而在划痕，我們可能有 看到這樣的事情。
>> So this one's a big one.
>> 所以這一塊是一個大的。
But consider the relative simplicity of the logic.
但考慮到相對 邏輯簡單性。
If x is less than y, then say x is less than y, else if x is greater than y,
如果x小於y，然後說x是少 比Y，否則如果x大於y，
then say x is greater than y.
然後說x是大於y。
And then, logically, if you think back to Scratch
然後，在邏輯上，如果， 回想一下划痕
or just your own human intuition, well, if x is not greater than y, and x
或者只是你自己的人的直覺， 好吧，如果x不大於y，並且x
is not less than y, then of course x is going to be equal to y.
不除Y更小，則當然 x被將是等於y。
So in this case, by nesting those Scratch blocks,
因此，在這種情況下，通過嵌套 這些划痕塊，
can we achieve a three way fork in the road?
我們可以實現一個三 在行進的方式叉？
>> Meanwhile, if we want to do that in C, it arguably
>> 同時，如果我們想 這樣做，在C，它可以說是
looks a little simpler-- at least once you get familiar with the syntax.
看起來至少有一點simpler-- 一旦你熟悉的語法。
If x is less than y, printf x is less than y.
如果x小於y， printf的x是小於y。
Else if x is greater than y, printf x is greater than y.
否則如果x大於y， printf的x是大於y。
Else printf x is equal to y-- and, again, with those backslash ends just
其他的printf x等於y--和， 再次，與那些反斜杠只
for those new lines so that if you actually ran this kind of program
對於這些新的生產線，這樣，如果你 居然跑這種方案
it would just move your cursor ultimately
它只是移動 光標最終
to the next line of the screen.
到屏幕的下一行。
>> Now, meanwhile Scratch had other more sophisticated features, only
>> 現在，同時有划痕等 更複雜的功能，只
some of which we're going to initially move over to the world of C.
其中有些我們要 最初移動到C的世界
And one of them was called a list in Scratch.
其中之一是 稱為划痕列表。
And this was a special type of variable that
這是一個特殊的 變量的類型
allowed you to store multiple things in it back, to back, to back, to back.
允許你存儲多個事 在回來，背，背，背。
>> In C, it doesn't have lists, per se, but something
>> 在C中，它不具有 名單，本身的事，但
that are more generally called arrays, although we'll
是更一般 所謂的陣列，雖然我們
come back later this semester to looking at something
回來以後這個學期 要尋找的東西
called a list, or really a linked list.
所謂的名單，還是真的鍊錶。
But for now, the closest equivalent in C for us
但現在，最接近 相當於C語言為我們
is going to be something called an array.
會是什麼 稱為陣列。
And an array is simply a special type of variable
和陣列是一個簡單的 特殊類型的可變的
that allows you to store data back, to back, to back, to back.
這允許你存儲數據 背，背，背，背到。
>> And, indeed, in Scratch, if we wanted to access
>> 而且，事實上，在划痕， 如果我們想訪問
the first element of an array or a list-- and I'm going to call it,
數組的第一元素或 一個列表中 - 我要去稱呼它，
by convention, argv, argument vector, but more on that before long.
按照慣例，argv的，說法 矢量，但不久還有更多。
If I want to get at the first element of argv, in the world of Scratch
如果我想要得到的第一個元素 ARGV的，在刮的世界
you actually do typically start counting from 1.
你實際上做一般 從1開始計數。
>> And so I might get item 1 of argv.
>> 所以，我可能會得到argv的第1項。
That's just how MIT implemented the notion of lists.
這是麻省理工學院的只是如何實現的 列表的概念。
But in C, I'm going to more simply just say, argv,
但在C，我要去 更簡單地只是說，ARGV，
which again is the name of my list-- or to be clear, an array.
這又是對我的名字 列表中 - 或者是明確的，一個數組。
And if I want the first elements, I'm going
如果我想第一 元素，我要去
to use square brackets, which you might not often used under a keyboard.
用方括號，你 可能不會經常鍵盤下使用。
>> But 0 just means, get me the first.
>> 但是，0只是意味著，拿到我的第一。
So on occasion and as time passes, we're going
等等場合和 久而久之，我們要去
to start to see these dichotomies between Scratch and C,
開始看到這些二分法 划痕和C之間，
whereby Scratch uses one.
即刮使用一個。
We in C use 0 here.
我們用C在這裡使用0。
But you'll quickly see once you understand
但你會很快看到 一旦你理解
the foundations of each language, that these things start to get all the more
每種語言的基礎，即 這些事情開始變得更加
familiar through practice and practice.
熟悉通過實踐和實踐。
>> So let's actually look now at a program.
>> 因此，讓我們實際上是在一個程序現在看起來。
Here shall be the first of our C source code for complete programs.
這裡應是第一個我們的C 完整程序的源代碼。
And the program we're going to offer for consideration
而該計劃，我們要去 提供審議
is the one that's equivalent to that earlier Scratch piece.
就是這相當於一個 那個早期的刮片。
>> So in here, we have what's arguably the simplest C program
>> 所以在這裡，我們有什麼 可以說是最簡單的C程序
you can write that actually does something.
你可以寫 實際上做什麼。
Now, we'll look past, for now, has include,
現在，我們來看看過去， 現在，已經包括，
standard io.h, and these angle brackets, and int, and void,
標準io.h，而這些角度 括號和int和無效的，
and the curly braces, and the like.
及大括號，和類似物。
>> And let's just focus on what, at least intuitively,
>> 而我們只專注於 什麼，至少直覺，
might jump out at you already.
可能會對你已經跳出。
In fact, main, I don't necessarily know what this is,
事實上，主要的，我不知道 一定知道這是什麼，
but much like Scratch had that when green flag clicked puzzle piece,
但就像刮了，當 綠旗點擊拼圖，
so does C as a programming language have a main piece of code that
這樣做C作為編程語言 有一個主一段代碼，
gets executed by default. And, indeed, it's literally going to be called main.
被默認執行。而且，事實上， 它字面上將被稱為主。
>> So main is a function.
>> 所以主要是一個函數。
And it's a special function that exists in C that when you run a program,
而且它是一個真實存在的特殊功能 用C，當你運行一個程序，
it is main that gets run by default. In the world of Scratch,
它是由被主運行 默認。在划痕的世界裡，
it was usually when green flag clicked that got run by default.
它通常是，當綠旗 點擊的得到了默認情況下運行。
>> Meanwhile, we've seen this before, printf or print formatted, that's
>> 同時，我們已經見過這個， printf的或打印的格式，這是
going to be a function that comes with C, along with a whole bunch of others,
也會有一些自帶的功能 C，伴隨著一大堆別人的，
that will from time and time again, in order to do exactly
從時間和時間的意願 再次，為了準確地做
as its name suggests, print something.
正如它的名字所暗示的，打印的東西。
What do we want to print?
我們究竟要打印？
Well, we'll see that by enclosing characters
好吧，我們會看到， 由封閉字符
like these-- hello world, backslash n in double quotes,
像these--世界你好， 反斜杠n的雙引號，
we can tell printf exactly what to print on the screen.
我們可以告訴準確的printf 什麼要打印在屏幕上。
>> But in order to do that, we unfortunately
>> 但為了做 這一點，我們很遺憾
need to take something that is already cryptic to us humans,
需要採取的東西是 已經隱晦了我們人類，
but at least it's somewhat readable-- sharp include, standard io.h, int,
但至少它有點readable-- 犀利包括標準io.h，INT，
main, void, printf, all of the magical incantations we just saw on the screen.
主要的，無效的printf，所有的神奇 咒語剛才我們看到在屏幕上。
But we actually have to go more arcane still.
但是實際上我們要 走得更神秘依舊。
We first need to translate the code that we write into machine code.
我們首先需要翻譯的代碼 我們編寫成機器代碼。
And recall from last week that machines, at least the ones we know here,
而從上週回顧機， 至少那些我們知道這裡，
at the end of the day only understand zeros and ones.
在一天結束的時候只 了解零和一。
>> And my God, if we had to write these zeros and ones to actually program,
>> 我的上帝，如果我們寫這些 零和的實際計劃，
it would very, very quickly take the fun out of anything.
它會非常快 採取樂趣的事情。
But it turns out, per last week, that these patterns of zeros and ones
但事實證明，每上週， 該零和一的這些模式
just have special meaning.
只是有特殊的意義。
In certain contexts, they might mean numbers.
在某些情況下， 他們可能意味著數。
>> In some contexts, they might mean letters, or colors, or any number
>> 在某些情況下，它們可能意味著 字母或顏色，或任何數目的
of other abstractions there upon.
其他抽象存在於。
But just as your computer has a CPU, Central Processing Unit,
但是，就像你的電腦有 一個CPU，中央處理單元，
or the brains inside of your computer.
或您的計算機內的大腦。
It's usually Intel inside, because that's
它通常是英特爾 在裡面，因為這是
one of the biggest companies that makes CPUs for computers.
最大的公司之一 這使得CPU的電腦。
>> Well, Intel CPUs and others simply have decided in advance
>> 那麼，英特爾的CPU及其他 只需提前決定
that certain patterns of zeros and ones shall mean specific things.
該零點的某些模式和 那些指具體的事情。
Certain patterns of zeros and ones will mean, print this to the screen,
零和一的某種模式 將意味著，打印此屏幕，
or add these two numbers, or subtract these two numbers,
或加這兩個數字，或 減去這兩個數字，
or move this piece of data from my computer's memory over here,
或將這塊數據從 我的電腦的記憶在這裡，
or any number of other very low level, but ultimately useful, operations.
或任何數量的其他非常低的水平， 但最終有用的，運營。
But, thankfully, we humans are not going to need to know this level of detail.
不過，值得慶幸的是，我們人類都不會 需要知道這些細節。
Indeed, just like last time, where we abstracted again, and again, and again,
事實上，和上次一樣，我們在那裡 又一次，又一次，又一次抽象，
building from very low level primitives like zeros and ones
從很低水平建設 基元像零和一
to higher level concepts like numbers, and letters,
更高層次的概念 像數字和字母，
and colors, and more, so can we as programmers
和顏色，以及多， 所以我們可以為程序員
stand on the shoulders of others who have come before us
站在肩上 別人在我們面前誰也來了
and use software that other people have written before us--
和使用的軟件，其他 人前us--采寫
namely programs called compilers.
即所謂的程序編譯器。
>> C is a language that is usually compiled,
>> C是一種語言， 通常編譯，
which means converted from source code to machine code.
這意味著從轉換 源代碼的機器代碼。
In particular, what this means is that if you've got your source
特別是，這意味著什麼 是，如果你有你的源代碼
code that you yourself write, as we soon will in just a moment on the screen,
代碼，您自己寫，因為我們很快 將在剛剛在屏幕上的時刻，
and you want to convert it ultimately to machine code--
並且希望將其轉換 最終以機器代碼 -
those zeros and ones that only your Mac or your PC
這些零和那些 只有你的Mac或PC機
understands-- you've got a first feed that source code in as
understands--你已經有了一個第一 養活源代碼作為
input to a special program called a compiler,
輸入到一個特 程序調用一個編譯器，
the output of which we shall see is machine code.
輸出其中我們 應當看到的是機器代碼。
And, indeed, last time we talked about, really, at the end of the day,
而且，事實上，上次我們聊 一下，果然，在一天結束的時候，
problem solving.
解決問題。
You've got inputs.
你有投入。
And you've got outputs.
和你有輸出。
And you've got some kind of algorithm in the middle.
和你有某種 在中間算法。
>> Algorithms can surely be implemented in software,
>> 算法可以肯定是 在軟件中實現，
as we saw with pseudocode last week and as we'll see with actual code
正如我們所看到上週偽 當我們將與實際的代碼看
this week.
本星期。
And so a compiler really just has a set of algorithms inside
所以編譯器真的只是 有一組算法內
of it that know how to convert the special keywords,
它知道如何 轉換成特殊的關鍵字，
like main, and printf, and others that we just
像主，和printf， 和其他人，我們只是
saw into the patterns of zeros and ones that Intel inside and other CPUs
只見到零的模式和 那些Intel Inside和其他CPU
actually understands.
其實理解。
So how do we do this?
那麼，如何才能做到這一點？
Where do we get a compiler?
我們在哪裡可以得到一個編譯器？
>> Most of us here have a Mac or a PC.
>> 我們中的大多數在這裡有一台Mac或PC。
And you're running Mac OS, or Windows, or Linux, or Solaris,
而你運行Mac OS，或 Windows或Linux或Solaris，
or any number of other operating systems.
或任何數量的其他 操作系統。
And, indeed, we could go out onto the web
而且，事實上，我們可以 走出去到網上
and download a compiler for your Mac or your PC
並下載一個編譯器 為您的Mac或PC機
for your particular operating system.
為您的特定的操作系統。
But we would all be on different pages, so to speak.
但是，我們都將是上 不同的頁面，可以這麼說。
We'd have slightly different configurations.
我們會略有 不同的配置。
And things wouldn't work all the same.
而事情是行不通的都是一樣的。
And, indeed, these days many of us don't use
而且，事實上，這些天 我們很多人不使用
software that runs only on our laptops.
僅運行在我們的筆記本電腦的軟件。
Instead, we use something like a browser that
相反，我們使用的東西 像的瀏覽器
allows us to access web-based applications in the cloud.
允許我們訪問基於Web的 在雲應用。
And later this semester, we will do exactly that.
後來這個學期， 我們將這樣做。
We will write applications or software using code-- not C,
我們將編寫應用程序或 使用代碼 - 軟件不是C，
but other languages like Python and JavaScript-- that run in the cloud.
但其他語言如Python和 JavaScript--在雲中運行。
>> And to do that, we ourselves during the semester
>> 要做到這一點，我們自己 在本學期
will actually use a cloud-based environment known as CS50 IDE.
將實際使用基於雲計算的 環境被稱為CS50 IDE。
This is a web-based programming environment, or integrated development
這是一個基於網絡的編程 環境，或集成開發
environment, IDe, that's built atop some open source software called Cloud 9.
環境，IDE，它內建一些之上 所謂雲9開源軟件。
And we've made some pedagogical simplifications to it
我們已經取得了一定的教學 簡化到它
so as to hide certain features in the first weeks that we don't need,
從而隱藏某些功能 我們並不需要在第一週，
after which you can reveal them and do most
之後就可以 揭示他們做最
anything you want with the environment.
任何你想要的環境。
>> And it allows us, too, to pre-install certain software.
>> 它讓我們也一樣，要 預安裝某些軟件。
Things like a so-called CS50 library, which we'll soon see
比如像所謂的CS50 圖書館，我們很快就會看到
provides us in C with some additional functionality.
為我們提供了用C與一些 附加功能。
So if you go to, ultimately, CS50.io, you'll be prompted to log in,
所以，如果你去，最終CS50.io， 你會被提示登錄，
and once you do and create an account for free,
一旦你這樣做，並創建 一個是免費的賬號，
you will be able to access an environment that looks quite like this.
你將能夠訪問 環境看起來很喜歡這一點。
>> Now, this is in the default mode.
>> 現在，這是默認模式。
Everything is nice and bright on the screen.
一切都是好的， 明亮的屏幕上。
Many of us have a habit of working on CS50 piece that's
我們很多人都習慣 工作CS50一塊是
quite late into the night.
挺到深夜。
And so some of you might prefer to turn it into night mode, so to speak.
所以，有些人可能更喜歡 把它變成夜間模式，可以這麼說。
>> But, ultimately, what you're going to see within CS50 IDE
>> 但是，最終，你在做什麼 要CS50 IDE中看到
is three distinct areas-- an area on the left where
是三個不同的areas-- 在離開的地方面積
your files are going to be in the cloud, an area on the top right
您的文件將要在 雲，在右上方的區域
where your code is going to be editable.
在您的代碼將是編輯。
You'll be able to open individual tabs for any program
您可以打開 對於任何程序各個選項卡
that you write this semester inside of that top right hand corner.
你寫的裡面這學期 最重要的是右上角。
And then most arcanely, and yet powerfully,
然後最arcanely， 然而有力，
is going to be this thing at the bottom known as a terminal window.
將是這個東西在 底部被稱為一個終端窗口。
>> This is an old school Command Line Interface,
>> 這是一個老同學 命令行界面，
or CLI, that allows you to execute commands
或CLI，允許 你執行命令
on the computer-- in this case, the computer in the cloud--
在這種情況下，computer--， 在cloud--電腦
to do things like compile your code from source code to machine code,
做事喜歡編譯代碼 從源代碼到機器碼，
to run your programs, or to start your web server, or to access your database,
運行您的程序，或者啟動 Web服務器或訪問數據庫，
and any number of other techniques that we'll start to use before long.
和任意數量的其他技術 我們將開始不久使用。
But to get there, we're going to actually have
但到那裡，我們 去居然有
to go online and start playing.
到網上去，並開始播放。
And to do that, let's first start tinkering with main,
要做到這一點，讓我們先 開始擺弄為主，
and write the main part of a program.
寫一個程序的主要部分。
And let's use that function printf, which we used earlier,
讓我們使用這個函數 printf的，這是我們前面使用，
simply to say something.
簡單地說幾句。
>> So here I am already inside of CS50 IDE.
>> 所以我在這裡已經CS50 IDE裡面。
I've logged in advance.
我登錄的進步。
And I full screened the window.
我完全屏蔽的窗口。
And so, ultimately, you too in coming problems
所以，最終，你 過在未來的問題
will follow similar steps that will provide online documentation.
將遵循類似步驟 將提供在線文檔。
So you don't need to worry about absorbing every little technical step
所以你不必擔心 每吸收一點技術一步
that I do here today.
我今天在這裡做。
>> But you'll get a screen like this.
>> 但你會得到這樣的畫面。
I happen to be in night mode.
我碰巧在夜間模式。
And you can brighten everything up by disabling night mode.
你可以照亮一切 同比禁用夜間模式。
And at the end of the day, you're going to see
而在底了 一天，你會看到
these three main areas-- the file browser at left, the code tabs up top,
這三個主要areas--文件 在瀏覽器的左邊，代碼標籤向上頂，
and the terminal window at the bottom.
和在底部的終端窗口。
>> Let me go ahead and write my first program.
>> 讓我繼續前進， 寫我的第一個程序。
I'm going to preemptively go to File, Save, and save my file as hello.c.
我要搶先去文件， 保存，我的文件保存為hello.c的。
Indeed, by convention, any program we write that's written in the C language
事實上，按照慣例，任何程序我們 寫是寫C語言
should be named something dot c, by convention.
名稱應該 C點，按照約定。
So I'm going to name it hello.c, because I just want to say hello to the world.
所以，我打算將其命名為hello.c的，因為 我只是想打個招呼世界。
Now I'm going to zoom out and click Save.
現在，我要放大 並點擊保存。
And all I have here now is a tab in which I can start writing code.
和所有我現在這裡是一個標籤 在我可以開始編寫代碼。
>> This is not going to compile.
>> 這不會編譯。
This means nothing.
這意味著什麼。
And so even if I converted this to zeros and ones,
所以，即使我轉換 這對零和一，
the CPU is going to have no idea what's going around.
在CPU將不得不無 知道發生了什麼繞來繞去。
But if I write lines that do match up with C's conventions-- C being,
但是，如果我寫的線條那些匹配 就以C的conventions-- C是，
again, this language-- with syntax like this, printf hello world-- and I've
再次，這language--語法像 對此，printf的招呼天下 - 我已經
gotten comfortable with doing this over time.
得到舒服 這樣隨著時間的推移。
So I don't think I made any typographical errors.
所以，我不認為我做了 任何印刷錯誤。
>> But, invariably, the very first time you do this, you will.
>> 但是，不約而同地，第一個 你這樣做的時候，你會的。
And what I am about to do might very well not work for you the first time.
什麼我將做很可能會 也不會為你工作的第一次。
And that's perfectly OK, because right now you
而這完全確定， 因為現在你
might just see a whole lot of newness, but over time once you get familiar
可能只是看到一大堆新奇的， 但隨著時間的推移，一旦你熟悉
with this environment, and this language, and others,
與此環境下，並 這種語言，等人，
you'll start to see things that are either correct or incorrect.
你會開始看到的東西， 要么是正確或不正確。
>> And this is what the teaching fellows and course
>> 這是什麼 教學研究員，當然
assistants get so good at over time, is spotting mistakes or bugs in your code.
助理在得到隨著時間的推移這麼好，是 察覺你的代碼錯誤或錯誤。
But I claim that there are no bugs in this code.
但我要求有 在這段代碼中沒有錯誤。
So I now want to run this program.
所以，我現在要運行這個程序。
>> Now on my own Mac or PC, I'm in the habit of double clicking icons
>> 現在我自己的Mac或PC，我在 中雙擊圖標的習慣
when I want to run some program.
當我要運行一些程序。
But that's not the model here.
但是，這不是模型在這裡。
In this environment, which is CS50 IDE.
在這樣的環境中，這是CS50的IDE。
We are using an operating system called Linux.
我們使用的操作系統 系統稱為Linux。
Linux is reminiscent of another operating system, generally known
Linux是讓人聯想到另一 操作系統，通常已知
as Unix.
作為Unix的。
And Linux is particularly known for having a Command Line Environment, CLI.
而Linux是特別出名 有一個命令行環境，CLI。
Now, we're using a specific flavor of Linux called Ubuntu.
現在，我們使用一個特定的 Linux的味道叫做Ubuntu Linux系統。
And Ubuntu is simply a certain version of Linux.
和Ubuntu是一個簡單的 某些版本的Linux。
>> But these Linux's these days do actually come with graphical user interfaces.
>> 但是這些的Linux的這些天真正做到 配備了圖形用戶界面。
And the one we happen to be using here is web-based.
和一個我們碰巧 在這裡使用是基於Web的。
So this might look even a little different from something
因此，這可能看起來甚至 從東西有點不同
you yourself might have seen or run in the past.
你自己可能有 看到或跑過去。
>> So I'm going to go ahead now and do the following.
>> 所以我要繼續前進 現在做到以下幾點。
I've saved this file as hello.c.
我已經保存此文件的hello.c。
I'm going to go ahead and type clanghello.c So Clang
我要繼續前進， 類型clanghello.c所以鏘
for the C language is a compiler.
對於C語言編譯器。
It's pre-installed in CS50 IDE.
這是預安裝在CS50 IDE。
And you can absolutely download and install this on your own Mac or PC.
你完全可以下載 在自己的Mac或PC上安裝它。
>> But, again, you wouldn't have all of the pre-configuration done for you.
>> 但是，同樣，你不會有所有的 為您預先配置完成。
So for now, I'm just going to run clanghello.c.
所以現在，我只是 要運行clanghello.c。
And now notice this syntax here will eventually
而現在注意到這一點語法 這裡最終將
realize just means that I'm in a folder or directory called Workspace.
認識只是意味著我在 文件夾或目錄被稱為工作區。
This dollar sign is just convention for meaning, type your commands here.
這個美元符號僅僅是慣例 為內涵，在這裡輸入你的命令。
>> It's what's called a prompt, just by convention is dollar sign.
>> 這就是被稱為一個提示，只是 按照慣例是美元符號。
And if I go ahead now and click Enter, nothing seems to have happened.
如果我繼續前進，現在並點擊 回車後，似乎沒有任何已經發生。
But that's actually a good thing.
但是，這實際上是一件好事。
The less that happens on your screen, the more likely
出現這種情況就少 您的屏幕，越有可能
your code is to be correct, at least syntactically.
你的代碼是正確， 至少語法。
>> So if I want to run this program, what do I do?
>> 所以，如果我想運行此 程序，我該怎麼辦？
Well, it turns out that the default name by convention
嗯，事實證明， 按照慣例默認名稱
for programs when you don't specify a name for your program is just a.out.
對於程序時，您不指定 名稱為您的計劃僅僅是為a.out。
And this syntax too, you'll get familiar with before long.
而這也是語法，你會 熟悉不久。
>> Dot slash just means, hey, CS50 IDE, run a program called a.out
>> 點斜線只是意味著，哎，CS50 IDE，運行一個名為a.out的程序
that's inside my current directory.
這是我的當前目錄裡。
That dot means the current directory.
這點是指當前目錄。
And we'll see what other such sequences of characters means before long.
我們會看到什麼其他的這些序列 人物不久手段。
>> So here we go, Enter, hello world.
>> 所以在這裡我們去，回車，世界你好。
And you'll notice, that what happened?
你會發現，發生了什麼？
Not only did it print hello world.
它不僅打印的hello world。
It also moved the cursor to the next line.
它也感動 光標移到下一行。
>> And why was that?
>> 以及為什麼呢？
What was the code that we wrote before that ensured that the cursor would
那是什麼，我們以前寫的代碼 即確保該光標將
go on the next line?
繼續下一行？
Funny thing about a computer is it's only going
大約一個有趣的事情 計算機是它一定會
to do literally what you tell it to do.
做字面上你告訴它做。
>> So if you tell it to printf hello, comma, space, world, close quote,
>> 所以，如果你告訴它給printf你好， 逗號，空間，世界，接近報價，
it's literally only going to print those characters.
它字面上只打算 打印這些字符。
But I had this special character at the end, recall, backslash n.
但我有這個特殊字符 在年底，召回，反斜線ñ。
And that's what ensured that the character went
而這正是保證 該字符去
to the next line of the screen.
到屏幕的下一行。
>> In fact, let me go and do this.
>> 事實上，讓我去做到這一點。
Let me go ahead and delete this.
讓我繼續前進，刪除。
Now, notice that the top of my screen there's
現在，請注意 我的屏幕上方有
a little red light in the tab indicating,
一個小紅燈 標籤顯示，
hey, you've not saved your file.
哎，你不保存文件。
So I'm going to go ahead with control S or command S, save the file.
所以，我要與控制繼續前進 S或命令S，保存文件。
Now it goes-- went for a moment-- green.
現在goes--去了moment--綠色。
And now it's back to just being a close icon.
而現在又回到了 只是作為一個關閉圖標。
>> If I now run clanghello.c again, Enter, dot slash, a.out, Enter,
>> 如果我現在再次運行clanghello.c， 進入，點斜線，a.out的，回車，
you'll see that it still worked.
你會看到，它仍然工作。
But it's arguably a little buggy.
但它可以說是一個小馬車。
Right now, my prompt-- workspace, and then that dollar sign,
現在，我的工作區prompt--， 然後是美元符號，
and then my actual prompt-- is all on the same line.
然後我的實際prompt-- 是所有在同一行上。
So this certainly an aesthetic bug, even if it's not really a logical bug.
所以這肯定是一個錯誤的審美， 即使它不是一個真正的邏輯錯誤。
>> So I'm going to undo what I just did.
>> 所以，我要撤銷我只是做了。
I'm going to rerun a.out.
我要重新運行的a.out。
Notice I've added the newline character back.
請注意，我已經添加了 換行符回來。
I've saved the file.
我保存的文件。
>> So I'm going to rerun a.out, and-- dammit, a bug, a bug meaning mistake.
>> 所以，我要的a.out重新運行，還有 - 該死，一個bug，錯誤的意思的錯誤。
So the bug is that even though I added the backslash n there,
因此，錯誤是，即使 我加了反斜線Ñ那裡，
re-saved, re-ran the program, the behavior was the same.
重新保存，重新運行該程序， 的行為是相同的。
Why would that be?
為什麼會是這樣？
>> I'm missing a step, right?
>> 我缺少的一個步驟，對不對？
That key step earlier was that you have to-- when you change your source code,
這關鍵的一步早前是你有 當你改變你的源代碼中場休息，
it turns out also run it through the compiler
事實證明也辦 它通過編譯
again so you get new machine code.
再次讓你獲得新的機器代碼。
And the machine code, the zeros and ones,
和機器代碼， 在零和一，
are going to be almost identical, but not perfectly so, because we need,
將要幾乎相同，但 不完全是這樣，因為我們需要的，
of course, that new line.
當然，新的線路。
>> So to fix this, I'm going to need to rerun clanghello.c, enter, dot
>> 因此，要解決這個問題，我會需要 重新運行clanghello.c，輸入，點
slash, a.out.
斜線，a.out的。
And now, hello world is back to where I expect it to be.
而現在，世界您好又回來了 在那裡我希望它是。
So this is all fine and good.
因此，這是一切優秀和良好。
But a.out is a pretty stupid name for a program, even though it happens to be,
但a.out的是一個相當愚蠢的名字 方案，即使它正好是，
for historical reasons, the default-- meaning assembly outputs.
由於歷史的原因， default--意思裝配輸出。
>> But let me go ahead here and do this differently.
>> 但讓​​我繼續在這裡 而不同的做到這一點。
I want my hello world program to actually be called hello.
我希望我的Hello World程序 實際上叫你好。
So if it were an icon on my desktop, it wouldn't be a.out.
所以，如果它是一個圖標我 台式機，它不會被A.OUT。
It would be called hello.
它會被稱為打招呼。
>> So to do this, it turns out that Clang, like many programs,
>> 因此，要做到這一點，事實證明 那鐺，像許多節目，
supports command line arguments, or flags, or switches,
支持命令行參數， 或標誌，或開關
which simply influence its behavior.
它只是影響其行為。
Specifically, Clang supports a dash o flag, which then takes a second word.
具體來說，鏘支持破折號Ø 標誌，然後拿著第二個字。
In this case, I'll arbitrarily, but reasonably, call it hello.
在這種情況下，我會隨意， 但合理的，把它打個招呼。
But I could call it anything I want, except a.out, which
但我可以把它叫做什麼 我想，除了a.out的，這
would be rather besides the point.
會相當除了點。
>> And then just specify the name of the file I do want to compile.
>> 然後只需指定名稱 文件我確實想編譯。
So now even though at the beginning of the command I still have Clang,
所以，現在即使在開始 命令我仍然有鐺的，
at the end of the command I still have the filename,
在命令結束時 我仍然有文件名，
I now have these command line arguments, these flags that are saying,
我現在有這些命令行 參數，這些標誌是在說，
oh, by the way, output-o, a file called hello, not the default a.out.
哦，對了，輸出-O，文件 名為hello，而不是默認的a.out。
>> So if I hit Enter now, nothing seems to have happened.
>> 所以，現在如果我打回車鍵，沒什麼 似乎已經發生了。
And, yet, now I can do dot slash hello.
而且，然而，現在我可以做點斜線打招呼。
So it's the same program.
所以這是相同的程序。
The zeros and ones are identical at the end of the day.
在零和一的 相同在一天結束。
>> But they're in two different files-- a.out,
>> 但是他們兩個 不同files--的a.out，
which is the first version and just foolishly named,
這是第一個版本 和公正的愚蠢命名，
and now hello, which is a much more compelling name for a program.
現在你好，這是一個非常 更引人注目的名字的程序。
But, honestly, I am never going to remember this again,
但是，說實話，我從來沒有 又要記住這一點，
and again, and again.
又一次，又一次。
And, actually, as we write more complicated programs,
而且，事實上，正如我們寫 更複雜的程序，
the commands you're going to have to write
你的命令 不得不寫
are going to get even more complicated still.
要報復 更複雜的仍。
>> And so not to worry.
>> 所以不用擔心。
It turns out that humans before us have realized they too
事實證明，人類前 我們已經意識到，他們也
had this exact same problem.
有這個相同的問題。
They too did not enjoy having to type fairly long, arcane commands,
他們也沒有享受不必 鍵入相當長的，神秘的命令，
let alone remember them.
更不用說記住他們。
And so humans before us have made other programs that make it easier
所以，擺在我們面前的人類已經取得 其他程序，可以更容易
to compile your software.
編譯軟件。
>> And, indeed, one such program is called Make.
>> 而且，事實上，這樣的一個 計劃被稱為製作。
So I'm going to go ahead and do this.
所以我要繼續前進，並做到這一點。
I'm going to undo everything I just did in the following way.
我要撤銷我的一切 正好在下面的方式一樣。
Let me type LS.
讓我LS型。
And you'll notice three things-- a.out, and a star, hello
你會注意到三個things-- a.out的，和一個明星，你好
and a star, and hello.c.
和一個明星，而hello.c中。
Hopefully, this should be a little intuitive,
但願，這應該 有一點直觀，
insofar as earlier there was nothing in this workspace.
只要前面有 沒有在此工作空間。
There was nothing that I had created until we started class.
沒有什麼，我有 創建，直到我們開始上課。
>> And I created hello.c.
>> 和我創建的hello.c。
I then compiled it, and called it a.out.
然後我編譯它，並把它稱為a.out的。
And then I compiled it again slightly differently and called it hello.
然後我再編譯稍微 不同，稱之為打招呼。
So I have three files in this directory, in this folder called Workspace.
所以我有這個目錄中的三個文件， 在這個文件夾叫工作空間。
Now, I can see that as well if I zoom out actually.
現在，我可以看到，以及 如果我縮小實際。
>> If I zoom out here and look at that top right hand
>> 如果我縮小這裡 看那個右上角
corner, as promised the left hand side of your screen
角落裡，如許左 屏幕的右側
is always going to show you what's in your account, what's
總是會告訴你 什麼是在您的帳戶，有什麼
inside of CS50 IDE.
裡面CS50的IDE。
And there is three files there.
而且有三個文件存在。
>> So I want to get rid of a.out and hello.
>> 所以，我想擺脫的a.out和打招呼。
And as you might imagine intuitively, you
正如你可能 想像直觀，你
could sort of control click or right click on this.
可以控制排序點擊 或右鍵點擊這個。
And this little menu pops up.
而這個小菜單彈出。
You can download the file, run it, preview it, refresh, rename,
您也可以下載文件，運行 它，預覽，刷新，重命名，
or what not.
或什麼不是。
>> And I could just delete, and it would go away.
>> 而且我可能只是刪除， 它會消失。
But let's do things with a command line for now, so as to get comfortable
但是讓我們做的事情有一個命令 行了，這樣才能讓自己舒服
with this, and do the following.
這一點，並做到以下幾點。
I'm going to go ahead and remove a.out by typing literally rma.out.
我要繼續前進，並刪除 通過鍵入字面上rma.out的a.out。
It turns out, the command for removing or deleting something,
原來，該命令 去除或刪除的東西，
is not remove or delete.
是不是刪除或刪除。
>> It's more succinctly RM, just to save you some keystrokes, and hit Enter.
>> 這是更簡潔RM，只是為了節省 你一些按鍵，並按下回車鍵。
Now we're going to be somewhat cryptically remove regular file a.out.
現在，我們要有點 神秘地刪除常規文件的a.out。
I don't really know what an irregular file would be yet.
我真的不知道是什麼的 不規則的文件會呢。
But I do want to remove it.
但我要刪除它。
>> So I'm going to type y for yes.
>> 所以，我要鍵入Y（是）。
Or I could type it out, and hit Enter.
或者，我可以鍵入它，然後按Enter鍵。
And, again, nothing seems to happen.
並再次，好像沒有什麼改變。
But that is, generally, a good thing.
但是，這是一般，是一件好事。
>> If I type LS this time, what should I see?
>> 如果我輸入ls這一次， 我應該怎麼看？
Hopefully, just hello and hello.c.
我們希望，只是打招呼，hello.c中。
Now, as an aside, you'll notice this star, asterisk,
現在，順便說一句，你會 注意到這一點明星，星號，
that's at the end of my programs.
這是在我的節目的結束。
And they're also showing up in green.
而且他們也顯示為綠色。
That is just CS50 IDE's way of cluing you into the fact
這僅僅是CS50 IDE的方式 cluing你到事實的
that that's not source code.
那這不是源代碼。
That's an executable, a runnable program that you can actually run
這是一個可執行文件，可運行 你可以實際運行的程序
by doing dot slash, and then it's name.
通過做點斜杠，然後它的名字。
>> Now, let me go ahead and remove this, rm hello, Enter, remove regular
>> 現在，讓我繼續和刪除 對此，RM你好，回車，定期刪除
file hello, yes.
文件你好，是的。
And now if I type LS, we're back to hello.c.
現在，如果我輸入LS， 我們又回到hello.c中。
Try not to delete your actual source code.
盡量不要刪除 實際的源代碼。
Even though there are features built into CS50 IDE where
即使有特點 內置IDE CS50在哪裡
you can go through your revision history and rewind in time if you accidentally
你可以通過你的修訂歷史記錄 並及時退，如果你不小心
delete something, do be mindful as per these prompts yes or no,
刪除一些東西，做銘記 按照這些提示是或否，
of what you actually want to do.
什麼你真正想做的事情。
And if I go up to the top left hand corner here,
如果我去到頂部 這裡左手角落，
all that remains is hello.c.
剩下的工作就是hello.c中。
So there's bunches of other commands that you
因此，有一束束 其他命令你
can execute in the world of Linux, one of which is, again, Make.
可在Linux世界執行， 其中之一是，再次進行。
And we're going to Make my program now as follows.
而我們要製作 我現在的程序如下。
>> Instead of doing clang, instead of doing clang-o,
>> 而不是做鐺的， 而不是做鐺-O，
I'm going to simply literally type, make hello.
我要簡單地 從字面上類型，製造打招呼。
And now notice, I am not typing make hello.c.
而現在發現，我 不打字做的hello.c。
I am typing make hello.
我打字做打招呼。
>> And this program Make that comes with CS50 IDE, and more
>> 而這個節目的製作 自帶CS50 IDE，以及更多
generally with Linux, is a program that's
一般的Linux， 是一個程序，是
going to make a program called Hello.
要做一個名為Hello程序。
And it's going to assume, by convention, that if this program can be made,
而且它要承擔，按照慣例， 如果可以進行該程序，
it's going to be made from a source code file ending in dot c, hello.c.
它會從一個源發 代碼文件中C點結束，hello.c中。
>> So if I hit Enter now, notice that the command that gets executed
>> 所以，現在如果我打回車，通知， 這被執行的命令
is actually even longer before than before.
實際上甚至更長 前比以前。
And that's because we've preconfigured CS50 IDE to have
那是因為我們已經 預配置CS50 IDE有
some additional features built in that we don't need just yet, but soon will.
建於一些額外的功能 我們並不需要，只是還沒有，但很快會。
But the key thing to realize is now I have a Hello program.
但關鍵的事情來實現 現在我有一個Hello程序。
>> If I type LS again, I have a hello program.
>> 如果我再次鍵入LS，我 有一個hello程序。
And I can run it with dot slash a.out, no,
而且我可以運行它 點斜線a.out的，不，
because the whole point of this exercise was dot slash hello.
因為這個整點 演習點斜線打招呼。
And now I have my hello world program.
現在，我有我的Hello World程序。
So moving forward, we're almost always just
所以向前走， 我們幾乎永遠只是
going to compile our programs using the command Make.
要編譯我們的節目 使用命令make。
And then we're going to run them by dot slash, and the program's name.
然後，我們將通過為它們運行 點斜線，程序的名字。
But realize what Make is doing for you, is it is itself not a compiler.
但要意識到什麼使正在為 你，是它本身不是一個編譯器。
It's just a convenience program that knows how to trigger a compiler
這只是一個方便程序 知道如何觸發一個編譯器
to run so that you yourself can use it.
運行，讓你自己可以使用它。
>> What other commands exist in Linux, and in turn the CS50 IDE?
>> 還有什麼其他的命令中存在 Linux和依次CS50的IDE？
We'll soon see that there's a CD command, Change Directory.
我們很快就會看到，有一個 CD命令，切換目錄。
This allows you within your command line interface
這允許您在 你的命令行界面
to move forward, and back, and open up different folders
繼續前進，和背部， 並打開不同的文件夾
without using your mouse.
不使用鼠標。
>> LS we saw, which stands for list the files in the current directory.
>> 我們看到了LS，代表名單 在當前目錄中的文件。
Make Dir, you can probably start to infer
讓迪爾，你可以 可能開始推斷
what these mean now-- make directory, if you want to create a folder.
這些意味著什麼now--創建目錄， 如果你想創建一個文件夾。
RM for remove, RM Dir for remove directory-- and these,
RM為刪除，RM為迪爾 刪除directory--而這些，
again, are the command line equivalents of what you
再次，是命令行 什麼你現金等價物
could do in CS50 IDE with your mouse.
可在CS50 IDE與你的鼠標。
But you'll soon find that sometimes it's just
但是，你很快就會發現 有時它只是
a lot faster to do things with a keyboard,
速度快了很多做 事用鍵盤，
and ultimately a lot more powerful.
最終很多更強大。
>> But it's hard to argue that anything we've been doing so far
>> 但是，這很難說 任何事情我們一直在做，到目前為止
is all that powerful, when all we've been saying is, hello world.
是所有強大的，當所有 我們一直在說的是，世界你好。
And, in fact, I hardcoded the words hello world into my program.
而且，事實上，我的硬編碼 也就是說世界你好了我的計劃。
There is no dynamism yet.
有沒有活力呢。
Scratch was an order of magnitude more interesting last week.
划痕是一個數量級 更有趣的最後一周。
>> And so let's get there.
>> 所以，讓我們在那裡。
Let's take a step toward that by way of some of these functions.
讓我們走向一個一步 一些這些功能的方法。
So not only does C come with printf, and bunches of other functions
所以不僅ç配備的printf， 其它的功能和束
some of which we'll see over time, it doesn't
其中的一些，我們會看到 隨著時間的推移，它不
make it all that easy right out of the gate in getting user input.
使這一切容易右出 在獲取用戶輸入的柵極。
>> In fact, one of the weaknesses of languages like C,
>> 弱點事實上，人們 的語言，如C，
and even Java and yet others, is that it doesn't
甚至Java和尚未 別人是，它不
make it easy to just get things like integers from users, or strings, words,
可以很容易地只得到一樣的東西 從用戶或字符串，整數的話，
and phrases, let alone things like floating point values, or real numbers
和短語，讓喜歡獨處的東西 浮點值，或實數
with decimal points, and really long numbers, as we'll soon see.
帶有小數點的，真 長數字，因為我們很快就會看到。
So this list of functions here, these are like other Scratch puzzle pieces
所以功能這個名單在這裡，這些 就像其他的划痕拼圖
that we have pre-installed in CS50 IDE that we'll use for a few weeks
我們已經預先安裝在CS50 IDE，我們將用數週
as training wheels of sorts, and eventually take them off, and look
作為各種訓練車輪，和 最終把他們趕走，並期待
underneath the hood, perhaps, at how these things are implemented.
引擎蓋，也許，在下方 這些東西是如何實現的。
>> But to do this, let's actually write a program.
>> 但要做到這一點，讓我們 其實寫一個程序。
Let me go ahead now.
現在讓我先走。
And I'm going to create a new file by clicking this little plus,
而且我要創建一個新的 通過點擊這個小加檔，
and clicking New File.
然後單擊新建文件。
>> I'm going to save this next one as, let's say, string.c,
>> 我要救這下 一個作為，讓我們說，string.c，
because I want to play with strings.
因為我想用繩子玩。
And string in C is just a sequence of characters.
和字符串在C是剛 字符序列。
So now let's go ahead and do the following.
所以，現在讓我們繼續 並做到以下幾點。
>> Include standard IO.h-- and it turns out standard IO,
>> 包括標準IO.h--和 事實證明標準IO，
IO just means input and output.
IO只是意味著輸入和輸出。
So it turns out that this line here is what
所以，事實證明， 這裡這條線是什麼
is the neighboring us to use printf.
在相鄰的我們用printf。
Printf, of course, produces output.
printf的，當然，產生輸出。
So in order to use printf, it turns out you have to have this line of code
因此，為了用printf，原來 出你必須有這行代碼
at the top of your file.
在你的文件的頂部。
>> And we'll come back to what that really means before long.
>> 我們會回來的是什麼 不久的真正含義。
It turns out that in any C program I write,
事實證明，在 任何C程序我寫的，
I've got to start it with code that looks like this.
我必須與啟動 代碼如下所示。
And you'll notice CS50 IDE, and other integrated development
你會發現CS50 IDE和 其他集成開發
environments like it, are going to try as best
喜歡它的環境， 要盡可能在
they can to finish your thought.
他們可以完成你的想法。
In fact, a moment ago if I undo what I just did, I hit Enter.
其實，剛才我是否撤消 我只是做了，我打回車鍵。
>> I then hit open curly brace, hit Enter again.
>> 然後我打左大 撐，命中再次輸入。
And it finished my thought.
它完成了我的想法。
It gave me a new line, indented no less for nice stylistic reasons we'll see.
它給了我一個新的生產線，縮進不會少 對於好的文體的原因，我們拭目以待。
And then it automatically gave me that curly brace to finish my thought.
然後它會自動給我 那花括號來完成我的想法。
Now, it doesn't always guess what you want to do.
現在，它並不總是 猜你想要做什麼。
But in large part, it does save you some keystrokes.
但在很大程度上，它確實 為您節省一些按鍵。
So a moment ago, we ran this program-- hello, world, and then compiled it,
所以，剛才，我們跑這program-- 你好，世界，然後編譯它，
and then ran it.
然後運行它。
But there's no dynamism here.
但這裡有沒有活力。
What if we wanted to do something different?
如果我們想 做不同的事情？
Well, what if I wanted to actually get a string from the user?
好吧，如果我想實際 獲取來自用戶的字符串？
I'm going to use a puzzle piece called exactly that-- get string.
我將使用一塊拼圖 正是所謂的that--得到的字符串。
>> Turns out in C that when you don't want to provide input to a puzzle piece,
>> 用C原來，當你不想要 提供輸入到一塊拼圖，
or more properly to a function, you literally just do open parenthesis,
或者更恰當給一個函數，你 從字面上只是做開括號，
close parenthesis.
右括號。
So it's as though there's no white box to type into.
因此，這好像有 沒有白框鍵入。
The say block before had a little white box.
之前說塊 有一個白色的小盒子。
We don't have that white box now.
我們沒有白框現在。
>> But when I call get string, I want to put the result somewhere.
>> 但是，當我調用get字符串，我 想不想找個地方把結果。
So a very common paradigm in C is to call a function, like get string here,
所以在C很常見的模式是 這裡調用一個函數，以獲得更多的字符串，
and then store its return value.
然後存儲它的返回值。
It's the result of its effort in something.
它的結果其 努力的東西。
>> And what is the construct in programming,
>> 什麼是 構造在編程，
whether in Scratch or now C, that we can use to actually store something?
無論是在划痕或現在C，我們 可以使用實際存儲的東西嗎？
Called it a variable, right?
稱它是可變的，對不對？
And in Scratch, we don't really care what was going in variables.
而在劃傷，我們真的不 關心變量打算。
>> But in this case, we actually do.
>> 但是，在這種情況下，我們實際上做的。
I'm going to say string.
我要說的字符串。
And then I could call this anything I want.
然後，我可以打電話給 這樣的事情我想要的。
I'm going to call it name, gets get string.
我要叫它 名稱，獲取得到的字符串。
>> And now even if you're a little new to this,
>> 現在，即使你 有點新本，
notice that I'm lacking some detail.
注意到，我缺少一些細節。
I'm forgetting a semi-colon.
我忘了一個分號。
I need to finish this thought.
我需要完成這一思想。
So I'm going to move my cursor, and hit semi-colon there.
所以，我打算將我的光標， 並創下分號那裡。
And what have I just done?
和你有我只是做了什麼？
In this line of code, number 5 at the moment,
在這行代碼， 此刻號5，
I'm calling get string with no inputs.
我調用get字符串，沒有投入。
So there's no little white box like the Save block has.
因此，有不小的白色 像盒保存塊。
>> I'm just saying, hey, computer, get me a string.
>> 我只是說，嘿， 電腦，給我一個字符串。
The equal sign is not really an equal sign, per se.
等號是不是真的 一個等號，本身。
It's the assignment operator, which means,
這是分配 操作者，這意味著，
hey, computer, move the value from the right over to the left.
哎，電腦，移動值 從以上至左右。
And in the left, I have the following.
而在左邊，我有以下。
>> Hey, computer, give me a string-- a sequence of characters.
>> 嘿，電腦，給我一個string-- 字符序列。
And call that string Name.
並調用該字符串名稱。
And I don't even have to call it Name.
我甚至不具備調用它的名稱。
>> I could call it, conventionally, something like S,
>> 我可以調用它，按照慣例， 像S，
much like we used i to call the variable i.
就像我們用我來 調用變量i。
But now I need to do something with it.
但現在我需要用它做什麼。
It would be pretty stupid to try compiling this code, running
這將是非常愚蠢的 嘗試編譯這段代碼，運行
this program, even though I'm getting a string,
這個程序，即使 我得到一個字符串，
because it's still just going to say hello world.
因為它仍然只是 去打招呼的世界。
>> But what if I do want to change this.
>> 但是，如果我不想要什麼來改變這種狀況。
Why don't I do this?
我為什麼不這樣做呢？
Percent s, comma s.
％的S，逗號秒。
And this is a little cryptic still.
這是一個有點神秘依舊。
>> So let me make my variables more clear.
>> 所以，讓我的變量更加清晰。
Let me name this variable Name.
讓我這個變量名稱。
And let's see if we can't tease apart what's happening here.
讓我們看看如果我們不能去惹 除了這裡發生了什麼。
>> So on line five, I'm getting a string.
>> 因此，對五號線，我得到的字符串。
And I'm storing that string, whatever the user has typed in
而我存儲這個字符串， 無論用戶已鍵入的
at his or her keyboard, in a variable called Name.
在他或她的鍵盤， 在一個名為名稱的變量。
And it turns out that printf doesn't just
而事實證明， printf的不只是
take one argument in double quotes, one input in double quotes.
採取雙重一個參數 引號，在雙引號的輸入。
>> It can take two, or three, or more, such that the second, or third, or fourth,
>> 它可以採取兩個或三個，或更多，如 使第二，或第三，或第四，
are all the names of variables, or specifically values,
是變量所有的名字， 或者特別重視，
that you want to plug into, dynamically, that string in quotes.
要插入， 動態，用引號引起該字符串。
In other words, what would be wrong with this?
換句話說，什麼 將問題呢？
If I just said hello name, backslash n, saved my file, compiled my code,
如果我只是說你好名稱，反斜線 N，救了我的文件，我的編譯代碼，
and ran this, what would happen?
跑了這一點，會發生什麼？
>> It's just going to say, hello name, literally N-A-M-E,
>> 它只是會說，你好 名字，從字面上N-A-M-E，
which is kind of stupid because it's no different from world.
這是一種愚蠢的，因為 這是一個從世界上沒有什麼不同。
So anything in quotes is what literally gets printed.
因此，在行情是什麼 什麼字面上被打印出來。
So if I want to have a placeholder there,
所以，如果我想有 一個佔位符那裡，
I actually need to use some special syntax.
我真正需要使用 一些特殊的語法。
And it turns out if you read the documentation for the printf function,
而事實證明，如果你讀了 對於printf函數的文檔，
it will tell you that if you use percent s,
它會告訴你， 如果你使用％的S，
you can substitute a value as follows.
您可以按如下替換值。
>> After a comma after that double quote, you simply
>> 後一個逗號後 雙引號，你只需
write the name of the variable that you want
寫的名字 要變
to plug in into that format code, or format specifier,
插上到該格式 代碼或格式說明，
percent s for strings.
％的S代表字符串。
And now if I've saved my file, I go back down to my terminal.
現在，如果我救了我的文件， 我回去到我的終端。
And I type Make String, because, again, the name of this
而I型製作繩， 因為，再次，在此名稱
file that I chose before is string.c.
我之前選擇的文件是string.c。
>> So I'm going to say Make String, enter.
>> 所以，我要說讓字符串，請輸入。
Oh my goodness, look at all of the mistakes we've made already.
我的天哪，看看所有的 錯誤我們已經取得了。
And this is-- what, this is really like a six, seven line program?
而這is--什麼，這實在是 像六，七行程序？
So this is where it can very quickly get overwhelming.
因此，這是它可以很 快速獲得壓倒性的。
>> This terminal window has now just regurgitated
>> 該終端窗口有 現在只是反芻
a huge number of error messages.
數量巨大的錯誤消息。
Surely, I don't have more error messages than I have lines of code.
當然，我沒有更多的錯誤 消息比我行代碼。
So what is going on?
那麼到底是怎麼回事？
>> Well, the best strategy to do anytime you
>> 那麼，最好的策略 做到任何時候你
do encounter an overwhelming list of errors like that,
確實遇到了壓倒性 這樣的錯誤列表，
is scroll back, look for the command you just ran, which in my case
被回滾，查找命令 你剛剛運行，這在我的情況下，
is make string.
為使字符串。
Look at what make did, and that's that long Clang command, no big deal there.
看看什麼使所做的，就是這樣 長鐺命令，沒什麼大不了的存在。
>> But the red is bad.
>> 但紅色是壞的。
Green is trying to be gentle and helpful.
格林試圖將 溫柔，樂於助人。
But it's still bad, in this case.
但它仍然很糟糕，在這種情況下。
But where is it bad?
但是，在這樣做不好？
>> String.c, line five, character five.
>> String.c，五號線，性格五位。
So this is just common convention.
所以這只是常見的約定。
Something colon something means line number and character number.
結腸癌的東西意味著什麼 行數和字符數。
Error, use of undeclared identifier string.
錯誤，使用未申報 標識字符串。
Did you mean standard in?
你的意思是標準？
>> So, unfortunately, Clang is trying to be helpful.
>> 所以，不幸的是，鏘 試圖有所幫助。
But it's wrong, in this case.
但是，它是錯的，在這種情況下。
No, Clang, I did not mean standard IO.
不，鏘，我不是故意的標準IO。
I meant that on line one, yes.
我的意思是在同一行，不錯。
>> But line five is this one here.
>> 但是，五號線在這裡這一個。
And Clang does not understand S-T-R-I-N-G.
而鏘不 了解S-T-R-I-N-G。
It's an undeclared identifier, a word it just has never seen before.
這是一個未聲明的標識符， 一句話，它只是從來沒有見過的。
And that's because C, the language we're writing code in right now,
那是因為C，語言 我們在寫代碼的權利，
does not have variables called strings.
不具有的變量稱為串。
>> It doesn't, by default, support something called a string.
>> 這不，在默認情況下，支持 所謂的字符串。
That's a CS50 piece of jargon, but very conventional.
這是一個CS50一塊 行話，但很傳統。
But I can fix this as follows.
但是，我可以按如下方式解決這個問題。
>> If I add one line of code to the top of this program,
>> 如果我添加一行代碼 這個程序的頂部，
include CS50.h, which is another file somewhere inside of CS50 IDE, somewhere
包括CS50.h，這是另一種文件 裡面的某個地方IDE CS50的某處
on the hard drive, so to speak, of the Ubuntu operating system
在硬盤上，可以這麼說， 在Ubuntu操作系統
that I'm running, that is the file that's
我參加競選，這 是的文件
going to teach the operating system what a string is, just
要教工作 系統中的字符串是什麼，只是
like standard io.h is the file in the operating system that's
像標準io.h是文件 在操作系統中那
going to teach it what printf is.
要教它是什麼的printf。
>> Indeed, we would have gotten a very similar message
>> 事實上，我們會得到 一個非常類似的消息
if IO had admitted standard IO.h and tried to use printf.
如果IO也認標準 IO.h並試圖用printf。
So I'm going to go ahead and just take Control L to clear my screen.
所以我要繼續前進，只是 採取控制L到清除我的屏幕。
Or you can type clear and it will just clear the terminal window.
或者，您可以鍵入清晰，它會 只是清除終端窗口。
But you can still scroll back in time.
但你仍然可以在時間上向後滾動。
>> And I'm going to rerun Make String.
>> 而我要重新運行製作繩。
Cross my fingers this time, Enter.
穿過我的手指此時，回車。
Oh my God, it worked.
哦，我的上帝，它的工作。
it shows me a long cryptic command that is what Make generated via Clang,
它顯示了我很長的神秘命令 這是通過鏘請生成的內容，
but no error messages.
但沒有錯誤消息。
So realize, even though you might get completely
所以實現的，即使 你可能會得到完全
overwhelmed with the number of error messages,
此番與 錯誤信息的數量，
it just might be this annoying cascading effect, where Clang doesn't understand
也許會是這惱人的級聯 實際上，在那裡鏘不明白
one thing, which means it then doesn't understand the next word,
一方面，這意味著它然後 不理解下一個字，
or the next line.
或下一行。
And so it just chokes on your code.
所以它只是扼流圈您的代碼。
But the fix might be simple.
但是，該補丁可能很簡單。
And so always focus on the very first line of output.
所以始終圍繞 輸出的第一行。
And if you don't understand it, just look
如果你不這樣做 理解，只是看
for keywords that might be clues, and the line number,
關鍵字，可能是 線索，並且行號，
and the character, where that mistake might be.
和字符，其中 這種錯誤可能是。
>> Now let me go ahead and type dot slash, string, enter.
>> 現在讓我先走，然後鍵入 點斜線，字符串，請輸入。
Hm, it's not saying hello anything.
嗯，這不是打個招呼什麼。
Why?
為什麼？
Well, recall, where is it running?
好了，還記得，它在哪兒跑？
>> It's probably stuck at the moment in a loop, if you will, on line six,
>> 它可能停留在此刻 在一個循環中，如果你願意，六線，
because Get String by design, written by CS50 staff,
因為設計的GET字符串， 通過CS50的工作人員寫的，
is literally meant to just sit there waiting, and waiting,
字面意思只是坐在 在那裡等著，等著，
and waiting for a string.
並等待一個字符串。
All we mean by string is human input.
所有我們所說的字符串是人力的投入。
So you know what?
所以，你知道嗎？
Let me go ahead.
讓我先走。
And just on a whim, let me type my name, David, enter.
而就心血來潮，讓我 輸入我的名字，大衛進入。
Now I have a more dynamic program.
現在我有一個更加動態的程序。
It said, hello David.
它說，你好大衛。
>> If I go ahead and run this again, let me try say Zamila name, enter.
>> 如果我繼續前進，再次運行此， 讓我試試說Zamila名稱，輸入。
And now we have a dynamic program.
現在我們有一個動態的程序。
I haven't hard coded world.
我沒有硬編碼的世界。
I haven't hard coded name, or David, or Zamila.
我沒有硬編碼 名稱或大衛，或Zamila。
>> Now it's much more like the programs we know, where if it take input,
>> 現在它更像程序 我們知道，在那裡，如果需要輸入，
it produces slightly different output.
它產生的輸出結果略有不同。
Now, this is not the best user experience, or UX.
現在，這並不是最好的 用戶體驗，或者UX。
I run the program.
我運行該程序。
>> I don't know what I'm supposed to do, unless I actually look at
>> 我不知道我應該 這樣做，除非我其實看
or remember the source code.
或記住的源代碼。
So let's make the user experience a little better
因此，讓用戶 遇到好一點
with the simplest of things.
用最簡單的事情。
Let me go back into this program, and simply say printf.
讓我回去到這個 程序，簡單地說printf的。
>> And let me go ahead and say name, colon, and a space, and then a semi-colon.
>> 讓我繼續說名字，結腸， 和一個空間，然後分號。
And just for kicks, no backlash n.
而只是踢，無隙ñ。
And that's deliberate, because I don't want
這就是故意的， 因為我不想
the prompt to move to the next line.
提示移動到下一行。
>> I want to, instead, do this, make string to recompile my code into new machine
>> 我想，相反，這樣做，使串 重新編譯我的代碼到新機
code dot slash string.
代碼點斜線的字符串。
Ah, this is much prettier.
啊，這是非常漂亮。
Now I actually know what the computer wants me to do, give it a name.
現在，我實際上知道什麼是電腦 要我做的，給它一個名字。
>> So I'm going to go ahead and type in Rob, enter, and hello, Rob.
>> 所以我要繼續前進，並鍵入 在羅布，進入，你好，羅布。
So, realize, this is still, at the end of the day, only a nine line program.
因此，實現，這仍然是，在結束 當天，只有一個九行程序。
But we've taken these baby steps.
但是，我們已經採取了這些嬰兒的步驟。
>> We wrote one line with which we were familiar, printf, hello world.
>> 我們寫了一行與我們 熟悉，printf的，世界你好。
Then we undid a little bit of that.
然後，我們毀掉了那一點。
And we actually used get string.
而我們實際使用的GET字符串。
And we tossed that value in a variable.
而我們在扔一個變量值。
And then we went ahead and improved it further with a third line.
然後我們說乾就幹，提高 它進一步與第三行。
And this iterative process of writing software is truly key.
與此迭代過程 寫軟件是真正的關鍵。
In CS50, and in life in general, you should generally not sit down,
在CS50，而在一般的生活， 一般情況下不應坐下，
have a program in mind, and try writing the whole damn thing all at once.
心中有一個程序，並嘗試寫作 整個該死的事情一下子。
>> It will, inevitably, result in way more errors than we ourselves saw here.
>> 這將不可避免地導致的方式 更多的錯誤比我們自己在這裡看到。
Even I, to this day, constantly make other stupid mistakes,
就連我，為了這一天，不斷 讓其他愚蠢的錯誤，
are actually harder mistakes that are harder to figure out.
其實更難錯誤 這是很難搞清楚。
But you will make more mistakes the more lines of code you write all at once.
但你會犯更多的錯誤越多 行代碼你寫的一次。
And so this practice of, write a little bit of code
所以這種做法， 編寫代碼一點點
that you're comfortable with, compile it, run it, test it more generally,
你是舒服，編譯 它，運行它，更普遍的測試，
then move on-- so just like we kept layering and layering last week,
然後移動on--所以就像我們不停 分層和上週層次感，
building from something very simple to something more complex,
從建築的東西很 簡單，更複雜的東西，
do the same here.
做同樣的在這裡。
Don't sit down, and try to write an entire problem.
不要坐下來，並嘗試 寫一個完整的問題。
Actually take these baby steps.
實際上採取這些嬰兒的步驟。
>> Now, strings aren't all that useful unto themselves.
>> 現在，字符串是不是所有的 對自己有用。
We'd actually, ideally, like to have something else in our toolkit.
實際上，我們應該，理想情況下，喜歡 在我們的工具包東西。
So let's actually do exactly that.
因此，讓我們真正做到這一點。
>> Let me go ahead now and whip up a slightly different program.
>> 現在讓我繼續前進，掀起 一個稍微不同的程序。
And we'll call this int.c, for integer.
我們會打電話給這個int.c，為整數。
I'm going to, similarly, include CS550.h.
我要去，同樣， 包括CS550.h。
I'm going to include standard IO.
我將包括標準IO。
And that's going to be pretty common in these first few days of the class.
而這將是很常見 在類的這些最初幾天。
>> And I'm going to ready myself with a main function.
>> 而我要準備好 我自己用的主要功能。
And now instead of getting a string, let's go ahead and get an int.
而現在，而不是得到一個字符串， 讓我們繼續前進，並得到一個int。
Let's call it i, and call it get int, close parens, semi-colon.
讓我們把它叫做我，並把它弄 INT，關閉括號，分號。
And now let's do something with it, printf.
現在，讓我們做 東西吧，printf的。
>> Let's say something like hello, backslash n, comma i.
>> 比方說像 你好，反斜杠N，逗號我。
So I'm pretty much mimicking what I did just a moment ago.
所以，我幾乎模仿 我所做的只是一個剛才。
I have a placeholder here.
我有一個佔位符在這裡。
I have comma i here, because I want to plug i into that placeholder.
我在這裡用逗號我，因為我想 堵塞我到該佔位符。
>> So let's go ahead and try compiling this program.
>> 因此，讓我們繼續前進，並嘗試 編譯此程序。
The file is called int.c.
該文件稱為int.c.
So I'm going to say, make int, enter.
所以我要說，讓INT輸入。
Oh my God, but no big deal, right?
噢，我的上帝，但沒什麼大不了的，對不對？
There's a mistake.
有一個錯誤。
>> There's a syntactic mistake here such that the program can't
>> 有一個語法錯誤 這裡是程序不能
be compiled inside int.c, line seven, character 27, error format
裡面int.c，行編譯 七，性格27，錯誤格式
specifies type char star, whatever that is.
指定char類型 明星，不管它是什麼。
But the argument type is int.
不過，參數類型為int。
>> So here, too, we're not going to-- even though today is a lot of material,
>> 所以在這裡，我們不打算中場休息 雖然今天是很多的材料，
we're going to overwhelm you with absolutely every feature of C,
我們要以壓倒你 絕對的C每一個功能，
and programming more generally, in just these first few weeks.
和編程更一般地， 在短短的這些最初的幾個星期。
So there's often going to be jargon with which you're not familiar.
因此，有經常將是行話 與你不熟悉。
And, in fact, char star is something we're going to come back to
而且，事實上，焦炭星是什麼 我們要回來
in a week or two's time.
在兩個星期的時間。
>> But for now, let's see if we can parse words that are familiar.
>> 但現在，讓我們看看如果我們能 解析是熟悉的字眼。
Formats-- so we heard format specifier, format code before.
Formats--所以我們聽到的格式 說明，格式代碼之前。
That's familiar.
這是熟悉的。
Type-- but the argument has type int.
類型 - 但參數的類型為int。
Wait a minute, i is an int.
等一下，我是一個int。
>> Maybe percent s actually has some defined meaning.
>> 也許％的5事實上 有一些定義的含義。
And, indeed, it does.
而且，事實上，它的作用。
An integer, if you want printf to substitute it,
一個整數，如果你想 printf的替代它，
you actually have to use a different format specifier.
你確實有使用 不同的格式說明。
And you wouldn't know this unless someone told you,
你不會知道這 除非有人告訴你，
or you had done it before.
或者你已經這樣做。
But percent i is what can be commonly used
但是我百分之什麼 可共同使用
in printf for plugging in an integer.
在printf中的一個整數堵塞。
You can also use percent d for a decimal integer.
您還可以使用百分比 d表示十進制整數。
But i is nice and simple here.
但我是好的，簡單的在這裡。
So we'll go with that.
因此，我們將與該走了。
>> Now let me go ahead and rerun make int, Enter.
>> 現在讓我繼續前進， 重新運行化妝INT，回車。
That's good, no errors.
這是很好的，沒有錯誤。
Dot slash int-- OK, bad user experience, because I haven't told myself
點斜線int-- OK，不好的用戶體驗， 因為我沒有告訴自己
what to do.
該怎麼辦。
But that's fine.
但是，這很好。
I'm catching on quickly.
我迅速迎頭趕上。
>> And now let me go ahead and type in David, OK, Zamila, Rob.
>> 現在讓我去前進， 鍵入大衛，OK，Zamila，羅布。
OK, so this is a good thing.
好了，所以這是一件好事。
This time, I'm using a function, a puzzle piece, called get int.
這一次，我使用的功能， 一個拼圖，名為get int類型。
And it turns out-- and we'll see this later in the term--
而事實證明out--，我們將 看到這個以後在term--
the CS50 staff has implemented get string in such a way
該工作人員CS50已實施 以這樣的方式獲得的字符串
that it will only physically get a string for you.
它只會物理 得到你的字符串。
>> It has implemented get int in such a way that it will only
>> 它已經實施的get int類型 這樣一種方式，它僅將
get an integer for you.
得到一個整數你。
And if you, the human, don't cooperate, it's
如果你的人， 不配合，這是
literally just going to say retry, retry, retry,
從字面上只是要 說重試，重試，重試，
literally sitting there looping, until you oblige with some magical number,
從字面上坐在那裡循環，直到 你迫使一些神奇的數字，
like 50, and hello 50.
像50和50打招呼。
>> Or if we run this again and type in 42, hello 42.
>> 或者，如果我們再次運行此 並鍵入42，你好42。
And so the get int function inside of that puzzle piece
這樣一來，GET INT功能 那一塊拼圖內
is enough logic, enough thought, to figure out, what is a word?
足夠的邏輯，足夠的思想， 要弄清楚，什麼是一個字？
And what is a number?
什麼是多少？
Only accepting, ultimately, numbers.
只有接受，最終的數字。
>> So it turns out that this isn't all that expressive.
>> 因此，原來這 是不是所有的表現力。
so far.
至今。
So, yay, last time we went pretty quickly
所以，耶，我們最後一次 去很快
into implementing games, and animation, and artistic works in Scratch.
為實現遊戲和動畫， 在划痕和藝術作品。
And here, we are being content with hello world, and hello 50.
而在這裡，我們正在內容 與世界你好，你好和50。
>> It's not all that inspiring.
>> 這是不是所有的令人振奮。
And, indeed, these first few examples will take some time
而且，事實上，這些前幾 實施例將需要一些時間
to ramp up in excitement.
在興奮的增產行動。
But we have so much more control now, in fact.
但是，我們有這麼多 現在控制，實際上。
And we're going to very quickly start layering
而且我們要非常 快速啟動分層
on top of these basic primitives.
這些基本的原語的頂部。
>> But first, let's understand what the limitations are.
>> 但首先，讓我們了解 什麼限制是。
In fact, one of the things Scratch doesn't easily
的東西事實上，人們 刮不容易
let us do is really look underneath the hood,
讓我們做的是真正審視 引擎蓋下，
and understand what a computer is, what it can do,
並且明白什麼是 計算機是，它能做什麼，
and what its limitations are.
和它的局限性是什麼。
And, indeed, that lack of understanding, potentially, long-term
而且，事實上，缺乏的 理解，潛在地，長期
can lead to our own mistakes-- writing bugs, writing insecure software that
可以導致我們自己的寫作mistakes-- 錯誤，寫出不安全的軟件，
gets hacked in some way.
以某種方式被黑客攻擊。
>> So let's take some steps toward understanding this a little better by
>> 因此，讓我們對一些步驟 理解這一點更好一點通過
way of, say, the following example.
的，這樣說了，下面的例子。
I'm going to go ahead and implement real quick a program called Adder.
我要繼續前進，實現 真正的快一個叫做加法程序。
Like, let's add some numbers together.
像，讓我們添加一些數字加在一起。
And I'm going to code some corners here, and just copy and paste
而且我要編寫一些角落 在這裡，只是複製和粘貼
where I was before, just so we can get going sooner.
我在那裡之前，恰好 所以我們可以得到更快去。
So now I've got the basic beginnings of a program called Adder.
所以，現在我已經得到了基本的開端 一個叫做加法器程序。
>> And let's go ahead and do this.
>> 讓我們繼續前進，做到這一點。
I'm going to go ahead and say, intx gets get int.
我要繼續前進， 比方說和INTx得到得到int類型。
And you know what?
你知道嗎？
Let's make a better user experience.
讓我們做一個更好的用戶體驗。
>> So let's just say x is, and effectively prompt the user to give us x.
>> 所以讓我們只說X是有效的 提示用戶給我們的X.
And then let me go ahead and say, printf how about y is, this time expecting
然後讓我先走，說的printf 怎麼樣y是，這一次期待
two values from the user.
從用戶的兩個值。
And then let's just go ahead and say, printf, the sum of x and y is.
然後就讓我們繼續前進， 比方說，printf的，x和y的總和為。
And now I don't want to do percent s.
現在我不想做百分之秒。
I want to do percent i, backslash n, and then plug in sum value.
我想做％的我，反斜線 N，再插上總和值。
>> So how can I go about doing this?
>> 所以，我怎麼能去這樣做？
You know what?
你知道嗎？
I know how to use variables.
我知道如何使用變量。
Let me just declare a new one, int z.
讓我聲明一個新的，INT態。
>> And I'm going to take a guess here.
>> 而我要在這裡採取了猜測。
If there are equal signs in this language, maybe I can just do x plus y,
如果在此等號 語言，也許我可以做X加Y，
so long as I end my thought with a semi-colon?
只要我結束我的 用分號想？
Now I can go back down here, plug in z, finish this thought with a semi-colon.
現在我可以回到這裡了，插上Z， 完成本以為用分號。
And let's see now, if these sequences of lines-- x is get int.
而且，我們現在看到的，如果這些 lines-- x的序列是獲得int類型。
Y is get int.
Y是獲得int類型。
>> Add x and y, store the value in z-- so, again, remember the equal sign
>> 添加x和y，存儲在值z-- 所以，再一次，記住等號
is not equal.
是不相等的。
It's assignment from right to left.
這是從右到左分配。
And let's print out that the sum of x and y is not literally z,
讓我們打印出的總和 x和y的是不是字面上Z，
but what's inside of z.
但什麼的Z裡面。
So let's make Adder -- nice, no mistakes this time.
所以，讓我們做加法 - 不錯，沒有錯誤這一次。
Dot slash Adder, enter, x is going to be 1.
點斜線加法器，輸入， x被將是1。
>> Y is going to be 2.
>> Y為將是2。
And the sum of x and y is 3.
x和y的總和為3。
So that's all fine and good.
所以這是一切優秀和良好。
>> So you would imagine that math should work in a program like this.
>> 所以，你會想像數學 應該在這樣的程序中工作。
But you know what?
但是，你知道嗎？
Is this variable, line 12, even necessary?
這是可變的，行 12，甚至是必要的？
You don't need to get in the habit of just storing things in variables
你不需要的習慣得到 只是存儲在變數的事情
just because you can.
只是因為你可以。
And, in fact, it's generally considered bad design
並且，實際上，它通常是 認為是不好的設計
if you are creating a variable, called z in this case, storing something in it,
如果您正在創建一個變量，叫 中的Z這種情況下，存儲在它的東西，
and then immediately using it, but never again.
然後立即 使用它，但從來沒有一次。
Why give something a name like z if you're literally
為什麼要給東西的名字 像Z如果你從字面上
going to use that thing only once, and so
要使用該 事僅一次，所以
proximal to where you created it in the first place,
近端創建哪裡 它擺在首位，
so close in terms of lines of code?
如此接近的代碼行的條款？
So you know what?
所以，你知道嗎？
It turns out that C is pretty flexible.
事實證明，C是非常靈活。
If I actually want to plug-in values here,
如果我真的想 插件值這裡，
I don't need to declare a new variable.
我並不需要聲明一個新的變量。
I could just plug-in x plus y, because C understands
我可以外掛x加 Y，因為C理解
arithmetic, and mathematical operators.
算術和數學運算。
>> So I can simply say, do this math, x plus y, whatever those values are,
>> 所以，我可以簡單地說，這樣做數學， X加Y，無論這些值，
plug the resulting integer into that string.
堵塞造成 整成字符串。
So this might be, though only one line shorter,
因此，這可能是，雖然 只有一條線短，
a better design, a better program, because there's less code, therefore
一個更好的設計，更好的節目， 因為有更少的代碼，因此
less for me to understand.
少我明白。
And it's also just cleaner, insofar as we're not
而且這也只是清潔， 只要我們不是
introducing new words, new symbols, like z,
引進新詞， 新的符號，比如Z，
even though they don't really serve much of a purpose.
即使他們真的不 服務太大的目的。
>> Unfortunately, math isn't all that reliable sometimes.
>> 不幸的是，數學不是 所有可靠的時候。
Let's go ahead and do this.
讓我們繼續前進，並做到這一點。
I'm going to go ahead now and do the following.
我要繼續前進 現在做到以下幾點。
>> Let's do printf, percent i, plus percent i, shall be percent i, backslash n.
>> 讓我們做的printf，我百分之，百分之加 我，應該我百分之，反斜線ñ。
And I'm going to do this-- xyx plus y.
而我要做的this-- XYX加y。
So I'm just going to rewrite this slightly differently here.
所以我只是要改寫 此略有不同在這裡。
Let me just do a quick sanity check.
我只想做一個快速的健全性檢查。
Again, let's not get ahead of ourselves.
再次，讓我們不要超前。
Make adder, dot slash adder.
做加法，點斜線加法器。
x is 1, y is 2, 1 plus 2 is 3.
x為1，y為2，1加2是3。
So that's good.
所以這是很好的。
But let's complicate this now a bit, and create a new file.
但是，讓我們現在這個複雜 了一下，並創建一個新的文件。
>> I'm going to call this one, say, ints, plural for integers.
>> 我會打電話給這一個， 說，整型，複數的整數。
Let me start where I was a moment ago.
讓我先在那裡我是剛才。
But now let's do a few other lines.
但是，現在讓我們做一些其他的線路。
Let me go ahead and do the following, printf, percent i, minus percent i,
讓我繼續前進，做到以下幾點， printf的，我百分比，減去％的我，
is percent i, comma x, comma yx minus y.
是我百分之逗號X，逗號YX減Y。
So I'm doing slightly different math there.
所以我稍微做 不同的數學存在。
Let's do another one.
讓我們做一個又一個。
So percent i times percent i is percent i, backslash n.
所以，我百分之百分之倍 我是百分之一，反斜線ñ。
Let's plug-in x, and y, and x times y.
讓我們插件x和y，以及x乘以y。
We'll use the asterisk on your computer for times.
我們將使用星號上 您的計算機時代。
>> You don't use x. x is a variable name here.
>> 你不會用x。 x是 這裡變量名。
You use the star for multiplication.
你用乘法的明星。
Let's do one more.
讓我們做一個。
Printf percent I, divided by percent i, is percent i,
百分之printf的我，分 由百分之一，百分之是我，
backslash n. xy divided by y-- so you use the forward slash in C
反斜杠ñ。 XY由y--分 所以你用C中的正斜杠
to do division.
做除法。
And let's do one other.
讓我們做一個其他的。
Remainder of percent i, divided by percent i, is percent i.
我百分比剩餘，分 由百分之一，百分之是我。
xy-- and now remainder is what's left over.
xy--現在剩下的 是什麼遺留下來的。
When you try dividing a denominator into a numerator,
當您嘗試將一 分母變成分子，
how much is left over that you couldn't divide out?
有多少是遺留下來 你不能分裂出去？
>> So there isn't really, necessarily, a symbol
>> 所以是不是真的， 必須地，一個符號
we've used in grade school for this.
我們在小學用於此。
But there in C. You can say x modulo y, where
但是，在C.你可以 例如x模y，其中
this percent sign in this context-- confusingly when you're inside
在這個context--這個百分號 容易混淆的，當你在裡面
of the double quotes, inside of printf, percent
雙引號的， 裡面的printf，百分比
is used as the format specifier.
用作格式說明。
>> When you use percent outside of that in a mathematical expression,
>> 當您使用百分比之外 在數學表達式，
it's the modulo operator for modular arithmetic-- for our purposes
它是模塊化模運算符 arithmetic--我們的目的
here, just means, what is the remainder of x divided by y?
在這裡，只是意味著，什麼是 x的剩餘除以y？
So x divided by y is x slash y.
所以x除以y為x斜線年。
What's the remainder of x divided by y?
什麼是x的除以y的餘數？
It's x mod y, as a programmer would say.
它的x模Y，作為一個程序員會說。
>> So if I made no mistakes here, let me go ahead and make ints, plural, nice,
>> 所以，如果我在這裡沒有失誤，讓我 繼續前進，使整型，複數，美觀大方，
and dot slash ints.
和點斜線整數。
And let's go ahead and do, let's say, 1, 10.
讓我們繼續前進， 這樣做，比方說，1，10。
All right, 1 plus 10 is 11, check.
好吧，1加10是11，檢查。
1 minus 10 is negative 9, check.
1減去10為負9，檢查。
>> 1 times 10 is 10, check.
>> 1次10是10，檢查。
1 divided by 10 is-- OK, we'll skip that one.
1 10 is--分 OK，我們將跳過一個。
Remainder of 1 divided by 10 is 1.
餘數1除以10為1。
That's correct.
這是正確的。
But there's a bug in here.
但有一個錯誤在這裡。
>> So the one I put my hand over, not correct.
>> 所以，一個我把我的 交出，不正確的。
I mean, it's close to 0.
我的意思是，這是接近0。
1 divided by 10, you know, if we're cutting some corners, sure, it's zero.
1除以10，你知道，如果我們 削減一些角落，當然，它是零。
But it should really be 1/10, 0.1, or 0.10, 0.1000, or so forth.
但它確實應該1/10， 0.1或0.10，0.1000，或等等。
>> It should not really be zero.
>> 它真的不應該是零。
Well, it turns out that the computer is doing literally what we told it to do.
那麼，事實證明，電腦 從字面上做什麼，我們告訴它做的事。
We are doing math like x divided by y.
我們正在做數學一樣x除以y。
And both x and y, per the lines of code earlier, are integers.
和x和y，每行 代碼前，都是整數。
>> Moreover, on line 15, we are telling printf, hey, printf plug-in
>> 此外，第15行，我們都 告訴printf的，嘿嘿，printf的插件
an integer, plug-in an integer, plug-in an integer-- specifically
的整數，插件的整數， 插件的integer--具體
x, and then y, and then x divided by y. x and y are ints.
x，然後y和則x 除以y。 x和y是整數。
We're good there.
我們是好那裡。
>> But what is x divided by x?
>> 但是，為x除以x？
x divided by y should be, mathematically, 1/10, or 0.1,
點¯x分由y是應該的， 數學上，1/10，或0.1，
which is a real number, a real number having, potentially, a decimal point.
這是一個實數，一個實數 有潛在的，一個小數點。
It's not an integer.
這不是一個整數。
>> But what is the closest integer to 1/10, or 0.1?
>> 但是，什麼是最接近 整數到1/10，或0.1？
Yeah, it kind of is zero.
是的，這一種是零。
0.1 is like this much.
0.1是這個樣子了。
And 1 is this much.
和1是本得多。
So 1/10 is closer to 0 than it is to one.
所以1/10更接近 0比它為一個。
>> And so what C is doing for us-- kind of because we told it to--
>> 所以什麼C是做us-- 樣的，因為我們告訴它中場休息
is truncating that integer.
被截斷的整數。
It's taking the value, which again is supposed to be something like 0.1000,
它採取的值，而這又是 應該是這樣的0.1000，
0 and so forth.
0等等。
And it's truncating everything after the decimal point
而且這一切截斷 小數點後
so that all of this stuff, because it doesn't
這樣，所有這一切 的東西，因為它沒有
fit in the notion of an integer, which is just a number like negative 1, 0, 1,
適合的整數的概念，這 就像負1，0，1的數，
up and down, it throws away everything after the decimal point because you
上下，它拋出了一切 小數點，因為你以後
can't fit a decimal point in an integer by definition.
不適合小數點 在由定義的整數。
>> So the answer here is zero.
>> 因此，這裡的答案是零。
So how do we fix this?
那麼，我們如何解決這個問題？
We need another solution all together.
我們需要另一種解決方案都在一起。
And we can do this, as follows.
我們可以做到這一點，如下所示。
>> Let me go ahead and create a new file, this one called floats.c.
>> 讓我繼續前進，創造一個新的 文件中，這個叫floats.c。
And save it here in the same directory, float.c.
這裡保存了 同一目錄下，float.c。
And let me go ahead and copy some of that code from earlier.
讓我繼續和複製 一些早期的代碼。
>> But instead of getting an int, let's do this.
>> 但是，而不是領 一個int，讓我們做到這一點。
Give me a floating point value called x. where a floating point
給我一個浮點值 名為x。其中，浮點
value is just literally something with a floating point.
值只是從字面上 一些與一個浮點。
It can move to the left, to the right.
它可以移動到左邊，在右邊。
It's a real number.
這是一個實數。
>> And let me call not get int, but get float,
>> 讓我沒有打電話 得到INT，但得到浮動，
which also was among the menu of options in the C250 library.
這也就是菜單中 在C250庫選項。
Let's change y to a float.
讓我們修改y為float。
So this becomes get float.
因此，這將成為獲取浮動。
>> And now, we don't want to plug in ints.
>> 而現在，我們不希望在整數堵塞。
It turns out we have to use percent f for float, percent f for float,
事實證明，我們必須使用百分 如欲浮動，浮法％的樓
and now save it.
現在保存它。
And now, fingers crossed, make floats, nice, dot slash floats.
而現在，手指交叉，使 彩車，美觀大方，點斜線浮動。
x is going to be one 1. y Is going to be 10 again.
x被打算當1ÿ 將會再次成為10。
>> And, nice, OK my addition is correct.
>> 而且，美觀大方，OK我除了是正確的。
I was hoping for more, but I forgot to write it.
我希望更多的， 但我忘了寫。
So let's go and fix this logical error.
因此，讓我們去解決這個邏輯上的錯誤。
>> Let's go ahead and grab the following.
>> 讓我們繼續前進，抓住以下。
We'll just do a little copy and paste.
我們只是做一些複製和粘貼。
And I'm going to say minus.
而我要說負。
>> And I'm going to say times.
>> 而我要說倍。
And I'm going to say divided.
而我要說的分歧。
And I'm not going to do modulo, which is not as germane here,
而且我不會做模， 這是不一樣鍺這裡，
divided by f, and times plus-- OK, let's do this again.
用f分割，時間plus-- 好吧，讓我們再次做到這一點。
>> Make floats, dot slash floats, and 1, 10, and-- nice, no, OK.
>> 製作花車，點斜線花車， 1，10，還有 - 不錯，沒有，OK。
So I'm an idiot.
所以，我是個白痴。
So this is very common in computer science
因此，這是很常見 在計算機科學
to make stupid mistakes like this.
做出愚蠢的錯誤是這樣的。
>> For pedagogical purposes, what I really wanted to do
>> 用於教導的目的， 我真正想做的事
was change the science here to plus, to minus, to times,
在這裡改變科學 要加，零下，到時候，
and to divide, as you hopefully noticed during this exercise.
和來劃分，你希望 這個練習過程中發現。
So now let's re-compile this program, do dot slash floats.
現在讓我們重新編譯這個 節目，做點斜線浮動。
>> And for the third time, let's see if it meets my expectations.
>> 而第三次，我們 看它是否符合我的期望。
1, 10, enter, yes, OK, 1.000, divided by 10.000, is 0.100000.
1，10，輸入，是的，OK，1.000， 由10.000分，是0.100000。
And it turns out we can control how many numbers are after those decimal points.
而事實證明，我們能控制多少 數字是那些小數點後。
We actually will.
實際上，我們會的。
We'll come back to that.
我們會回來這一點。
>> But now, in fact, the math is correct.
>> 但現在，其實數學是正確的。
So, again, what's the takeaway here?
那麼，又是什麼這裡的外賣？
It turns out that in C, there are not only just strings-- and, in fact,
事實證明，在C，有 不僅只是strings--，事實上，
there aren't really, because we add those with the CS50 library.
有沒有真正的，因為我們 添加這些與CS50庫。
But there aren't just ints.
但也有不只是整數。
>> There are also floats.
>> 也有浮動。
And it turns out a bunch of other data types too, that we'll use before long.
而事實證明了一堆其他數據 類型也一樣，我們將在不久使用。
Turns out if you want a single character, not a string of characters,
事實證明，如果你想單 字符，而不是一個字符串，
you can use just a char.
你可以只使用一個char。
>> Turns out that if you want a bool, a Boolean value, true or false only,
>> 事實證明，如果你想有一個布爾值， 一個布爾值，只有真或假，
thanks to the CS50 library, we've added to C the bool data type as well.
感謝CS50庫，我們已經 添加到C BOOL數據類型為好。
But it's also present in many other languages as well.
但它也存在於 許多其他語言。
And it turns out that sometimes you need bigger numbers then come by default
而事實證明，有時你 需要更大的數字則默認情況下都
with ints and floats.
與整型和浮點型。
>> And, in fact, a double is a number that uses not 32 bits, but 64 bits.
>> 並且，實際上，雙是一個數字 使用不是32位，但64位。
And a long long is a number that uses not 32, bits but 64 bits,
和長隆是一個數字， 不使用32位，但64位，
respectively, for floating point values and integers, respectively.
分別為浮點 值和整數，分別為。
So let's actually now see this in action.
所以，讓我們現在實際上 看到這個動作。
>> I'm going to go ahead here and whip up one other program.
>> 我要在這裡繼續 並掀起另一個程序。
Here, I'm going to go ahead and do include CS50.h.
在這裡，我要繼續前進 並且確實包括CS50.h.
And let me go, include standard IO.h.
讓我走，包括標準IO.h.
>> And you'll notice something funky is happening here.
>> 你會發現什麼 時髦發生在這裡。
It's not color coding things in the same way as it did before.
這不是顏色編碼的東西 以同樣的方式，因為它以前那樣。
And it turns out, that's because I haven't given the thing a file name.
而事實證明，那是因為我 沒有給的東西的文件名。
>> I'm going to call this one sizeof.c, and hit Save.
>> 我會打電話給這一個 sizeof.c，並創下保存。
And notice what happens to my very white code against that black backdrop.
並注意發生了什麼我很 白色的代碼針對黑色背景。
Now, at least there's some purple in there.
現在，至少有 一些紫色在那裡。
And it is syntax highlighted.
它是語法高亮。
>> That's because, quite simply, I've told the IDE what type of file
>> 這是因為，很簡單，我已經 告訴IDE哪些類型的文件
it is by giving it a name, and specifically a file extension.
它是由給它一個名稱， 具體的文件擴展名。
Now, let's go ahead and do this.
現在，讓我們繼續前進，做到這一點。
I'm going to go ahead and very simply print out the following-- bool
我要繼續前進，很 簡單地打印出following--布爾
is percent LU.
是百分之LU。
>> We'll come back to that in just a moment.
>> 我們會回來的 在短短的時刻。
And then I'm going to print size of bool.
然後我要去 布爾的打印尺寸。
And now, just to save myself some time, I'm
而現在，只是為了節省 我有一段時間，我
going to do a whole bunch of these at once.
要做一個整體 這些一堆一次。
And, specifically, I'm going to change this to a char and char.
而且，具體而言，我要去 更改為一個char和char。
This one, I'm going to change to a double and a double.
這一次，我要改變 以一張雙人床和一個雙。
>> This one, I'm going to change to a float and a float.
>> 這一次，我要改變 一個浮子和一個浮動。
This one, I'm going to change to an int and an int.
這一次，我要去 更改為int和一個int。
And this one, I'm going to change to a long long.
而這一次，我要去 更改為一個很長很長。
And it's still taking a long time, long long.
它仍然採取 時間長了，很長很長。
>> And then, lastly, I gave myself one too many, string.
>> 然後，最後，我放棄 我太多了，字符串。
It turns out that in C, there's the special operator called
事實證明，在C，有 被稱為特殊的運算符
size of that's literally going to, when run,
那大小是字面上 要在運行時，
tell us the size of each of these variables.
告訴我們的大小 這些變量。
And this is a way, now, we can connect back
這是一種方式，現在， 我們可以連接回
to last week's discussion of data and representation.
上週的討論 數據和代表性。
>> Let me go ahead and compile size of dot slash size of.
>> 讓我繼續前進，編譯 的點斜線大小的尺寸。
And let's see.
讓我們來看看。
It turns out that in C, specifically on CS50 IDE,
事實證明，在C， 特別是在CS50 IDE，
specifically on the operating system Ubuntu,
特別是在 操作系統Ubuntu的，
which is a 64-bit operating system in this case,
這是一個64位操作 系統在此情況下，
a bool is going to use one byte of space.
一個布爾打算 使用的空間的一個字節。
That's how size is measured, not in bits, but in bytes.
這就是大小如何衡量， 不在位，但在字節。
And recall that one byte is eight bits.
並且記得，一個字節為8位。
So a bool, even though you technically only need a 0 or 1,
因此，一個布爾值，即使你 技術上只需要一個0或1，
it's a little wasteful how we've implemented it.
這是一個有點浪費 如何我們已經實現了它。
It's actually going to use a whole byte-- so all zeros, are maybe
它實際上是要使用一個整體 byte--因此所有零，也許是
all ones, or something like that, or just one 1 among eight bits.
所有的人，或者類似的東西， 或只是一個1間八位。
>> A char, meanwhile, used for a character like an Ascii character per last week,
>> 一個char，同時，用於字符 每一樣上週ASCII字符，
is going to be one character.
將是一個字符。
And that synchs up with our notion of it being no more than 256 bits-- rather,
這SYNCHS與我們的觀念 它是不超過256 bits--相當，
synchs up with it being no longer than 8 bits, which
SYNCHS了它是沒有 超過8位，這
gives us as many as 256 values.
為我們提供了多達256個值。
A double is going to be 8 bytes or 64 bits.
雙打算 為8字節或64位。
>> A float is 4.
>> 一個浮點是4。
An int is 4.
一個int是4。
A long, long is 8.
長，長為8。
And a string is 8.
和一個字符串為8。
But don't worry about that.
但是不要擔心。
We're going to peel back that layer.
我們要剝開那層。
It turns out, strings can be longer than 8 bytes.
事實證明，字符串可以 超過8個字節。
>> And, indeed, we've written strings already, hello world,
>> 而且，事實上，我們已經寫 弦已經，世界你好，
longer than 8 bytes.
超過8個字節。
But we'll come back to that in just a moment.
但是，我們會回來的 在短短的時刻。
But the take away here is the following.
但帶走這裡如下。
>> Any computer only has a finite amount of memory and space.
>> 任何計算機中僅具有有限 的存儲器和空間量。
You can only store so many files on your Mac or PC.
你只能儲存那麼多 你的Mac或PC上的文件。
You can only store so many programs in RAM running at once, necessarily, even
您只能存儲在這麼多程序 RAM運行一次，一定，甚至
with virtual memory, because you have a finite amount of RAM.
使用虛擬內存，因為 你的內存有限數量。
>> And just to picture-- if you've never opened up a laptop
>> 而只是為了picture--如果 你從來沒有打開一台筆記本電腦
or ordered extra memory for a computer, you
或下令額外的內存 對於一台電腦，你
might not know that inside of your computer
可能不知道 你的電腦裡面
is something that looks a little like this.
是一些看起來 有點像這樣。
So this is just a common company named Crucial that makes RAM for computers.
所以，這只是一個普通的公司命名為 至關重要的是，使計算機的RAM。
And RAM is where programs live while they're running.
和RAM就是程序 而他們正在運行生活。
>> So on every Mac or PC, when you double click a program, and it opens up,
>> 所以每次Mac或PC，當您雙擊上 點擊一個程序，它打開了，
and it opens some Word document or something like that,
它打開了一些Word文檔 或類似的東西，
it stores it temporarily in RAM, because RAM is faster
它存儲在臨時 RAM，RAM因為速度更快
than your hard disk, or your solid state disk.
比你的硬盤上，或 你的固態硬盤。
So it's just where programs go to live when they're running,
所以，這只是程序的地方去 當他們正在運行的生活，
or when files are being used.
或當正在使用的文件。
>> So you have things that look like this inside of your laptop,
>> 所以，你有事情看起來 這樣你的筆記本電腦裡面，
or slightly bigger things inside of your desktop.
或者稍微大一點的東西 裡面的桌面。
But the key is you only have a finite number of these things.
但關鍵是你只有一個 有限數量的這些事情。
And there's only a finite amount of hardware sitting on this desk right
還有的只是一個有限的 硬件坐在這張桌子右邊
here.
這裡。
>> So, surely, we can't store infinitely long numbers.
>> 因此，可以肯定，我們不能存儲 無限長的數字。
And, yet, if you think back to grade school, how many digits can
而且，然而，如果你想回 小學的時候，有多少位可以
you have to the right of a decimal point?
你有權利 一個小數點？
For that matter, how many digits can you have to the left of a decimal point?
對於這個問題，有多少位可以 你有一個小數點左邊？
Really, infinitely many.
真的，無限多的。
>> Now, we humans might only know how to pronounce million,
>> 現在，我們人類唯一可能 知道如何發音萬元，
and billion, trillion, and quadrillion, and quintillion.
和十億，萬億，和 萬億和三次方。
And I'm pushing the limits of my understanding-- or my-- I understand
而我推的限制我 understanding--或my--我明白
numbers, but my pronunciation of numbers.
數字，但我 數字的發音。
But they can get infinitely large with infinitely many digits to the left
但他們可以得到無限大 無限多的數字向左
or to the right of a decimal point.
或小數點的右邊。
>> But computers only have a finite amount of memory,
>> 但電腦只有一個 內存量有限，
a finite number of transistors, a finite number of light bulbs inside.
晶體管的一個有限數量，一 數量有限的內部燈泡。
So what happens when you run out of space?
會發生什麼時 您運行的空間？
In other words, if you think back to last week
換句話說，如果 回想起上週
when we talked about numbers themselves being represented in binary,
當我們談到數字 自己被代表二進制，
suppose that we've got this 8-bit value here.
假設我們有 這8位值在這裡。
>> And we have seven 1's and one 0.
>> 而且我們有七個1的和一個0。
And suppose that we want to add 1 to this value.
而假設我們想 添加1至這個值。
This is a really big number right now.
這是一個非常大的數字現在。
>> This is 254, if I remember the math from last week right.
>> 這是254，如果我沒有記錯 從上週權的數學。
But what if I change that rightmost 0 to a 1?
但是，如果我改變 最右邊是0到1？
The whole number, of course, becomes eight 1's.
整數， 當然，成為8個1的。
So we're still good.
所以，我們還是不錯的。
>> And that probably represents 255, though depending on context
>> 這可能代表 255，雖然根據上下文
it could actually represent a negative number.
它實際上代表 負數。
But more on that another time.
但更多的是另一次。
This feels like it's about as high as I can count.
這感覺就像它是關於 高達我可以指望。
>> Now, it's only 8 bits.
>> 現在，它只有8位。
And my Mac, surely, has way more than 8 bits of memory.
而我的Mac，當然，有辦法 內存大於8位。
But it does have finite.
但它確實有有限的。
So the same argument applies, even if we have more of these ones on the screen.
所以同樣的觀點也適用，即使我們 有更多的人，這些在屏幕上。
>> But what happens if you're storing this number, 255,
>> 但是，如果你發生了什麼 存儲該號碼，255，
and you want to count 1 bit higher?
並且要算1位高？
You want to go from 255 to 256.
你想去從255到256。
The problem, of course, is that if you start counting at zero like last week,
的問題，當然，是如果 從零開始，就像上週算起，
you can't count as high as 256, let alone 257,
你不能指望高 256，更不用說257，
let alone 258,m because what happens when you add a 1?
別說258，男因為什麼 當您添加1會怎麼樣？
If you do the old grade school approach, you put a 1 here,
如果你做舊小學 方法，你把這裡1，
and then 1 plus 1 is 2, but that's really a zero, you carry the 1,
然後1加1是2，但是這 真的是零，你扛1，
carry the 1, carry the 1.
扛1，攜帶1。
All of these things, these 1's, go to zero.
所有這些事情， 這些1的，去到零。
And you wind up, yes, as someone pointed out, a 1 on the left hand side.
和你風，是的，正如有人 在左手側所指出的，一個1。
But everything you can actually see and fit in memory
但是，一切都可以 真正看到並裝入內存
is just eight 0's, which is to say at some point if you, a computer,
是只有八0年代，這是說 在某些時候，如果你一台電腦，
tried counting high enough up, you're going to wrap around, it would seem,
試著計數足夠高了，你 要環繞，這似乎
to zero, or maybe even negative numbers, which are even lower than zero.
零，或者甚至負 號，這是大於零甚至更低。
>> And we can kind of see this.
>> 我們可以樣的看到這一點。
Let me go ahead and write a real quick program here.
我要繼續寫 一個真正的快速程序在這裡。
a program called Overflow.
一個叫溢出程序。
Include CS50.h, include standard IO.h-- oh,
包括CS50.h包括 標準IO.h--哦，
I really missed my syntax highlighting.
我真的很想念我的語法高亮。
So let's save this as overflow.c.
因此，讓我們這個保存為overflow.c。
>> And now int main void-- and before long, we'll
>> 而現在INT主要void-- 過不了多久，我們就會
come back to explaining why we keep writing int main void.
回過頭來解釋為什麼 我們繼續寫INT主作廢。
But for now, let's just do it, taking it for granted.
但現在，我們只是做 它，視之為理所當然。
Let's give myself an int, and initialize it to 0.
讓我們給自己一個int， 並初始化為0。
>> Let's then do for int i get zero-- actually, let's do an infinite loop
>> 讓我們再對INT做我得到zero-- 其實，讓我們做一個無限循環
and see what happens.
看看會發生什麼。
While true, then let's print out n is percent i, backslash n, plug-in n.
雖然如此，那麼讓我們打印出ñ 是我百分比，反斜線N，插件在正。
But, now, let's do n gets n plus 1.
但是，現在，讓我們做n得到n與1。
>> So in other words, on each iteration of this infinite loop,
>> 因此，換句話說，在每 這個無限循環迭代，
let's take n's value, and add 1 to it, and then
讓我們取n的值， 並把它加1，然後
store the result back in n on the left.
將結果存儲回在正在左側。
And, in fact, we've seen syntax slightly like this, briefly.
而且，事實上，我們已經看到了語法 微微就是這樣，簡單。
A cool trick is instead of writing all this out,
一個很棒的技巧反而 編寫出這一切的，
you can actually say an n plus equals 1.
你可以居然說一個n加等於1。
>> Or if you really want to be fancy, you can say n plus plus semi-colon.
>> 或者，如果你真的想成為幻想， 你可以說n與加分號。
But these latter two are just what we'd call syntactic sugar
但後​​兩個都只是 我們會打電話語法糖
for the first thing.
對的第一件事。
>> The first thing is more explicit, totally fine, totally correct.
>> 的第一件事是更加明確， 完全正常的，完全正確的。
But this is more common, I'll say.
但是，這是比較常見的，我會說。
So we'll do this for just a moment.
所以，我們會為短短的時刻做到這一點。
>> Let's now make overflow, which sounds rather ominous, dot slash overflow.
>> 現在，讓我們做溢出，這聽起來 而不祥，點斜線溢出。
Let's see, n's getting pretty big.
讓我們來看看，正變得越來越蠻大的。
But let's think, how big can n get?
但我們認為，有多大可能得到ň？
>> n is an int.
>> n是一個int。
We saw a moment ago with the size of example that an int is four bytes.
我們看到剛才用的大小 例子，一個int是四個字節。
We know from last week, four bytes is 32 bits, because 8 times 4, that's 32.
我們從上週知道，四個字節是 32位，因為8次4，這是32。
That's going to be 4 billion.
那將是4個十億。
>> And we are up to 800,000.
>> 而我們可達80萬。
This is going to take forever to count as high as I possibly can.
這將永遠採取 數高達我所能。
So I'm going to go ahead, as you might before long,
所以我要繼續前進， 正如你可能過不了多久，
and hit Control C-- frankly, Control C, a lot, where Control C generally
並創下控制C--坦言，控制 C，很多，其中對照C一般
means cancel.
手段取消。
Unfortunately, because this is running in the cloud,
不幸的是，因為這 在雲中運行時，
sometimes the cloud is spitting out so much stuff,
有時雲 吐出了這麼多東西，
so much output, it's going to take a little while for my input
如此多的產量，這將 取一小會兒我輸入
to get to the cloud.
去雲。
So even though I hit Control C a few seconds ago,
所以，即使我打 對照C幾秒鐘前，
this is definitely the side effect of an infinite loop.
這絕對是側 無限循環的效果。
>> And so in such cases, we're going to leave that be.
>> 因此在這種情況下，我們 要離開的是。
And we're going to add another terminal window over here
而且我們要增加另一個 在這裡的終端窗口
with the plus, which of course doesn't like that, since it's still thinking.
與加，這當然不 這樣，因為它仍在思考。
And let's go ahead and be a little more reasonable.
讓我們繼續前進，並 多了幾分合理性。
>> I'm going to go ahead and do this only finitely many times.
>> 我要繼續前進，做 這只有有限多次。
Let's use a for loop, which I alluded to earlier.
讓我們用一個for循環， 我前面提到。
Let's do this.
我們開工吧。
Give me another variable int i gets 0.
再給我一次變量int我得到0。
i is less than, let's say, 64 i++.
我不到，比方說，64個I ++。
And now let me go ahead and print out n is percent i, comma n.
現在讓我繼續和打印 出n是百分之一，逗號ñ。
And then n-- this is still going to take forever.
然後N--這仍然是 要採取永遠。
Let's do this.
我們開工吧。
>> n gets n times 2.
>> n得到n次2。
Or we could be fancy and do times equals 2.
或者我們可以被看中 做次等於2。
But let's just say n equals itself, times 2.
但是，讓我們只說ñ 等於本身，乘以2。
In other words, in this new version of the program,
換句話說，在該 程序的新版本，
I don't want to wait forever from like 800,000 to 4 billion.
我不想永遠等待 從像80萬至4十億。
Let's just get this over with.
就讓我們這種過度使用。
>> Let's actually double n each time.
>> 讓我們實際上每次加倍ñ。
Which, recall, doubling is the opposite of having, of course.
其中，召回，加倍是 對面有當然的。
And whereas last week we have something again, and again,
和而上週我們有 重複的事情，並再次，
and again, super fast, doubling will surely
又一次，超快速， 加倍必將
get us from 1 to the biggest possible value that we can count to with an int.
1讓我們以最大的可能 值，我們可以用一個int計數。
>> So let's do exactly this.
>> 因此，讓我們做的正是這一點。
And we'll come back to this before long.
我們再回過頭來此不久。
But this, again, is just like the repeat block in Scratch.
但是這又好比 在從無到有的重複塊。
And you'll use this before long.
你會不久使用。
>> This just means count from zero up to, but not equal, to 64.
>> 這也就意味著，從零計數 達，但不相等，為64。
And on each iteration of this loop, just keep incrementing i.
而在此每次迭代 循環，只是不停地增加i。
So i++-- and this general construct on line 7 is just a super common way
所以，我++  - 這一般結構 第7行僅僅是一個超級常見的方式
of repeating some lines of code, some number of times.
重複的部分線路 代碼，一些次數。
Which lines of code?
哪行代碼？
These curly braces, as you may have gleaned from now,
這些大括號，如你 可能從現在收集，
means, do the following.
手段，做到以下幾點。
>> It's in like Scratch, when it has the yellow blocks
>> 它像划痕，當 它具有黃色塊
and other colors that kind of embrace or hug other blocks.
和其他顏色的那種 擁抱或擁抱其他塊。
That's what those curly braces are doing here.
這就是那些花 括號在這裡做。
So if I got my syntax right-- you can see the carrot symbol in C means
所以，如果我得到了我的語法right--你 可以看到C表示胡蘿蔔符號
that's how many times I was trying to solve this problem.
這就是我多少次 試圖解決這個問題。
So let's get rid of that one altogether, and close that window.
因此，讓我們擺脫的那一個 乾脆，並關閉該窗口。
And we'll use the new one.
我們將使用新的。
Make overflow, dot slash overflow, Enter, all right,
使溢出，點斜杠 溢出，進入，所有的權利，
it looks bad at first.
它看起來壞在第一。
But let's scroll back in time, because I did this 64 times.
但是，讓我們向後滾動的時候， 因為我這樣做64次。
>> And notice the first time, n is 1.
>> 和在第一時間通知，n是1。
Second time, n is 2, then 4, then 8, then 16.
第二次，n為2， 然後4，然後按8，然後16。
And it seems that as soon as I get to roughly 1 billion,
並盡快似乎 我得到低於約1十億，
if I double it again, that should give me 2 billion.
如果我再翻一番它， 應該給我兩十億。
But it turns out, it's right on the cusp.
但事實證明，這是 正確的風口浪尖上。
>> And so it actually overflows an int from 1 billion
>> 所以它實際上溢出 1十億一個int
to roughly negative 2 billion, because an integer,
大致2負 十億，因為一個整數，
unlike the numbers we were assuming last week,
不像我們的數字 上週假設，
can be both positive and negative in reality and in a computer.
既可以是正和負 在現實中，並在一台計算機。
And so at least one of those bits is effectively stolen.
而這些，所以至少一個 位被有效被盜。
So we really only have 31 bits, or 2 billion possible values.
所以，我們真的只有31位， 或2十億可能的值。
>> But for now, the takeaway is quite simply, whatever these numbers are
>> 但就目前而言，外賣相當 簡單地說，不管這些數字
and whatever the math is, something bad happens eventually,
而無論數學， 有壞事發生，最終，
because eventually you are trying to permute the bits one too many times.
因為最終你試圖 重排的位太多次。
And you effectively go from all 1's to maybe all 0's, or maybe
你有效地都去 1對也許所有0，或者
just some other pattern that it clearly, depending on context,
只是一些其他的模式，它 清楚地，根據上下文，
can be interpreted as a negative number.
可以理解為一個負數。
And so it would seem the highest I can count in this particular program
因此它似乎最高的I 可以在這個特定的程序計數
is only roughly 1 billion.
只有大約1十億。
But there's a partial solution here.
但是，這裡有一個部分解決方案。
You know what?
你知道嗎？
>> Let me change from an int to a long long.
>> 讓我從改變 詮釋一個很長很長。
And let me go ahead here and say-- I'm going to have
讓我繼續在這裡 和say--我將有
to change this to an unsigned long.
要改變這種為unsigned long。
Or, let's see, I never remember myself.
或者，讓我們來看看，我從來不記得自己。
>> Let's go ahead and make overflow.
>> 讓我們繼續前進，使溢出。
No, that's not it, LLD, thank you.
不，這不是它，LLD，謝謝。
So sometimes Clang can be helpful.
所以有時鏘能有所幫助。
I did not remember what the format specifier was for a long long.
我不記得是什麼格式 說明是一個很長很長。
>> But, indeed, Clang told me.
>> 但是，事實上，鏘告訴我的。
Green is some kind of good, still means you made a mistake.
綠色是某種好， 仍然意味著你犯了一個錯誤。
It's guessing that I meant LLD.
它是猜，我的意思是LLD。
>> So let me take it's advice, a long long decimal number, save that.
>> 因此，讓我把它的建議，長 長十進制數，保存。
And let me rerun it, dot slash overflow, Enter.
讓我重新運行它，點 斜線溢出，回車。
And now what's cool is this.
現在什麼是酷是這樣的。
>> If I scroll back in time, we still start counting at the same place-- 1, 2, 4,
>> 如果我回卷的時候，我們還是開始 在同一place--計數1，2，4，
8, 16.
8，16。
Notice, we get all the way up to 1 billion.
請注意，我們得到了所有的 一路攀升至1十億。
But then we safely get to 2 billion.
但是，我們安全到達2十億。
>> Then we get to 4 billion, then 8 billion, 17 billion.
>> 然後我們4十億， 然後從8十億，17個十億。
And we go higher, and higher, and higher.
而我們走的更高，而且 越來越高。
Eventually, this, too, breaks.
最終，這也算休息。
>> Eventually, with a long long, which is the 64-bit value, not
>> 最終，用長長的， 它是64位的值，而不是
a 32-bit value, if you count too high, you wrap around 0.
一個32位的值，如果算上 過高，環繞0。
And in this case, we happen to end up with a negative number.
在這種情況下，我們碰巧 結束了一個負數。
>> So this is a problem.
>> 因此，這是一個問題。
And it turns out that this problem is not all that arcane.
而事實證明，這 問題是，不是所有的神秘。
Even though I've deliberately induced it with these mistakes,
即使我刻意 這些錯誤引起的，
it turns out we see it kind of all around us, or at least some of us do.
事實證明，我們那種看到它的全部 我們，或者至少我們中的一些周圍的人。
>> So in Lego Star Wars, if you've ever played the game,
>> 因此，在樂高星球大戰，如果 你曾經玩過的遊戲，
it turns out you can go around breaking things up in LEGO world,
事實證明，你可以去周圍 打破東西在世界樂高，
and collecting coins, essentially.
和收集硬幣，本質上。
And if you've ever played this game way too much time,
如果你打過 這個遊戲了太多的時間，
as this unnamed individual here did, the total number
因為這無名的個人 在這裡做到了，總數
of coins that you can collect is, it would seem, 4 billion.
你可以收集硬幣 是，它似乎，4個十億。
>> Now, with it's actually rounded.
>> 現在，它的實際四捨五入。
So LEGO was trying to keep things user friendly.
所以LEGO試圖 讓事情變得人性化。
They didn't do it exactly 2 to the 32 power, per last week.
他們沒有做到這一點正是2 32次冪，每上週。
But 4 billion is a reason.
但4個十億是一個道理。
It seems, based on this information, that LEGO, and the company that
看來，基於該信息， 這LEGO，該公司的
made this actual software, decided that the maximum number of coins
使這個實際的軟件，決定 該硬幣的最大數目
the user can accumulate is, indeed, 4 billion,
用戶可以積累 確實是，4個十億，
because they chose in their code to use not a long long, apparently,
因為他們選擇在自己的代碼 使用不是很長很長，很顯然，
but just an integer, an unsigned integer, only a positive integer, whose
但僅僅是一個整數，一個無符號 整數，只有一個正整數，其
max value is roughly that.
最大值大約是這一點。
Well, here's another funny one.
那麼，這裡的另一個有趣的。
So in the game Civilization, which some of you might be familiar, with
所以在遊戲中文明，這 有些人可能很熟悉，與
it turns out that years ago there was a bug in this game whereby
原來，幾年前有 在本場比賽由此錯誤
if you played the role of Gandhi in the game,
如果你所扮演的角色 甘地在比賽中，
instead of him being very pacifist, instead was incredibly, incredibly
代替他的是非常和平， 反而是令人難以置信的，令人難以置信
aggressive, in some circumstances.
攻擊性，在某些情況下。
In particular, the way that Civilization works is that if you, the player,
特別是，方式文明 作品是，如果您的播放器，
adopt democracy, your aggressiveness score gets
採取民主，你 侵略性成績獲得
decremented by two, so minus minus, and then minus minus.
由兩個，所以減去遞減 減，再減去負。
>> So you subtract 2 from your actual iterating.
>> 所以你減去2從 實際的迭代。
Unfortunately, if your iterating is initially 1, and you subtract 2 from it
不幸的是，如果你的是迭代 最初1，你從中減去2
after adopting democracy as Gandhi here might
採用經過民主 甘地在這裡可能
have done, because he was very passive-- 1 on the scale of aggressiveness.
這樣做，是因為他很passive-- 1對侵略性的規模。
But if he adopts democracy, then he goes from 1 to negative 1.
但是，如果他採取民主，那麼 他去從1到1負。
>> Unfortunately, they were using unsigned numbers,
>> 不幸的是，它們是 使用無符號數，
which means they treated even negative numbers as though they were positive.
這意味著他們對待甚至是負 數字，好像他們是積極的。
And it turns out that the positive equivalent of negative 1,
而且事實證明， 負1陽性當量，
in typical computer programs, is 255.
在典型的計算機程序，為255。
So if Gandhi adopts democracy, and therefore has
因此，如果採用甘地 ，因此具有民主
his aggressiveness score decreased, it actually rolls around to 255
他的侵略性評分下降， 它實際上來臨時，以255
and makes him the most aggressive character in the game.
而讓他最 侵略性的比賽。
So you can Google up on this.
所以，你可以在此Google了。
And it was, indeed, an accidental programming bug,
而且，的確是一個 意外編程錯誤，
but that's entered quite the lore ever since.
但是這相當進入 絕殺至今。
>> That's all fun and cute.
>> 這是所有的樂趣和可愛。
More frightening is when actual real world devices, and not games,
更可怕的是，當實際 真實世界的設備，而不是遊戲，
have these same bugs.
有這些相同的錯誤。
In fact, just a year ago an article came out about the Boeing 787 Dreamliner.
事實上，就在一年前的一篇文章來了 更多關於波音787夢想飛機。
>> And the article at first glance reads a little arcane.
>> 和製品在第一 讀取一目了然有點神秘。
But it said this, a software vulnerability in Boeing's
但它說，這是一家軟件 在波音公司的脆弱性
new 787 Dreamliner jet has the potential to cause pilots
新型787夢想飛機具有 可能造成飛行員
to lose control of the aircraft, possibly
失去控制 飛機，可能
in mid-flight, the FAA officials warned airlines recently.
在飛行中，美國聯邦航空局官員 告誡航空公司最近。
It was the determination that a model 787
這是確定 一個模型787
airplane that has been powered continuously for 248 days
已通電飛機 連續248天
can lose all alternating current, AC, electrical power due to the generator
可能會失去所有的交流電流，交流， 電功率，由於發電機
control units, GCUs, simultaneously going into fail safe mode.
控制單元，同時GCUs， 進入故障安全模式。
It's kind of losing me.
這是一種失去我的。
But the memo stated, OK, now I got that, the condition was caused by a software
但備忘錄說，好了，現在我得到的， 條件是由軟件引起的
counter internal to the generator control
專櫃內部 發電機控制
units that will overflow after 248 days of continuous power.
單元後，將溢出 248天連續功率。
We are issuing this notice to prevent loss
頒發本 注意防止損失
of all AC electrical power, which could result
所有交流電 功率，這可能導致
in loss of control of the airplane.
在飛機的失控。
>> So, literally, there is some integer, or some equivalent data type,
>> 所以，從字面上看，有一些整數， 或者一些等價的數據類型，
being used in software in an actual airplane
在軟件被使用 在實際的飛機
that if you keep your airplane on long enough, which apparently
如果你保持你的飛機 足夠長的時間，這顯然
can be the case if you're just running them constantly and never unplugging
可如果你只是運行情況 他們不斷地從不拔下
your airplane, it seems, or letting its batteries die,
你的飛機，現在看來，還是 讓其電池不行了，
will eventually count up, and up, and up, and up, and up, and up.
將最終計數和向上， 和起來，向上，及以上，和向上。
>> And, by nature, a finite amount of memory
>> 並且，按質，一 內存數量有限
will overflow, rolling back to zero or some negative value,
會溢出，回滾到 零或者一些負值，
a side effect of which is the frighteningly real reality
其中的一個副作用是 實得嚇人現實
that the plane might need to be rebooted, effectively,
這架飛機可能需要 必須重新啟動，有效，
or might fall, worse, as it flies.
也可能下降，更糟糕的，因為它飛起來。
So these kinds of issues are still with us,
所以這類問題 仍然伴隨著我們，
even-- this was a 2015 article, all the more frightening
even--這是一個2015年的文章， 所有的更可怕
when you don't necessarily understand, appreciate, or anticipate
當你不一定 理解，欣賞，或預期
those kinds of errors.
這些類型的錯誤。
>> So it turns out there's one other bad thing about data representation.
>> 因此，原來還有另一個 有關數據表示壞事。
It turns out that even floats are kind of flawed, because floats, too,
事實證明，即使花車 樣的缺陷，因為花車也是如此，
I proposed are 32 bits, or maybe 64 if you use a double.
我提出的是32位的，或 也許64如果你使用雙。
But that's still finite.
但是，這仍然是有限的。
>> And the catch is that if you can put an infinite number of numbers
>> 而美中不足的是，如果你能 把數的無限數量
after the decimal point, there is no way you
小數點後， 沒有辦法，你
can represent all the possible numbers that we were taught
可以代表所有可能的 我們被教導號碼
in grade school can exist in the world.
在小學可以在世界上存在。
A computer, essentially, has to choose a subset of those numbers
一台電腦，從本質上講，有 選擇這些數字的一個子集
to represent accurately.
準確地表示。
>> Now, the computer can round maybe a little bit,
>> 現在，該計算機可以 輪也許一點點，
and can allow you to roughly store any number you might possibly want.
並且可以讓你大致店 任何號碼，你有可能會需要。
But just intuitively, if you have a finite number of bits,
但是，僅僅憑直覺，如果你 有比特的有限數目，
you can only permute them in so many finite ways.
你只能他們重排 在很多方面有限。
So you can't possibly use a finite number
所以，你不可能 用有限數量的
of permutation of bits, patterns of zeros and ones,
比特置換， 零和一的模式，
to represent an infinite number of numbers,
代表無限 號的數目，
which suggests that computers might very well be lying to us sometimes.
這表明計算機可能 很好是對我們撒謊的時候。
>> In fact, let's do this.
>> 事實上，讓我們做到這一點。
Let me go back into CS50 IDE.
讓我重新回到CS50 IDE。
Let me go ahead and create a little program
讓我繼續前進， 創建一個小程序
called Imprecision, to show that computers are, indeed, imprecise.
叫不精確，就表明 電腦的確都是不精確的。
>> And let me go ahead and start with some of that code from before,
>> 讓我繼續前進，並與開始 一些代碼來自之前，
and now just do the following.
現在只要做到以下幾點。
Let me go ahead and do printf, percent f, backslash n, 1 divided by 10.
我要繼續做的printf，百分比 樓反斜線N，1除以10。
In other words, let's dive in deeper to 1/10, like 1 and divided by 10.
換句話說，讓我們在更深的下潛 到1/10，象1和除以10。
Surely, a computer can represent 1/10.
當然，一個計算機可以代表1/10。
>> So let's go ahead and make imprecision.
>> 因此，讓我們繼續前進，使不精確。
Let's see.
讓我們來看看。
Format specifies type double.
格式指定double類型。
But the argument has type int.
但參數的類型為int。
What's going on?
這是怎麼回事？
>> Oh, interesting, so it's a lesson learned from before.
>> 呵呵，有意思，所以這是一個 從課前的教訓。
I'm saying, hey, computer show me a float with percent f.
我說，哎，電腦展 我百分之F A浮動。
But I'm giving it 2 ints.
但我給它2個整數。
So it turns out, I can fix this in a couple of ways.
所以，事實證明，我可以修復 這幾種方式。
>> I could just turn one into 1.0, and 10 into 10.0, which would, indeed,
>> 我只是把一成1.0，和 10到10.0，這，的確，
have the effect of converting them into floats-- still hopefully
有轉換的效果 他們進入floats--仍有望
the same number.
相同的號碼。
Or it turns out there's something we'll see again before long.
或者，它原來有什麼東西 我們不久再見到。
You could cast the numbers.
你可以投中的數字。
>> You can, using this parenthetical expression, you can say,
>> 您可以使用此括號 表達式，你可以說，
hey, computer, take this 10, which I know is an int.
哎，電腦，藉此 10，我知道是一個int。
But treat it, please, as though it's a float.
但是對待它，請 就好像它是一個浮動。
But this feels unnecessarily complex.
但這種感覺過於複雜。
>> For our purposes today, let's just literally
>> 對於我們今天的目的， 我們只是從字面上
make them floating point values with a decimal point, like this.
讓他們浮點值 帶小數點，就像這樣。
Let me go ahead and rerun, make imprecision, good, dot slash
讓我繼續前進並重新運行，使 不精確，好，點斜線
imprecision, enter.
不精確，進入。
OK, we're looking good.
OK，我們正在尋找好的。
>> 1 divided by 10, according to my Mac here, is, indeed, 0.100000.
>> 1除以10，按照我的 蘋果在這裡，的確是0.100000。
Now, I was taught in grade school there should be an infinite number of 0's.
現在，我學會了上小學的時候有 應該是0的無限數量。
So let's at least try to see some of those.
因此，讓我們至少嘗試 看到其中的一些。
It turns out that printf is a little fancier still than we've been using.
事實證明，printf的是一個小 票友仍然比我們一直在使用。
It turns out you don't have to specify just percent f, or just percent i.
原來你沒有指定 剛剛％的F或只是我百分比。
You can actually specify some control options here.
實際上，你可以指定 這裡的一些控制選項。
>> Specifically, I'm going to say, hey, printf,
>> 具體來說，我要去 就是說，哎，printf的，
actually show me 10 decimal points.
居然告訴我10小數點。
So it looks a little weird.
所以它看起來有點怪異。
But you say percent, dot, how many numbers
但是你說個百分點， 點，多少號
you want to see after the decimal point, and then f
你想以後看到 小數點，以及則f
for flat, just because that's what the documentation says.
平，只是因為這是 文件說什麼。
Let me go ahead and save that.
讓我繼續前進並保存。
>> And notice too, I'm getting tired of retyping things.
>> 並注意過，我越來越 厭倦了重複輸入的事情。
So I'm just setting the up and down arrow on my keys here.
所以我只是設置和 在這裡我的鑰匙向下箭頭。
And if I keep hitting up, you can see all of the commands
如果我繼續打了，你 可以看到所有的命令
that I made, or incorrectly made.
我犯了，或不正確的。
>> And I'm going to go ahead now and not actually use that, apparently.
>> 而我現在要繼續前進， 沒有實際使用，顯然。
Make imprecision, dot slash imprecision-- so
讓不精確，點 斜線imprecision--所以
what I was taught in grade school checks out.
我所教 小學檢查出來。
Even if I print it to 10 decimal places it, indeed, is 0.10000.
即使我把它打印到10進制 地方，它確實是0.10000。
But you know what?
但是，你知道嗎？
>> Let's get a little greedy.
>> 讓我們有點貪心。
Let's say, like, show me 55 points after the decimal.
比方說，比如，告訴我55 小數點後點。
Let's really take this program out for a spin.
讓我們真的採取這種 劃出來兜風。
Let me remake it with make imprecision, dot slash, imprecision.
讓我用make改造它 不精確，點斜線，不精確。
>> And here we go.
>> 現在我們開始。
Your childhood was a lie.
你的童年是一個謊言。
Apparently, 1 divided by 10 is indeed 0.100000000000000005551115123--
很顯然，1除以10的確 0.100000000000000005551115123--
>> What is going on?
>> 到底是怎麼回事？
Well, it turns out, if you kind of look far enough out in the underlying
那麼，事實證明，如果你種 看遠遠不夠出在底層
representation of this number, it actually
這表示 數目，它實際上
is not exactly 1/10, or 0.1 and an infinite number of zeros.
是不完全的1/10，或0.1和 無限數量的零。
Now, why is that?
現在，這是為什麼？
>> Well, even though this is a simple number to us humans, 1 divided by 10,
>> 那麼，即使這是一個簡單的 我們人類數，1除以10，
it's still one of infinitely many numbers that we could think up.
它仍然是無限多的一個 數字，我們能想到的。
But a computer can only represent finitely many so numbers.
但是，一台電腦只能代表 有限多個這樣的數字。
And so, effectively, what the computer is showing us is its closest
所以，有效的，是什麼 電腦正顯示出我們的是其最接近
approximation to the number we want to believe is 1/10,
近似​​與數 我們願意相信是1/10，
or really 0.10000 ad infinitum.
還是真的0.10000循環往復。
>> Rather, though, this is as close as it can get.
>> 而，雖然，這是 盡可能接近，因為它可以得到的。
And, indeed, if you look underneath the hood,
而且，事實上，如果你看看 引擎蓋下，
as we are here by looking 55 digits after the decimal,
因為我們在這裡通過看 小數點後55位，
we actually see that reality.
實際上我們看到的現實。
Now as an aside, if you've ever seen the movie--
現在，順便說一句，如果你 見過movie--
most of you probably haven't-- but Superman 3 some years ago,
大多數人可能haven't-- 但超人3若干年前，
Richard Pryor essentially leveraged this reality in his company to steal a lot
理查德·普賴爾基本上是利用這 現實中，他的公司竊取了很多
of fractions and fractions of pennies, because the company-- as I recall,
便士的分數和分數的， 因為我記得在company--，
it's been a while-- was essentially throwing away anything that didn't fit
它是一個while--基本上是 扔掉任何東西，不適合
into the notion of cents.
進入仙的概念。
>> But if you add up all these tiny, tiny, tiny numbers again,
>> 但是，如果你把所有這些 很小，很小，很小的數字再次，
and again, and again, you can, as in his case, make a good amount of money.
又一次，又一次，你可以象在 他的情況下，賺錢的一個良好的數額。
>> That same idea was ripped off by a more recent, but still now older
>> 那同樣的想法被扯掉 更近，但還是現在年紀大了
movie, called Office Space, where the guys in that movie,
電影，叫辦公空間， 凡在那部電影的傢伙，
did the same thing, screwed it up completely, ended up with way too much
做同樣的事情，搞砸了 徹底，結束了太多
money in their bank account.
錢在自己的銀行賬戶。
It was all very suspicious.
這一切都是很可疑。
But at the end of the day, imprecision is all around us.
但在一天結束時， 不精確就在我們身邊。
>> And that, too, can be frighteningly the case.
>> 並且，也可以是 令人震驚的情況。
It turns out that Superman 3 and Office Space aside, there
原來，3超人 和辦公空間之外，還有
can be some very real world ramifications
可能有一些非常現實的 世界後果
of the realities of imprecise representation of data
不精確的現實 數據的表示
that even we humans to this day don't necessarily
即使我們人類 這一天不一定
understand as well as we should, or remember as often as we should.
理解，以及我們應該， 或記住盡可能多我們應該。
And, indeed, the following clip is from a look at some very real world
而且，事實上，以下剪輯是 從看一些很真實的世界
ramifications of what happens if you don't appreciate the imprecision that
如果你會發生什麼後果 不欣賞的不精確性
can happen in numbers representation.
在數字代表出現。
>> [VIDEO PLAYBACK]
>> [視頻回放]
>> -Computers, we've all come to accept the often frustrating problems that
>> -Computers，我們都逐漸接受 經常令人沮喪的問題，
go with them-- bugs, viruses, and software glitches,
去them--錯誤，病毒， 和軟件故障，
for small prices to pay for the convenience.
對於小的價格支付 為方便。
But in high tech and high speed military and space program applications,
但是，在高科技和高速度 軍事和航天計劃的應用，
the smallest problem can be magnified into disaster.
最小的問題即可 被放大成災難。
>> On June 4th, 1996, scientists prepared to launch an unmanned Ariane 5 rocket.
>> 在1996年6月4日，科學家們準備 發射無人阿麗亞娜5型火箭。
It was carrying scientific satellites designed
它攜帶的科學 衛星設計
to establish precisely how the earth's magnetic field interacts
建立精確如何 地球的磁場相互作用
with solar winds.
與太陽風。
The rocket was built for the European Space Agency,
火箭是專為 歐洲航天局，
and lifted off from its facility on the coast of French Guiana.
並從其設施升空 在法屬圭亞那的海岸。
>> -At about 37 seconds into the flight, they first
>> -At約37秒進 飛行中，他們首先
noticed something was going wrong.
注意到某些事正在錯誤的。
The nozzles were swiveling in a way they really shouldn't.
噴嘴在被旋轉 某種意義上說，他們實在不應該。
Around 40 seconds into the flight, clearly, the vehicle was in trouble.
大約40秒後進入飛行， 顯然，車輛遇到了麻煩。
>> And that's when they made a decision to destroy it.
>> 那就是當他們做了 決定摧毀它。
The range safety officer, with tremendous guts, pressed the button,
該範圍內的安全官員，與 巨大的膽量，按下按鈕，
blew up the rocket, before it could become a hazard to the public safety.
炸毀了火箭，它可能前 成為對公眾安全造成危害。
>> -This was the maiden voyage of the Ariane 5.
>>  - 這是處女 阿麗亞娜5的航程。
And its destruction took place because of a flaw
而其毀滅了 地方，因為一個缺陷
embedded in the rocket's software.
嵌入火箭的軟件。
-The problem on the Ariane was that there was a number that
在阿麗亞娜-The問題是 認為有許多
required 64 bits to express.
需要64位來表示。
And they wanted to convert it to a 16-bit number.
他們想轉換 它的16位數字。
They assumed that the number was never going
他們假定 數字是永遠不會
to be very big, that most of those digits in a 64-bit number were zeroes.
是非常大的，大多數的那些 在一個64位的號碼數字是零。
They were wrong.
但他們錯了。
>> -The inability of one software program to accept
>> -The無力之一 軟件程序接受
the kind of number generated by another was at the root of the failure.
所產生的那種數 另一種是在失敗的根源。
Software development had become a very costly part of new technology.
軟件開發已經成為一個 的新技術非常昂貴的部分。
The Ariane rocket have been very successful, so much of the software
該阿麗亞娜火箭已經很 成功，那麼多的軟件
created for it was also used in the Ariane 5.
創造了它也是 在阿麗亞娜5中。
>> -The basic problem was that the Ariane 5 was faster, accelerated faster.
>> -The根本的問題是，阿麗亞娜 5增快，加速快。
And the software hadn't accounted for that.
而且軟件早已不是 佔了點。
>> -The destruction of the rocket was a huge financial disaster,
>> 火箭-The破壞 是一個巨大的金融災難，
all due to a minute software error.
一切緣於一分鐘，軟件錯誤。
But this wasn't the first time data conversion problems
但是，這不是第一次 實時數據轉換問題
had plagued modern rocket technology.
一直困擾現代火箭技術。
>> -In 1991, with the start of the first Gulf War,
>> -in 1991年，開始時 第一次海灣戰爭中，
the Patriot Missile experienced a similar kind
愛國者導彈 經歷了類似的一種
of number conversion problem.
數轉換的問題。
And as a result, 28 people, 28 American soldiers,
而作為一個結果，28人， 28名美國士兵，
were killed, and about 100 others wounded,
被打死，約 100人受傷，
when the Patriot, which was supposed to protect against incoming scuds,
當愛國者，這本來是 防止傳入的飛毛腿導彈，
failed to fire a missile.
沒有發射導彈。
>> -When Iraq invaded Kuwait, and America launched Desert Storm in early 1991,
>>  - 當伊拉克入侵科威特和美國 在1991年年初推出沙漠風暴
Patriot Missile batteries were deployed to protect Saudi Arabia and Israel
愛國者導彈部署 保護沙特阿拉伯和以色列
from Iraqi Scud missile attacks.
伊拉克飛毛腿導彈襲擊。
The Patriot is a US medium-range surface to air system, manufactured
愛國者是美國中程 表面空氣系統，製造
by the Raytheon company.
由雷神公司。
>> -The size of the Patriot interceptor itself is about roughly 20 feet long.
>> 愛國者攔截-The大小 本身是關於約20英尺長。
And it weighs about 2,000 pounds.
它重約2000磅。
And it carries a warhead of about, I think it's roughly 150 pounds.
同時還可以進行約一個彈頭， 我認為這是大約150磅。
And the warhead itself is a high explosive, which
和彈頭本身 高爆發力，這
has fragments around it.
周圍有碎片。
The casing of the warhead is designed to act like buckshot.
彈頭的外殼是 旨在像大號鉛彈。
>> -The missiles are carried four per container,
>> -The導彈進行 百分之四的容器中，
and are transported by a semi trailer.
和由半拖車運輸。
>> -The Patriot anti-missile system goes back at least 20 years now.
>> -The愛國者反導彈系統 追溯到現在至少有20年。
It was originally designed as an air defense missile
它最初的設計 作為防空導彈
to shoot down enemy airplanes.
擊落敵人的飛機。
In the first Gulf War, when that war came along,
在第一次海灣戰爭， 當戰爭來了，
the Army wanted to use it to shoot down scuds, not airplanes.
陸軍想用它來 擊落飛毛腿導彈，而不是飛機。
>> The Iraqi Air Force was not so much of a problem.
>> 伊拉克空軍 沒有那麼多的問題。
But the Army was worried about scuds.
但軍隊是擔心飛毛腿導彈。
And so they tried to upgrade the Patriot.
所以他們試圖 升級愛國者。
>> -Intercepting an enemy missile traveling at mach 5
>> -Intercepting敵人 在導彈5馬赫旅行
was going to be challenging enough.
將要被足夠的挑戰性。
But when the Patriot was rushed into service,
但是，當愛國者 被送往投入服務，
the Army was not aware of an Iraqi modification that made
陸軍不知道的 伊拉克的修改，使得
their scuds nearly impossible to hit.
他們的飛毛腿導彈幾乎是不可能的打擊。
>> -What happened is the scuds that were coming in were unstable.
>>  - 什麼事是飛毛腿導彈的 要來的是不穩定的。
They were wobbling.
他們在晃動。
The reason for this was the Iraqis, in order
這樣做的原因是 伊拉克人，為了
to get 600 kilometers out of a 300 kilometer
獲得600公里 出300公里
range missile, took weight out of the front warhead.
中程導彈，重了 從前面彈頭。
They made the warhead lighter.
他們提出的彈頭更輕。
>> So now the Patriot is trying to come at the Scud.
>> 所以，現在的愛國者 苦思的飛毛腿。
And most of the time, the overwhelming majority of the time,
和大部分的時間，該 絕大多數的時間，
it would just fly by the Scud.
它只是由飛毛腿飛。
Once the Patriot system operators realized the Patriot missed its target,
一旦愛國者系統運營商 實現了愛國者錯過了目標，
they detonated the Patriot's warhead to avoid possible casualties if it
他們引爆愛國者的彈頭 以避免如果可能的人員傷亡
was allowed to fall to the ground.
被允許倒在地上。
>> -That was what most people saw, those big fireballs in the sky,
>>  - 那是大多數人所看到的， 在天空中那些大火球，
and misunderstood as intercepts of Scud warheads.
和誤解成 飛毛腿彈頭的攔截。
>> -Although in the night skies, Patriots appeared
>>  - 雖然在夜間 天空，出現了愛國者
to be successfully destroying Scuds, at Dhahran,
要成功地 摧毀飛毛腿導彈，在宰赫蘭
there could be no mistake about its performance.
有可能是沒有錯 關於它的性能。
There, the Patriot's radar system lost track of an incoming Scud,
目前，愛國者的雷達系統 失去了進入的飛毛腿的軌道，
and never launched due to a software flaw.
從不因推出 到一個軟件缺陷。
It was the Israelis who first discovered that the longer the system was on,
這是誰首先發現了以色列人 的時間越長該系統上，
the greater the time discrepancy became, due to a clock embedded
越大時間差異 成為，由於嵌入的時鐘
in the system's computer.
在系統的計算機。
>> -About two weeks before the tragedy in Dhahran,
>>  - 關於前兩週 悲劇發生在宰赫蘭
the Israelis reported to the Defense Department
以色列人報 國防部
that the system was losing time.
該系統正在失去的時間。
After about eight hours or running, they noticed that the system
約8小時運行之後， 他們注意到，該系統
was becoming noticeably less accurate.
變得明顯不準確。
The Defense Department responded by telling all of the Patriot batteries
國防部回應 告訴所有的愛國者電池
to not leave the systems on for a long time.
不離開系統 上很長一段時間。
They never said what a long time was-- eight hours, 10 hours, 1,000 hours.
他們從來不說什麼了很久was-- 八小時，10小時，千小時。
Nobody knew.
沒有人知道。
>> -The Patriot battery stationed at the barracks
>> -The愛國者電池 駐紮在軍營
at Dhahran and its flawed internal clock had been on over 100 hours
在宰赫蘭和內部缺陷 時鐘已經超過100小時一直在
on the night of February 25th.
2月25日的夜晚。
>> -It tracked time to an accuracy of about a tenth of a second.
>>  - 它跟踪的時間精度 約一秒鐘的十分之一。
Now, a tenth of a second is an interesting number,
現在，第二的第十 是一個有趣的數字，
because it can't be expressed in binary exactly, which
因為它不能表示 二進制準確地說，這
means it can't be expressed exactly in any modern digital computer.
意味著它不能精確地表達 在任何現代數字計算機。
It's hard to believe.
很難相信。
>> But use this as an example.
>> 但是使用此作為一個例子。
Let's take the number one third.
讓我們來數三分之一。
One third cannot be expressed in decimal exactly.
三分之一不能 十進制明確地表達。
One third is 0.333 going on for infinity.
三分之一是0.333 持續了無窮大。
>> There is no way to do that with absolute accuracy in decimal.
>> 有沒有辦法做到這一點與 絕對精度十進制。
That's exactly the kind of problem that happened in the Patriot.
這正是那種問題 這發生在愛國者。
The longer the system ran, the worse the time error became.
時間越長，系統運行時， 更糟糕的時間誤差成了。
>> -After 100 hours of operation, the error in time was only about one third
>>  - 後運行100小時後， 在時間誤差僅為約三分之一
of a second.
的第二。
But in terms of targeting a missile traveling at mach 5,
但是，在一個目標的角度 導彈在5馬赫旅行，
it resulted in a tracking error of over 600 meters.
它導致了跟踪 超過600米錯誤。
It would be a fatal error for the soldiers on what
這將是一個致命的錯誤 對於什麼戰士
happened is a Scud launch was detected by early Warning satellites
碰巧是飛毛腿發射是 通過預警衛星檢測
and they knew that the Scud was coming in their general direction.
他們知道，是飛毛腿 未來在他們的大方向。
They didn't know where it was coming.
他們不知道有人來了。
>> -It was now up to the radar component of the Patriot system
>>  - 它現在要由雷達 愛國者系統的組成部分
defending Dhahran to locate and keep track of the incoming enemy missile.
衛冕達蘭定位和保持 跟踪來襲的敵方導彈。
>> -The radar was very smart.
>> -The雷達是非常聰明的。
It would actually track the position of the Scud,
它實際上是將跟踪 飛毛腿的位置，
and then predict where it probably would be the next time the radar sent
然後預測出可能 將是下一個時間的雷達發送
a pulse out.
脈衝出來。
That was called a range gate.
這是所謂的範圍內門。
>> -Then, once the Patriot decides enough time has
>>  - 然後，一旦愛國者 決定時間已夠
passed to go back and check the next location for this detected object,
傳遞回去檢查下 此檢測物體的位置，
it goes back.
它可以追溯到。
So when it went back to the wrong place, it then sees no object.
因此，當它回到了錯 地方，然後看見沒有對象。
And it decides that there was no object, it was a false detection,
和它決定，沒有 對象，這是一個錯誤的檢測，
and drops the track.
和下降的軌道。
>> -The incoming Scud disappeared from the radar screen.
>> -The傳入飛毛腿消失 從雷達屏幕上。
And seconds later, it slammed into the barracks.
幾秒鐘後，它 撞上軍營。
The Scud killed 28, and was the last one fired during the first Gulf War.
飛毛腿打死28，並且是最後一個 在第一次海灣戰爭中開火。
>> Tragically, the updated software arrived at Dhahran the following day.
>> 可悲的是，更新的軟件 抵達宰赫蘭的第二天。
The software flaw had been fixed, closing
該軟件有缺陷 得到修復，閉合
one chapter in the troubled history of the Patriot missile.
在陷入困境的一章 愛國者導彈的歷史。
>> [VIDEO PLAYBACK]
>> [視頻回放]
DAVID J. MALAN: So this is all to say that these issues of overflow
DAVID J. MALAN：所以這是所有 說，溢出的這些問題
and imprecision are all too real.
和不精確都太真實了。
So how did we get here?
那麼我們是如何來到這裡的？
We began with just talking about printf.
我們開始只是談論的printf。
Again, this function that prints something to the screen,
再次，此函數 打印一些東西到屏幕上，
and we introduced thereafter a few other functions
我們隨後推出 幾個其他功能
from the so-called CS50's library.
從所謂CS50的庫。
And we'll continue to see these in due time.
我們將繼續 看到這些在適當的時候。
And we, particularly, used get string, and get int, and now also get float,
而我們，尤其是使用的GET字符串， 並獲得INT，現在還可以獲得浮動，
and yet others still will we encounter and use ourselves before long.
還有一些仍然會遇到我們 不久使用自己。
>> But on occasion, have we already seen a need
>> 但有時，有 我們已經看到有必要
to store what those functions hand back?
存儲什麼這些功能的手背？
They hand us back a string, or an int, or a float.
他們一方面我們回到一個字符串， 或int或浮動。
And sometimes we need to put that string, or int, or float, somewhere.
有時，我們需要把該 字符串或int，或float地方。
>> And to store those things, recall just like in Scratch, we have variables.
>> 並存儲那些東西，只是召回 就像在刮，我們有變數。
But unlike in Scratch, in C we have actual types
但與划痕， 在C中有實際的類型
of variables-- data types, more generally--
variables--數據 類型，更generally--
among them, a string, an int, a float, and these others still.
其中，一個字符串，一個int，一個 浮動，而這些人依然。
>> And so when we declare variables in C, we'll have to declare our data types.
>> 所以，當我們用C聲明變量， 我們必須聲明的數據類型。
This is not something we'll have to do later in the semester
這不是我們 必須在學期過去了做
as we transition to other languages.
因為我們過渡到其他語言。
But for now, we do need to a priori in advance,
但現在，我們確實需要 到預先先驗，
explain to the computer what type of variable we want it to give us.
解釋計算機是什麼類型 可變的，我們希望它給我們。
>> Now, meanwhile, to print those kinds of data types,
>> 現在，同時，進行打印 這些類型的數據類型，
we have to tell printf what to expect.
我們要告訴printf的什麼期望。
And we saw percent s for strings, and percent i for integers,
我們看到字符串％的S， 和我百分之整數，
and a few others already.
和其他幾個人了。
And those are simply requirements for the visual presentation
而這些僅僅是要求 對於視覺呈現
of that information.
這些信息。
>> And each of these can actually be parametrized or tweaked in some way,
>> 而且每個這些其實是可以 參數化或以某種方式調整，
if you want to further control the type of output that you get.
如果你想進一步控制 你得到的輸出類型。
And, in fact, it turns out that not only is there backslash n for a new line.
而且，事實上，它不僅證明 有反斜杠n，則新行。
There's something else called backslash r for a carriage return, which
還有別的東西叫反斜線 r代表回車，這
is more akin to an old school typewriter,
更類似於一個 老同學打字機，
and also Windows used for many years.
並且還視窗使用多年。
>> There's backslash t for tabs.
>> 有製表符反斜杠噸。
Turns out, that if you want to double quote inside of a string,
事實證明，如果你想 字符串裡面的雙引號，
recall that we've used double quote double
我們已經使用召回 雙引號雙
quote on the left and the right ends of our strings thus far.
引用在左側和右 迄今為止，我們的字符串結束。
That would seem to confuse things.
這似乎混淆的東西。
>> If you want to put a double quote in the middle of a string-- and, indeed,
>> 如果你想要把雙引號中 一個string--，實際上中間，
it is confusing to see.
它是混亂看到的。
And so you have to escape, so to speak, a double quote with something
所以你要逃跑，所以 說話，用的東西一個雙引號
like, literally, backslash double quote.
像，從字面上看，反斜杠雙引號。
And there's a few other still.
而且還有一些其他的還在。
And we'll see more of those in actual use before long.
我們將看到更多的這些 在不久的實際使用。
>> So let's now transition from data, and representation,
>> 現在讓我們從過渡 數據和代表性，
and arithmetic operators, all of which gave us some building
和算術運算符，所有 這給了我們一些建築
blocks with which to play.
與玩積木。
But now let's actually give us the rest of the vocabulary
但現在，讓我們實際上給 我們的詞彙的其餘部分
that we already had last week with Scratch
我們已經完成了 上週與划痕
by taking a look at some other constructs in C-- not all of them.
通過一些其他的考慮看看 在C--結構不是所有的人。
But the ideas we're about to see really just
但是我們的想法 就要看真的只是
to emphasize the translation from one language, Scratch, to another, C.
要強調從翻譯 一種語言，從無到有，到另一個，C.
>> And over time, we'll pick up more tools for our toolkit,
>> 隨著時間的推移，我們會拿起 更多的工具，我們的工具包，
so to speak, syntactically.
可以這麼說，語​​法上。
And, indeed, you'll see that the ideas are now rather familiar from last week.
而且，事實上，你會看到的想法 現在從上週相當熟悉。
So let's do this.
因此，讓我們做到這一點。
>> Let's go ahead and whip up a program that actually uses some expressions,
>> 讓我們繼續前進，並掀起程序 實際使用一些表情，
a Boolean expression.
布爾表達式。
Let me go ahead here and create a new file.
讓我繼續在這裡 並創建一個新的文件。
I'll call this condition.c.
我會打電話給這個condition.c。
>> Let me go ahead and include the CS50 library.
>> 讓我繼續前進， 包括CS50庫。
And let me go ahead and include standard IO.h for our functions,
讓我繼續前進，包括 標準IO.h我們的功能，
and printf, and more respectively.
和printf，更分別。
Let me give myself that boilerplate of int main void, whose explanation we'll
讓我給自己的樣板 INT主要無效，其解釋我們
come back to in the future.
回來的未來。
>> Now let me go ahead and give myself an int via get int.
>> 現在讓我先走，並把 我通過get INT一個int。
Then let me go ahead and do this.
然後讓我繼續前進，做到這一點。
I want to say if i is less-- let's distinguish between positive, negative,
我想說，如果我是less--讓我們 正，負區分
or zero values.
或零值。
>> So if i is less than zero, let me just have this program simply say,
>> 所以，如果我是小於零，讓我 只是有這個計劃簡單地說，
negative, backslash n, else if i is greater than zero.
負，反斜線N，否則 如果i大於零。
Now I'm, of course, going to say printf positive, backslash n.
現在，我當然會說 printf的正面，反斜線ñ。
And then else if-- I could do this.
然後，其他if--我能做到這一點。
>> I could do if i equals 0.
>> 如果我等於0，我可以做的。
But I'd be making at least one mistake already.
但我在做被 至少一個錯誤了。
Recall that the equal sign is not equal, as we humans know it.
回想一下，等號 不相等的，因為我們人類知道這一點。
>> But it's the assignment operator.
>> 但它的賦值操作符。
And we don't want to take 0 on the right and put it in i on the left.
而我們不希望在採取0 權利，把它放在我的左邊。
So to avoid this confusion, or perhaps misuse of the equals sign,
因此，為了避免這種混亂，或 也許是平等的濫用簽收，
humans decided some years ago that in many programming languages
人類決定幾年前 在許多編程語言
when you want to check for equality between the left and the right,
當您要檢查等式 左和右之間，
you actually use equals equals.
你實際使用等於等號。
So you hit the equals sign twice.
所以，你打等號的兩倍。
When you want to assign from right to left, you use a single equal sign.
當你想從分配權 到左，你用一個等號。
So we could do this-- else if i equals equals zero.
因此，我們可以做別的this-- 如果我等於為零。
>> I could then go and open my curly braces,
>> 然後，我可以去 打開我的大括號，
and say, printf 0, backslash n, done.
並說，printf的0，反斜線N，完成。
But remember how these forks in the road can work.
但要記住，這些是如何 在岔路口能正常工作。
And, really, just think about the logic.
而且，真的，只是想想邏輯。
i is a number.
i是一個數字。
It's an integer, specifically.
這是一個整數，具體。
And that means it's going to be less than 0, or greater than 0, or 0.
這意味著它將會是少 大於0，或者大於0，或者0大。
So there is kind of this implied default case.
因此，有一種這樣 隱含的默認情況。
>> And so we could, just like Scratch, dispense with the else if,
>> 因此，我們可以，就像 劃傷，免除了其他如，
and just say else.
而只是說別的。
Logically, if you the programmer know there's only
從邏輯上講，如果您在 程序員知道，只有
three buckets into which a scenario can fall-- the first,
三個存儲成一個 情況可能fall--第一，
the second, or the third in this case-- don't
第二，或第三 在這個case--不
bother adding the additional precision and the additional logic there.
懶得添加額外的精度 和附加​​邏輯那裡。
Just go ahead with the default case here of else.
只是繼續用 默認情況下，這裡的人。
>> Now, let's go ahead after saving this, make
>> 現在，讓我們繼續 保存此之後，使
conditions dot slash conditions-- not a great user interface,
條件斜線點條件 - 不是一個偉大的用戶界面，
because I'm not prompting the user, as I mentioned earlier.
因為我不惹得 用戶，正如我前面提到的。
But that's fine.
但是，這很好。
We'll keep it simple.
我們將保持簡單。
Let's try the number 42.
讓我們嘗試數字42。
And that's positive.
這就是積極的。
Let's try the number negative 42, negative.
讓我們嘗試次數 負42負。
>> Let's try the value 0.
>> 讓我們嘗試值0。
And, indeed, it works.
而且，事實上，它的工作原理。
Now, you'll see with problems before long, testing things three times,
現在，你將與之前看到的問題 長，檢測的事三次，
probably not sufficient.
可能不充分。
You probably want to test some bigger numbers, some smaller
你可能想測試一些 更大的數字，一些規模較小的
numbers, some corner cases, as we'll come to describe them.
數字，一些角落情況下，如 我們會來描述它們。
>> But for now, this is a pretty simple program.
>> 但現在，這是一個 很簡單的程序。
And I'm pretty sure, logically, that it falls into three cases.
而且我敢肯定，在邏輯上， 它分為三種情況。
And, indeed, even though we just focused on the potential downsides
而且，事實上，即使我們只是 集中在潛在的缺點
of imprecision and overflow, in reality where many of CS50's problems,
不精確和溢出，在 現實中，許多的CS50的問題，
we are not going to worry about, all the time,
我們不會擔心 一下，所有的時間，
those issues of overflow and imprecision, because, in fact, in C,
溢出的這些問題， 不精確的，因為，事實上，在C，
it's actually not all that easy to avoid those things.
它實際上不是所有的 容易避免這些東西。
If you want to count up bigger, and bigger, and bigger,
如果你想計數 大，大，大，
it turns out there are techniques you can use, often involving things called
事實證明，有技術，您 可以使用，常累及東西叫做
libraries, collections of code, that other people wrote that you can use,
圖書館的館藏代碼，即 其他人寫的，你可以使用，
and other languages like Java and others, actually
和其他語言如 Java和其他人，其實
make it a lot easier to count even higher.
讓人們更方便 數甚至更高。
So it really is some of these dangers a function of the language you use.
因此，它確實是有些危險 您使用的語言的函數。
And in the coming weeks, we'll see how dangerous C really
並在未來幾週內，我們將 看有多危險真的Ç
can be if you don't use it properly.
可如果不正確地使用它。
But from there, and with Python, and JavaScript, will
但是從那裡，並與 蟒蛇，和JavaScript，將
we layer on some additional protections, and run fewer of those risks.
我們圖層上的某些額外的保護， 並運行這些風險較少。
>> So let's make a little more interesting logic in our program.
>> 因此，讓多一點 有趣的邏輯在我們的節目。
So let me go ahead and create a program called Logical
因此，讓我繼續創建 一個叫做邏輯程序
just so I can play with some actual logic, logical.c.
只是這樣我就可以玩一些 實際的邏輯，logical.c。
I'll just copy and paste some code from earlier so I get back
我只是複製和粘貼一些 從早期的代碼，所以我回來
to this nice starting point.
這個漂亮的出發點。
>> Let me this time do char C. I'm going to give it a name of C
>> 讓我這個時候做字符C.我 打算給它的C名稱
just because it's conventional, get a character from the user.
只是因為它的傳統， 獲取來自用戶的字符。
And let's pretend like I'm implementing part
讓我們假裝 我實施的一部分
of that Rm program, the remove program before that prompted the user
該室的方案，刪除 在此之前，程序提示用戶
to remove a file.
刪除文件。
How could we do this?
我們怎麼能做到這一點？
>> I want to say, if C equals equals, quote unquote,
>> 我想說的是，如果C等於 等於，報價引文結束，
y, then I'm going to assume that the user has chosen yes.
Y，然後我要去承擔 該用戶已經是選擇。
I'm just going to print yes.
我只是要打印的是。
If it were actually writing the removal program,
如果它被實際編寫 拆除程序，
we could remove the file with more lines of code.
我們可以刪除文件 有更多行的代碼。
But we'll keep it simple.
但我們會保持它的簡單。
>> Else if c equals equals n-- and now here, I'm going to say,
>> 如果C等於等於N-- 現在這裡，我會說，
the user must have meant no.
用戶必須意味著沒有。
And then else, you know what?
然後別的，你知道嗎？
I don't know what else the user is going to type.
我不知道還有什麼 用戶將要輸入。
So I'm just going to say that that is an error, whatever
所以，我只是說， 這是一個錯誤，無論
he or she actually typed.
他或她實際鍵入。
>> So what's going on here?
>> 那麼是什麼回事？
There is a fundamental difference versus what I've done in the past.
有一個根本的區別 與我在過去所做的那樣。
Double quotes, double quotes, double quotes, and, yet, single quotes,
雙引號，雙引號，雙 報價和，但是，單引號
single quotes.
單引號。
It turns out in C, that when you want to write a string,
原來，在C，當 你想要寫一個字符串，
you do use double quotes, just as we've been using all this time with printf.
你使用雙引號，就像我們已經 使用所有這一次的printf了。
>> But if you want to deal with just a single character, a so-called char,
>> 但是，如果你要處理的只是一個 單個字符，所謂字符，
then you actually use single quotes.
那麼你實際使用單引號。
Those of you who've programmed before, you might not have
你們當中誰已設定 之前，你可能沒有
had to worry about this distinction in certain languages.
不用擔心這個 區別在某些語言。
In C, it does matter.
在C中，這非常重要。
And so when I get a char and I want to compare that char using equals
所以，當我得到一個char，我想 使用equals來比較字符
equals to some letter like y or n, I do, indeed, need to have the single quotes.
等於像y或n一些信，我做的， 的確，需要有單引號。
>> Now, let's go ahead and do this.
>> 現在，讓我們繼續前進，做到這一點。
Let's go ahead and do make logical dot slash logical.
讓我們繼續前進，不要做 邏輯點斜線邏輯。
And now I'm being prompted.
而現在我被提示。
So, presumably, a better user experience would actually tell me what to do here.
因此，據推測，更好的用戶體驗 實際上告訴我在這裡做什麼。
But I'm going to just blindly say y for yes, OK, nice.
但我要去只是盲目 說Y（是），不錯，真不錯。
>> Let's run it again, n for no, nice.
>> 讓我們再次運行它，正因為沒有，美觀大方。
Suppose like certain people I know, my caps lock key is on all too often.
假設像某些人我知道， 我的大寫鎖定鍵是所有過於頻繁。
So I do capital Y, enter, error.
所以我做資本Y，回車，錯誤。
OK, it's not exactly what I'm expecting.
OK，這不是正是我期待的。
Indeed, the computer is doing literally what
的確，計算機 簡直是在做什麼
I told it to do-- check for lowercase y and lowercase n.
我告訴它do--檢查 小寫字母y和小寫的n。
This doesn't feel like good user experience, though.
這並不覺得自己是最好 用戶體驗，雖然。
Let me ask for and accept either lower case or upper case.
讓我索取，接受採訪 無論是小寫或大寫。
So it turns out, you might want to say something like in Scratch,
因此，原來，你可能想 說類似的划痕，
like literally or C equals equals capital single quoted y.
像字面上或C等於 等於資本單引號年。
Turns out, C does not have this literal keyword or.
事實證明，C沒有 這個文字關鍵字或。
>> But it does have two vertical bars.
>> 但它確實有兩個豎條。
You have to hold Shift usually, if you're using a US keyboard,
你要平時按住Shift， 如果您使用的是美式鍵盤，
and hit the vertical bar key above your return key.
並擊中豎線 按鍵上的回車鍵。
But this vertical bar vertical bar means or.
但是，這豎線 豎線表示或。
>> If, by contrast, we wanted to say and, like in Scratch,
>> 如果，相反，我們希望 說，就像在刮，
we could do ampersand ampersand.
我們可以做的符號與符號。
That makes no logical sense here, because a human could not possibly
這使得沒有任何邏輯意義在這裡， 因為人不可能
have typed both y and lowercase y and capital Y as the same character.
鍵入y和小寫ÿ 和資本y為相同的字符。
So or is what we intend here.
所以，還是就是我們打算在這裡。
>> So if I do this in both places, or c equals equals capital N, now rerun,
>> 所以，如果我這樣做，在這兩個地方，或c 等於等於資本N，現在重新運行，
make logical, rerun logical.
使邏輯，重新運行邏輯。
Now, I can type y.
現在，我可以鍵入y。
And I can do it again with capital Y, or capital N.
而且我可以再做一次 資本Y，或資本N.
And I could add in additional combinations still.
而且我可以添加額外的 組合依然。
>> So this is a logical program insofar as now
>> 因此，這是一個邏輯 程序只要現在
I'm checking logically for this value or this value.
我檢查的邏輯 這個值或該值。
And I don't have to, necessarily, come up with two more ifs or else ifs.
我不就得了，必然， 拿出兩個IFS否則IFS。
I can actually combine some of the related logic together in this way.
其實我可以結合一些 以這種方式將相關邏輯。
So this would be better designed than simply
因此，這將是更好 設計不是簡單的
saying, if C equals lower case y, print yes, else if c equals capital Y,
他說，如果C等於較低的情況下，y， 打印是的，如果C等於資本Y，
print yes, else if c equals lower-- in other words,
打印是的，如果C等於 lower--換句話說，
you don't have to have more and more branches.
你不必有 越來越多的分支。
You can combine some of the equivalent branches logically, as in this way.
您可以結合一些等價的 分支邏輯，如在這種方式。
>> So let's take a look at just one final ingredient, one final construct,
>> 因此，讓我們來看看只有一個 最後一個要素，一是最終的構建，
that C allows.
這C允許。
And we'll come back in the future to others still.
我們會回來的 今後其他的還是。
And then we'll conclude by looking at not the correctness of code--
然後我們通過觀察得出結論： 在代碼 - 不正確性
getting code to work-- but the design of code, and plant those seeds early on.
讓代碼work--而設計 的代碼，建廠初期這些種子。
>> So let me go ahead and open up a new file here.
>> 因此，讓我繼續前進， 在這裡開闢一個新的文件。
You know what?
你知道嗎？
I'm going to re-implement that same program,
我要重新實現 同樣的程序，
but using a different construct.
但使用不同的構建體。
>> So let me quickly give myself access to include CS50.h
>> 因此，讓我趕緊給自己 獲得包括CS50.h
for the CS50 library, standard Io.h for printf.
為CS50庫， 標準Io.h像printf。
Give me my int main void.
給我INT主要無效。
And then over here, let me go ahead and do this.
然後在這裡，讓 我繼續前進，做到這一點。
>> Char c gets get char, just like before.
>> 煤焦Ç得到得到CHAR，就像以前一樣。
And I'm going to use a new construct now-- switch, on what character?
而且我將使用一個新的結構 now--切換，什麼角色？
So switch is kind of like switching a train tracks.
因此，開關是一種像 切換火車軌道。
Or, really, it is kind of an if else, if else if,
或者，真的，這是怎麼樣的 如果一個別人，如果別人如果
but written somewhat differently.
但寫的有些不同。
>> A switch looks like this.
>> 開關看起來是這樣的。
You have switch, and then what character or number you want to look at,
你有開關，然後什麼 字符或你想看看號碼，
then some curly braces like in Scratch, just say do this stuff.
然後一些大括號喜歡 划痕，只是說做這個東西。
And then you have different cases.
然後你有不同的情況。
>> You don't use if and else.
>> 你不if和else使用。
You literally use the word case.
你從字面上用字情況。
And you would say something like this.
你會說這樣的事情。
>> So in the case of a lowercase y, or in the case of a capital Y,
>> 因此，在一個小寫y的情況下， 或在資本Y的情況下，
go ahead and print out yes.
繼續前進並打印出肯定的。
And then break out of the switch.
然後打出來的開關。
That's it.
而已。
We're done.
我們就大功告成了。
>> Else if, so to speak, lower case n, or capital N,
>> 否則，如果，可以這麼說， 小寫n或大寫字母N，
then go ahead and print out no, and then break.
然後繼續和打印 出去不，再突破。
Else-- and this kind of is the default case indeed-- printf error--
Else--和這種是 默認情況下indeed--的printf error--
and just for good measure, though logically this break is not necessary
和公正的良好措施，但 這在邏輯上破則沒有必要
because we're at the end of the switch anyway,
因為我們是在最後 反正開關，
I'm now breaking out of the switch.
現在我打破了開關了。
So this looks a little different.
因此，這看起來有點不同。
>> But, logically, it's actually equivalent.
>> 但是，從邏輯上講，它是 實際上相當於。
And why would you use one over the other?
你為什麼要使用 一個比其他？
Sometimes, just personal preference, sometimes the aesthetics,
有時候，只是個人喜好， 有時美學，
if I glance at this now, there's something
如果我看了一眼這個 現在，有什麼東西
to be said for the readability of this code.
以說是為 這個代碼的可讀性。
I mean, never mind the fact that this code is new to many of us in the room.
我的意思是，心中永遠的事實，這 代碼是新的在房間裡我們許多人。
>> But it just kind of is pretty.
>> 但它只是一種很漂亮。
You see lowercase y, capital Y, lower case n, capital N default,
你看小寫字母Y，資本Y， 小寫N，大寫字母N默認情況下，
it just kind of jumps out at you in a way
它只是一種跳躍 出你的方式
that, arguably, maybe the previous example
如此，可以說，也許 在前面的例子
with the ifs, and the vertical bars, and the else ifs, might not have.
與如果，和垂直桿， 和其他IFS，可能沒有。
So this is really a matter of personal choice, really, or readability,
因此，這是真正的個人問題 選擇，真的，還是可讀性，
of the code.
的代碼。
>> But in terms of functionality, let me go ahead and make a switch, dot slash
>> 但在功能方面，讓我 繼續前進，使開關，點斜杠
switch, and now type in lowercase y, capital Y, lowercase n, capital N,
開關，現在鍵入小寫字母Y， 資本Y，小寫的n，資本N，
David, retry because that's not a single character.
大衛，重試，因為這是 不是單個字符。
Let's do x, error, as expected.
讓我們做X，錯誤，符合市場預期。
And, logically-- and this is something I would encourage in general-- even
和，logically--這是值得 我會鼓勵general--甚至
though we're only scratching the surface of some of these features.
雖然我們只是刮傷 的一些功能上。
>> And it might not be obvious when you yourself sit down at the keyboard,
>> 它可能不是很明顯，當你 自己坐到鍵盤，
how does this work?
這個怎麼用？
What would this do?
你會這樣嗎？
The beautiful thing about having a laptop, or desktop, or access
關於有美麗的東西 膝上型或桌面，或訪問
to a computer with a compiler, and with a code editor like this,
與編譯器的計算機， 與這樣的代碼編輯器，
is you can almost always answer these questions for yourself just by trying.
是你幾乎總是可以回答這些 問題為自己只是嘗試。
>> For instance, if the rhetorical question at hand were,
>> 例如，如果修辭 在眼前的問題是，
what happens if you forget your break statements?
如果你忘記了，會發生什麼 你break語句？
Which is actually a very common thing to do,
這實際上是一個 很平常的事，
because it doesn't look like you really need them.
因為它看起來並不 就像你真的需要它們。
They don't really complete your thought like a parenthesis or a curly
他們並不真正完成 像想一個括號或捲曲
brace does.
括號一樣。
Let's go ahead and recompile the code and see.
讓我們繼續前進， 重新編譯代碼，看看。
So make switch, dot slash switch.
因此，請開關，點斜線開關。
Let's type in lower case y, the top case, Enter.
讓我們輸入小寫 Y，頂的情況下，回車。
So I typed y.
所以我輸入年。
>> The program said yes, no, error, as though it was changing its mind.
>> 該計劃說的沒錯，沒有，錯誤， 因為雖然它是改變了主意。
But it kind of was, because what happens with a switch is the first case that
但是，那種是的，因為會發生什麼 有開關是第一種情況是
match essentially means, hey computer, execute all of the code beneath it.
比賽實際上意味著，哎電腦， 執行所有代碼的下方。
And if you don't say break, or don't say break, or don't say break,
如果你不說破，或 不說破，還是不說破，
the computer is going to blow through all of those lines
電腦會爆 通過所有這些行
and execute all of them until it gets to that curly brace.
並執行所有的人，直到 它獲取到大括號。
So the brakes are, indeed, necessary.
因此，剎車，的確有必要。
But a takeaway here is, when in doubt, try something.
但這裡外賣，當 有疑問，嘗試一些東西。
Maybe save your code first, or save it in an extra file
也許先救你的代碼， 或將其保存在一個額外的文件
if you're really worried about messing up and having to recover
如果你真的很擔心 搞亂了，不得不恢復
the work that you know is working.
你知道的工作是工作。
>> But try things.
>> 但嘗試的事情。
And don't be as afraid, perhaps, of what the computer might do,
不要像害怕，也許， 什麼樣的電腦可能會做，
or that you might break something.
或者，你可能碰壞。
You can always revert back to some earlier version.
您可以隨時恢復 一些早期版本。
>> So let's end by looking at the design of code.
>> 因此，讓我們通過觀察結束 在代碼的設計。
We have this ability now to write conditions, and write loops,
現在，我們有這個能力來寫 的條件下，與寫循環，
and variables, and call functions.
和變量，和通話功能。
So, frankly, we're kind of back at where we were a week ago with Scratch,
因此，坦率地說，我們是那種回 我們是一個星期前從無到有，
albeit with a less compelling textual environment than Scratch allows.
儘管有一個不太引人注目的文本 環境比刮允許。
>> But notice how quickly we've acquired that vocabulary, even if it's
>> 但是請注意，我們的速度已經獲得 那個詞彙，即使是
going to take a little while to sink in, so that we can now use this vocabulary
要帶一小會兒下沉， 所以，我們現在可以使用這個詞彙
to write more interesting programs.
寫出比較有趣的節目。
And let's take a baby step toward that, as follows.
讓我們一起來小步 往那，如下所示。
Let me go ahead and create a new file here.
讓我繼續前進， 在這裡創建一個新文件。
>> I'm going to call this prototype.c, and introduce
>> 我要調用此 prototype.c，並引進
for the first time, the ability to make your own functions.
首次的能力 使自己的功能。
Some of you might have done this with Scratch,
有些人可能有 有划痕做到了這一點，
whereby you can create your own custom blocks in Scratch,
讓你可以創建你 在刮自己的自定義模塊，
and then drag them into place wherever you'd like in C.
然後將它們拖放到的地方 無論你想在C.
And in most programming languages, you can do exactly
而在大多數編程 語言，你可以做完全
that-- make your own functions, if they don't already exist.
that--使自己的功能， 如果它們不存在。
>> So, for instance, let me go ahead and include CS50.h, and include
>> 所以，舉例來說，讓我先走 和包括CS50.h，並且包括
standard IO.h, int main void.
標準IO.h，INT主要作廢。
And now we have a placeholder ready to go.
現在我們有一個 佔位蓄勢待發。
I keep printing things like people's names today.
我一直在承印物 像今天的人的名字。
And that feels like-- wouldn't be nice if there
那種感覺like-- 不會是很好，如果有
were a function called print name?
是所謂的打印功能的名稱？
I don't have to use printf.
我沒有用printf。
I don't have to remember all the format codes.
我不必記住 所有的格式代碼。
Why don't I, or why didn't someone before me,
為什麼不要我，為什麼 沒有人在我面前，
create a function called print name, that given some name,
創建一個函數調用打印 名，給予一定的名字，
simply prints it out?
簡單地打印出來？
>> In other words, if I say, hey, computer, give me a string
>> 換句話說，如果我說，嘿， 電腦，給我一個字符串
by asking the user for such, via CS50's get string function.
通過詢問用戶這樣， 通過CS50的get字符串函數。
Hey, computer, put that string in the variable in the left hand side,
嘿，計算機，把那個字符串 在左手側的變量，
and call it s.
並稱之為秒。
And then, hey computer, go ahead and print that person's name, done.
然後，嘿嘿計算機，勇往直前 並打印此人的姓名，完成。
>> Now, it would be nice, because this program, aptly named,
>> 現在，這將是很好的，因為 這一方案，適當命名的，
tells me what it's supposed to do by way of those function's names.
告訴我這是什麼應該做的 這些函數的名稱的方式。
Let me go and make prototype, Enter.
讓我走，讓原型，回車。
And, unfortunately, this isn't going to fly.
而且，不幸的是， 這是不會飛。
>> Prototype.c, line 7, character 5, error, implicit declaration
>> Prototype.c，7號線，字符 5，錯誤，隱式聲明
of function print name is invalid in C99, C99
函數打印名字 在C99，C99是無效的
meaning a version of C that came out in 1999.
這意味著一個版本的C 在1999年就出來了。
That's all.
就這樣。
>> So I don't know what all of this means yet.
>> 所以，我不知道是什麼 所有這一切意味著呢。
But I do recognize error in red.
但我認識到紅色的錯誤。
That's pretty obvious.
這是很明顯的。
>> And it seems that with the green character here,
>> 並且似乎與 綠色性格在這裡，
the issue is with print name, open paren s, close paren, semi-colon.
問題是打印的名字，開 括號S，右括號，分號。
But implicit declaration of function we did see briefly earlier.
但隱式聲明 函數，我們確實看到前面簡單。
This means, simply, that Clang does not know what I mean.
這意味著，簡單地說，鏘 不知道我的意思。
>> I've used a vocabulary word that it's never seen or been taught before.
>> 我用一個詞彙詞，它的 以前從未見過或被教導。
And so I need to teach it what this function means.
所以，我要教它 這個函數是什麼意思。
So I'm going to go ahead and do that.
所以我要繼續前進，並做到這一點。
>> I'm going to go ahead and implement my own function called Print Name.
>> 我要繼續前進，實現 我自己的函數調用打印名稱。
And I'm going to say, as follows, that it does this, printf, hello, percent
而我要說，如下所示，這 它這樣做，printf的，你好，百分比
s, backslash n, name, semi-colon.
S，反斜線N，名稱，分號。
So what did I just do?
那麼，為什麼我只是做？
>> So it turns out, to implement your own function,
>> 因此，原來，為了 實現自己的功能，
we kind of borrow some of the same structure as main
我們種借用一些 相同的結構主要
that we've just been taken for granted, and I
我們剛剛得到 理所當然的，我
know just copying and pasting pretty much what
知道剛才複製和 粘貼幾乎什麼
I've been writing in the past.
我已經寫了過去。
But notice the pattern here.
但這裡要注意的格局。
Int, Main, Void, we'll tease apart before long what that actually means.
詮釋，主，無效的，我們將梳理出 沒過多久什麼實際意義。
>> But for today, just notice the parallelism.
>> 但在今天，只是 注意到並行性。
Void, print name, string name, so there's
太虛，打印的名字， 字符串名稱，所以有
a purple keyword, which we're going to start
一個紫色的關鍵字，這 我們要開始
calling a return type, the name of the function, and then the input.
調用返回類型，名稱 的功能，並且然後將輸入。
So, actually, we can distill this kind of like last week
所以，實際上，我們可以提煉出 這種上週一樣的
as, this is the name or the algorithm of the code we're
如，這是名稱或 我們的代碼算法
going to write-- the algorithm underlying
去寫 - 的 底層算法
the code we're going to write.
代碼我們將書寫。
>> This is its input.
>> 這是它的輸入。
This is its output.
這是它的輸出。
This function, print name, is designed to take a string called name,
此功能，打印的名字，是 設計上採用了一個名為名稱的字符串，
or whatever, as input, and then void.
也好，作為輸入，然後空隙。
It doesn't return anything, like get string or get int does.
它不返回任何東西， 像得到字符串或得到INT一樣。
So it's going to hand me something back.
所以它要交給我的東西回來。
It's just going to have a side effect, so to speak,
它只是將有一個 副作用，可以這麼說，
of printing a person's name.
印刷一個人的名字。
So notice, line 7, I can call print name.
因此注意到，7號線，我 可以調用打印名稱。
Line 10, I can define or implement print name.
10號線，我可以定義 或實施打印的名稱。
But, unfortunately, that's not enough.
但不幸的是，這還不夠。
>> Let me go ahead and recompile this after saving.
>> 讓我繼續前進， 保存後重新編譯這一點。
Whoa, now, I've made it worse, it would seem.
哇，現在，我做了它 更糟的是，它似乎。
So implicit declaration of function print name is invalid.
這樣的隱式聲明 功能打印名稱無效。
And, again, there's more errors.
並再次，還有更多的錯誤。
But as I cautioned earlier, even if you get overwhelmed with,
但正如我前面提醒，即使 如果你不知所措，
or a little sad to see so many errors, focus only on the first
還是有點難過，看到這麼多 錯誤，只專注於第一
initially, because it might just have had a cascading effect.
最初，因為它可能只是 產生了連鎖效應。
So C, or Clang more specifically, still does not recognize print name.
所以C，或鏘更具體地， 仍不能識別打印的名稱。
>> And that's because Clang, by design, is kind of dumb.
>> 那是因為鐺， 在設計上，是種愚蠢。
It only does what you tell it to do.
它只做你告訴它做什麼。
And it only does so in the order in which you tell it to do.
而且只在該命令這樣做 在你告訴它做。
>> So I have defined main on line four, like we've been doing pretty often.
>> 所以我定義主四線， 就像我們一直很經常做的事情。
I've defined print name on line 10.
我在第10行定義的打印名稱。
But I'm trying to use print name on line seven.
但我想使用 在七號線打印的名稱。
>> It's too soon, doesn't exist yet.
>> 這太快了，還不存在。
So I could be clever, and be like, OK, so let's just play along,
所以，我可能是聰明，像， 好了，我們只是一起玩，
and move print name up here, and re-compile.
和移動打印的名字了 這裡，和重新編譯。
Oh my God.
哦，我的上帝。
It worked.
有效。
It was as simple as that.
它是那樣簡單。
>> But the logic is exactly that.
>> 但邏輯正是如此。
You have to teach Clang what it is by defining the function first.
你要教鏘什麼 是通過首先確定函數。
Then you can use it.
然後你可以使用它。
But, frankly, this feels like a slippery slope.
但是，坦率地說，這種感覺 像滑坡。
>> So every time I run into a problem, I'm just
>> 所以每次我運行 一個問題，我只是
going to highlight and copy the code I wrote, cut it and paste it up here.
要突出顯示並複製代碼 我寫的，就把它和它粘貼在這裡了。
And, surely, we could contrive some scenarios
而且，可以肯定，我們可以 圖謀一些場景
where one function might need to call another.
其中一個可能的功能 需要調用另一個。
And you just can't put every function above every other.
而你只是不能把每 功能上面隔。
>> So it turns out there's a better solution.
>> 因此，原來在那裡的 一個更好的解決方案。
We can leave this be.
我們可以離開這個可以。
And, frankly, it's generally nice, and convenient, and good design
而且，坦率地說，這是普遍不錯， 方便，良好的設計
to put main first, because, again, main just like when green flag clicked,
把主要一是因為，再次， 主要就好像當綠旗​​點擊，
that is the function that gets executed by default.
這是函數是 被默認執行。
So you might as well put it at the top of the file
所以，你不妨把 它在該文件的頂部
so that when you or any other human looks at the file
所以，當您或任何 其他人查看文件
you know what's going on just by reading main first.
你知道這是怎麼回事 通過閱讀主要首位。
So it turns out, we can tell Clang proactively, hey, Clang, on line four,
所以，事實證明，我們可以告訴鏘 主動，嘿嘿，鏘，四線，
I promise to implement a function called Print
我答應實施 一個函數調用打印
Name that takes a string called name as input, and returns nothing, void.
名稱以一個字符串名為name 作為輸入，並且沒有返回的，無效的。
And I'll get around to implementing it later.
我會避開 後來實現它。
>> Here comes Main.
>> 這裡談到主。
Main now on line 9 can use Print Name because Clang
現在主要在第9行可以使用 打印名稱，因為鏘
is trusting that, eventually, it will encounter the definition
被信任的是，最終， 它會遇到的定義
of the implementation of Print Name.
姓名正楷的實施。
So after saving my file, let me go ahead and make prototype,
所以，救了我的文件之後，讓 我繼續前進，使原型，
looks good this time.
看起來不錯，這一次。
Dot slash, prototype, let me go ahead and type in a name.
點斜線，原型，讓我 繼續前進，鍵入一個名稱。
David, hello David, Zamila, hello Zamila, and, indeed, now it works.
大衛，你好大衛Zamila，你好 Zamila，事實上，現在的作品。
>> So the ingredient here is that we've made a custom function, like a custom
>> 因此，這裡的成分是，我們已經 做了一個自定義的功能，如自定義
Scratch block we're calling it.
划痕塊中，我們要調用它。
But unlike Scratch where you can just create it and start using it,
但是，與划痕在那裡你可以 只是創建它，並開始使用它，
now we have to be a little more pedantic,
現在我們要成為一個 多一點迂腐，
and actually train Clang to use, or to expect it.
實際上訓練鏘 使用，或指望它。
Now, as an aside, why all this time have we been just blindly on faith including
現在，順便說一句，為什麼這段時間有 我們一直只是盲目信仰，包括
CS50.h, and including standard IO.h?
CS50.h，並且包括標準IO.h？
>> Well, it turns out, among a few other things,
>> 那麼，事實證明， 其中一些其他的東西，
all that's in those dot h files, which happen to be files.
所有的這些點^ h 文件，這恰好是文件。
They're header files, so to speak.
他們在頭文件，可以這麼說。
They're still written in C. But they're a different type of file.
他們還在用C寫的但是 他們是不同類型的文件。
>> For now, you can pretty much assume that all that is inside of CS50.h
>> 現在，你幾乎可以承擔 所有這是CS50.h內
is some one-liners like this, not for functions called Print Name,
一些單行尚且如此， 名為打印名稱的功能，
but for Get String, Get Float, and a few others.
但對於獲取字符串，獲取 浮動，和其他幾個人。
And there are similar prototypes, one liners, inside of standard IO.h
而也有類似的原型， 單行，標準IO.h內
for printf, which is now in my own Print Name function.
像printf，這是現在在 我自己打印名稱的功能。
So in other words, this whole time we've just been blindly copying and pasting
因此，換句話說，這整個時間內，我們 剛剛被盲目複製和粘貼
include this, include that, what's going on?
包括這一點，包括 這，這是怎麼回事？
Those are just kind of clues to Clang as to what functions
這些僅僅是一種線索 以鐺，以什麼功能
are, indeed, implemented, just elsewhere in different files
的確都是執行，只是 在不同的文件別處
elsewhere on the system.
別處在系統上。
>> So we've implemented print name.
>> 因此，我們已經實現打印的名稱。
It does have this side effect of printing something on the screen.
它確實有這種副作用 打印屏幕上的內容。
But it doesn't actually hand me something back.
但它實際上並沒有 遞給我的東西回來。
How do we go about implementing a program that
我們如何去 執行一個程序，
does hand me something back?
並交給我的東西回來？
>> Well, let's try this.
>> 好吧，讓我們試試這個。
Let me go ahead and implement a file called return.c
我要繼續貫徹 一個名為return.c
so we can demonstrate how something like Get String, or Get Int,
所以我們可以演示如何的東西 以獲得更多的字符串，或得到詮釋，
is actually returning something back to the user.
實際上回國 回饋給用戶。
Let's go ahead and define int main void.
讓我們繼續前進，並確定主要INT無效。
>> And, again, in the future, we'll explain what that int and that void
>> 並再次，在未來，我們將 解釋什麼是int和這一空白
is actually doing.
其實這樣做。
But for today, we'll take it for granted.
但今天，我們將 理所當然。
I'm going to go ahead and printf, for a good user experience, x is.
我會繼續和printf， 一個良好的用戶體驗，x是。
And then I'm going to wait for the user to give me x with get int.
然後，我會等待 用戶給我x，其中GET INT。
>> And then I'm going to go ahead and print out x to the square.
>> 然後我要繼續前進 並打印出X到廣場。
So when you only have a keyboard, people commonly
所以，當你只有一個 鍵盤，一般的人
use the little carrot symbol on the keyboard
使用小蘿蔔 鍵盤上的符號
to represent to the power of, or the exponent of.
代表的功率 的，或者的指數。
So x squared is present i.
SO x的平方是目前我。
>> And now I'm going to do this.
>> 現在我要做到這一點。
I could just do-- what's x squared? x squared is x times x.
我可以do--什麼的x 平方？點¯x平方為x倍的X.
>> And we did this some time ago already today.
>> 我們這樣做了一些 今天已經很久以前。
This doesn't feel like all that much progress.
這種感覺並不像 那麼多的進展。
You know what?
你知道嗎？
Let's leverage some of that idea from last time of abstraction.
讓我們利用一些想法 從抽象的最後一次。
>> Wouldn't it be nice if there's a function called
>> 那豈不是很好，如果 有一個調用的函數
square that does exactly that?
方認為正是這麼做的？
It still, at the end of the day, does the same math.
它仍然在的結束 一天，做了同樣的數學。
But let's abstract away the idea of taking
但是，讓我們抽象 拿走的想法
one number multiplied by another, and just give it a name,
一個數字乘以 另一個，只要給它一個名稱，
like square this value.
像方此值。
>> And, in other words, in C, let's create a function
>> 並且，換句話說，在 C，讓我們創建一個功能
called square that does exactly that.
叫方認為正是這麼做的。
It's going to be called square.
這將被調用方。
It's going to take an int.
這將需要一個int。
And we'll will just call it n, by default.
我們會只是 稱之為N，默認情況下。
>> But we could call it anything we want.
>> 但我們可以把它叫做什麼，我們想要的。
And all that it's going to do, literally, is return
和所有它會 這樣做，從字面上看，就是回報
the result of n times n.
n次n的結果。
But because it is returning something, which
但是，因為它是 回國東西，這
is the keyword in purple we've never seen before, I, on line 11,
在紫色我們已經關鍵字 以前從未見過，我，第11行，
can't just say void this time.
不能說作廢這個時候。
>> Void, in the example we just saw rather of print name, just means,
>> 太虛，在這個例子中，我們剛才看到 而打印的名字，只是表示，
do something.
做一點事。
But don't hand me something back.
但是，不要遞給我的東西回來。
In this case, I do want to return n times n,
在這種情況下，我想 返回n次N，
or whatever that is, that number.
或者不管它是什麼，該號碼。
>> So I can't say, hey, computer, I return nothing, void.
>> 所以，我不能說，哎，電腦， 我返回任何結果，無效的。
It's going to return, by nature, an int.
這將返回在本質上，一個int。
And so that's all that's going on here.
所以，這是所有在這裡嗎。
>> The input to square is going to be an int.
>> 輸入方 將是一個int。
And so that we can use it, it has to have a name, N. It's going to output
因此，我們可以使用它，它有 有一個名字，N.這將輸出
an int that doesn't need a name.
一個int並不需要一個名字。
We can leave it to main, or whoever is using me to remember this value if we
我們可以把它交給主，或者是誰 用我記住，如果我們這個值
want with its own variable.
想擁有自己的變量。
>> And, again, the only new keyword here is Return.
>> 並再次，唯一的新 關鍵字這裡是回歸。
And I'm just doing some math.
而我只是在做一些數學。
If I really wanted to be unnecessary, I could say int product gets n times n.
如果我真的想成為不必要的， 我可以說INT產品得到n次ñ。
>> And then I could say, return product.
>> 然後，我可以說，回歸產品。
But, again, to my point earlier of this just not being good design--
但同樣，我的觀點同期 這恰恰不是好的設計 -
like, why introduce a name, a symbol, like product,
喜歡，為什麼引入一個名字， 一個符號，如產品，
just to immediately return it?
只是立即返回呢？
It's a little cleaner, a little tighter, so
這是一個有點清潔， 有點緊張，所以
to speak, just to say return n times n, get rid of this line altogether.
說話，只是說回n倍 N，擺脫這一行乾脆。
>> And it's just less code to read, less opportunity for mistakes.
>> 它只是較少的代碼閱讀， 失誤少的機會。
And let's see if this actually now works.
讓我們看看這個 其實現在的作品。
Now, I'm going to go ahead and make return.
現在，我要去 提前做出回報。
>> Uh-oh, implicit declaration of function.
>> 嗯，哦，功能隱式聲明。
I made this mistake before, no big deal.
我以前犯了這個錯誤，沒什麼大不了的。
Let me just type, or highlight and copy, the exact same function prototype,
我只需鍵入，或突出顯示和 複製，完全相同的函數原型，
or signature, of the function up here.
或簽名，該功能在這裡的。
Or I could move the whole function.
或者，我可以移動整個功能。
>> But that's a little lazy.
>> 但是，這是一個有點懶惰。
So we won't do that.
因此，我們不會那麼做。
Now, let me make return again, dot slash return.
現在，讓我回 再次，點斜線回報。
>> x is 2. x squared is 4. x is 3. x squared is 9.
>> x為2。X的平方等於4。 x被。X的平方等於9。
And the function seems now to be working.
而功能似乎 現在的工作。
So what's the difference here?
那麼，有什麼區別嗎？
I have a function that's called square, in this case, which I put in an input.
我有一個這就是所謂的平方函數， 在這種情況下，我把在一個輸入。
And I get back an output.
而我回來的輸出。
And yet, previously, if I open the other example
然而，此前，如果 我打開其他的例子
from earlier, which was called prototype.c,
從早期的，這 被稱為prototype.c，
I had print name, which returned void, so to speak,
我有打印的名稱， 退回作廢，可以這麼說，
Or it returned nothing, and simply had a side effect.
或者，它返回什麼， 簡單地產生了副作用。
>> So what's going on here?
>> 那麼是什麼回事？
Well, consider the function get string for just a moment.
那麼，考慮功能 得到的字符串只是一瞬間。
We've been using the function get string in the following way.
我們一直在使用功能 得到以下列方式串。
>> We've had a function get string, like include CS50.h,
>> 我們有一個函數來獲取 字符串，如包括CS50.h，
include standard IO.h, int, main, void.
包括標準IO.h，INT，主要的，無效的。
And then every time I've called get string thus far,
然後每一次我 名為get字符串到目前為止，
I've said something like, string s gets get string, because get string--
我說的一樣，字符串s 得到得到的字符串，因為GET string--
let's call this get.c-- get string itself returns a string that I can then
我們稱之為get.c-- GET字符串 本身返回一個字符串，我可以再
use, and say, hello, comma, percent s, backslash n, s.
用了，說，你好，逗號， ％的S，反斜線N，S。
>> So this is the same example, really, that we had earlier.
>> 因此，這是相同的例子， 真的，我們前面了。
So get string returns a value.
因此，獲得字符串返回一個值。
But a moment ago, print string does not return a value.
但是剛才，打印字符串 沒有返回值。
It simply has a side effect.
它只是有一個副作用。
So this is a fundamental difference.
所以這是一個根本的區別。
We've seen different types of functions now,
我們已經看到了不同的 類型的功能現在，
some of which have returned values, some of which don't.
其中一些已經返回 值，其中一些則沒有。
So maybe it's string, or int, or float.
因此，也許它的字符串或整型，浮點或。
Or maybe it's just void.
或者，也許它只是無效。
>> And the difference is that these functions that
>> 不同的是 這些函數
get data and return a value are actually bringing something back to the table,
獲取數據並返回一個值實際上是 把東西回表，
so to speak.
可以這麼說。
So let's go ahead and look at one final set
因此，讓我們繼續前進， 看一眼決勝盤
of examples that gives a sense, now, of how we might, indeed, abstract better,
的實施例，給出了一個感，現在的 我們怎麼可能，的確，抽象更好，
and better, and better, or more, and more, and more, in order
更好，更好或更多 多，而且多，為了
to write, ultimately, better code.
寫，最終更好的代碼。
Let's go ahead, and in the spirit of Scratch, do the following.
讓我們繼續前進，並在精神 刮，做到以下幾點。
>> Let me go ahead and include CS50.h and standard IO.h.
>> 讓我繼續前進，包括 CS50.h和標準IO.h.
Let me go ahead and give myself an int, main, void.
讓我先走，並把 我自己一個int，主要的，無效的。
And let me go ahead, call this cough.c.
讓我先走，稱此cough.c。
>> And let me go ahead and just like Scratch, print out cough/n.
>> 讓我繼續前進，只是 像划痕，打印出咳嗽/ N。
And I want to do this three times.
我想這樣做三次。
So I'm, of course, just going to copy and paste three times.
所以我，當然，只是去 複製和粘貼三次。
I'm now going to make cough dot slash cough.
我現在要作 咳嗽點斜線咳嗽。
Let's give myself a little more room here, Enter, cough, cough, cough.
讓我們給自己多一點的房間 在這裡，回車，咳，咳，咳。
>> There's, obviously, already an opportunity for improvement.
>> 還有，很明顯，已經是一個 機會改善。
I've copied and pasted a few times today.
我複製並粘貼 今天一幾次。
But that was only so I didn't have to type as many characters.
但是，這是唯一的，所以我沒有 必須輸入盡可能多的字符。
I still changed what those lines of code are.
我還是改變了什麼 這些代碼行。
>> These three lines are identical, which feels lazy and indeed is,
>> 這三條線是相同的， 這感覺懶惰，的確是，
and is probably not the right approach.
而可能是不正確的方法。
So with what ingredient could we improve this code?
那麼什麼成分 我們可以改善這個代碼？
We don't have to copy and paste code.
我們不必複製和粘貼的代碼。
>> And, indeed, any time you feel yourself copying and pasting,
>> 而且，事實上，任何時候你感覺 自己複製和粘貼，
and not even changing code, odds are there's a better way.
即使不更改代碼， 賠率是有一個更好的辦法。
And, indeed, there is.
而且，事實上，有。
Let me go ahead and do a for loop, even though the syntax might not
讓我繼續前進，循環做了， 即使語法可能不
come naturally yet.
自然來呢。
>> Do this three times, simply by doing the following--
>> 這樣做三次，只需 通過執行following--
and I happen to know this from practice.
我碰巧從實踐中知道這一點。
But we have a number of examples now.
但是，我們有一些例子吧。
And you'll see online more references still.
你會看到在線 更多的參考依然。
>> This is the syntax on line 6, that much like Scratch that repeats
>> 這是第6行的句法，即 就像從頭開始重複
block, repeat the following three times.
塊，重複下面的三倍。
It's a little magical for now.
這是一個有點神奇現在。
But this will get more, and more familiar.
但是，這會得到更多， 越來越熟悉。
>> And it's going to repeat line eight three times,
>> 而且它會重複 八號線三次，
so that if I re-compile make cough, dot slash cough, cough, cough, cough.
所以，如果我重新編譯化妝咳嗽， 點斜線咳，咳，咳，咳。
It still works the same way.
它仍然以同樣的方式。
So that's all fine and good.
所以這是一切優秀和良好。
But that's not very abstracted.
但是，這不是很抽象。
>> It's perfectly correct.
>> 這是完全正確的。
But it feels like there could be an opportunity,
但感覺好像有 可能是一個機會，
as in the world of Scratch, to kind of start
作為在世界 從無到有，來樣開始
to add some semantics here so that I don't just have some for loop,
在這裡添加一些語義使 我不只是有一定的循環，
and a function that says cough, or does cough.
和一個函數，說 咳嗽，還是咳嗽。
You know what?
你知道嗎？
Let me try to be a little cooler than that,
我想做個 有點涼比，
and actually write a function that has some side effects, call it cough.
實際上編寫一個函數， 有一定的副作用，稱之為咳嗽。
>> And it takes no input, and returns no value as output.
>> 而且它沒有輸入， 無返回值作為輸出。
But you know what it does?
但是你知道它做什麼？
It does this-- printf, quote unquote, cough.
它this--的printf， 報價引文結束，咳嗽。
>> And now up here, I'm going to go ahead and for int,
>> 現在在這裡，我要去 繼續前進，對於int，
i gets zero, i less than 3, i plus plus.
我得到零，我不到3，我加再加。
I'm going to not do printf, which is arguably a low level implementation
我會不會做的printf，這是 可以說是一個低層次的實現
detail.
詳情。
I don't care how to cough.
我不在乎怎麼咳嗽。
I just want to use the cough function.
我只是想用止咳的功能。
And I'm just going to call cough.
而我只是要打電話咳嗽。
>> Now, notice the dichotomy.
>> 現在，請注意二分法。
When you call a function, if you don't want to give it inputs, totally fine.
當你調用一個函數，如果你不 想給它輸入，完全罰款。
Just do open paren, close paren, and you're done.
只要做開括號，接近 括號，就大功告成了。
>> When you define a function, or declare a function's prototype,
>> 當你定義一個函數，或 聲明函數的原型，
if you know in advance it's not going to take any arguments,
如果你事先知道這不是 要採取任何參數，
say void in those parentheses there.
說這些括號出現空白。
And that makes certain that you won't accidentally misuse it.
這使某些你 會不小心誤用。
Let me go ahead and make cough.
讓我繼續前進，使咳嗽。
And, of course, I've made a mistake.
而且，當然，我犯了一個錯誤。
>> Dammit, there's that implicit declaration.
>> 該死的，還有那 隱式聲明。
But that's fine.
但是，這很好。
It's an easy fix.
這是一個容易解決。
I just need the prototype higher up in my file than I'm actually using it.
我需要的只是原型上漲 在我的文件比我實際使用它。
>> So now let me make cough again, nice.
>> 所以，現在讓我又咳嗽，美觀大方。
Now, it works.
現在，它的工作原理。
Make cough, cough, cough, cough.
讓咳，咳，咳，咳。
So you might think that we're really just over engineering this problem.
所以，你可能會認為我們真的 剛過工程這個問題。
And, indeed, we are.
而且，事實上，我們是。
This is not a good candidate of a program
這不是一個好 的程序的候補
at the moment for refactoring, and doing what's
在時刻 重構，做什麼
called hierarchical decomposition, where you take some code, and then
所謂的層次分解， 在這裡你需要一些代碼，然後
you kind of factor things out, so as to ascribe more semantics to them,
有種你因子東西出來，這樣 歸於更多的語義他們，
and reuse it ultimately longer term.
和重用它最終長期的。
But it's a building block toward more sophisticated programs
但它是一個構建塊朝 更複雜的程序
that we will start writing before long that
我們將開始 之前寫了長
allows us to have the vocabulary with which to write better code.
讓我們有詞彙 與寫出更好的代碼。
And, indeed, let's see if we can't generalize this further.
而且，事實上，讓我們看看，如果我們 不能一概而論進一步此。
>> It seems a little lame that I, main, need to worry about this darn for loop,
>> 這似乎有點跛，我，主， 需要擔心這個該死的for循環，
and calling cough again and again.
並一再呼籲咳嗽。
Why can't I just tell cough, please cough three times?
為什麼我不能只是告訴咳嗽， 請咳嗽三次？
In other words, why can't I just give input to cough and do this?
換句話說，為什麼我不能只是 給輸入咳嗽，做到這一點？
>> Why can't I just say, in main cough three times.
>> 為什麼我不能只是說，在 主咳嗽三次。
And now, this is kind of magical.
而現在，這是種神奇。
It's very iterative here.
這是非常反复的在這裡。
And it's, indeed, a baby step.
而且它是，事實上，一個嬰兒的一步。
>> But just the ability to say on line eight, cough three times,
>> 但就在能力上說， 八號線，咳嗽三次，
it's just so much more readable.
它只是這麼多的可讀性。
And, plus, I don't have to know or care how cough is implemented.
而且，再加上，我不必知道 或護理咳嗽是如何實現的。
And, indeed, later in the term and for final projects,
而且，事實上，在後來的 長期和最終項目，
if you tackle a project with a classmate or two classmates,
如果你處理一個項目 一個同學或兩位同學，
you'll realize that you're going to have to, or want to, divide the work.
你會意識到，你要 有，或者想，分工。
>> And you're going to want to decide in advance, who's going to do what,
>> 而你會想決定 事先，誰去做些什麼，
and in which pieces?
並在其中部分？
And wouldn't it be nice if you, for instance,
而不會是好的 如果，例如，
take charge of writing main, done.
負責撰寫主力，完成。
And your roommate, or your partner more generally,
而你的室友，或者你 夥伴更一般地，
takes care of implementing cough.
負責實施的咳嗽。
>> And this division, these walls of abstraction,
>> 而且這種劃分，這些 抽象的牆，
or layers of abstraction if you will, are super powerful,
抽象或層，如果 你會，是超級強大，
because especially for larger, more complex programs and systems,
因為特別是較大的， 更複雜的程序和系統，
it allows multiple people to build things together, and ultimately
它允許多個人建 東西放在一起，最終
stitch their work together in this way.
縫合在一起以這種方式工作。
But, of course, we need to now fix cough.
但是，當然，我們 現在需要解決的咳嗽。
We need to tell cough that, hey, you know what?
我們需要告訴咳嗽 ，嘿，你知道嗎？
You're going to need to take an input-- so not void, but int and now.
你將需要採取 input--所以並不作廢，int和現在。
Let's go ahead and put into cough the int. i gets zero.
讓我們繼續前進並投入 咳嗽整型。我得到零。
>> i is less than how many times.
>> i小於多少倍。
I said three before.
我以前說過三種。
But that's not what I want.
但是，這不是我想要的。
I want cough to be generalized to support any number of iterations.
我想咳嗽推廣到 支持任何數量的迭代。
>> So, indeed, it's n that I want, whatever the user tells me.
>> 所以，事實上，它是n表示我想， 無論用戶告訴我。
Now, I can go ahead and say print cough.
現在，我可以繼續說打印咳嗽。
And no matter what number the user passes in,
無論什麼號碼 用戶通過在，
I will iterate that many times.
我會重複很多次。
>> So at the end of the day, program is identical.
>> 這樣在一天結束時， 程序是相同的。
But notice all of this stuff could even be in another file.
但是請注意，所有的這些東西 甚至可以是在另一文件中。
Indeed, I don't know at the moment how printf is implemented.
事實上，我不知道在 此刻怎麼printf的實現。
>> I don't know at the moment how get string, or get int, or get float
>> 我不知道此刻怎麼弄 串，或得到int或獲得浮動
are implemented.
的貫徹落實。
And I don't want to see them on my screen.
而且我不希望 看到他們我的屏幕上。
As it is, I'm starting to focus on my program, not those functions.
正因為如此，我開始專注於 我的程序，而不是那些功能。
>> And so, indeed, as soon as you start factoring code like this out,
>> 所以，事實上，只要你 開始分解這樣的代碼了，
could we even move cough to a separate file?
可能我們連招咳嗽 到一個單獨的文件？
Someone else could implement it.
別人可以實現它。
And you and your program become the very beautiful, and very readable,
你和你的程序成為 很漂亮，非常具有可讀性，
arguably, really four line program right there.
可以說，真正的4 行程序就在那裡。
>> So let's go ahead now and make one more change.
>> 現在讓我們繼續前進 並作一次改變。
Notice that my prototype has to change up top.
請注意，我的原型 必須改變往上頂。
So let me fix that so I don't get yelled at.
因此，讓我解決，這麼 我沒有得到大聲呵斥。
>> Make cough, let me run cough once more, still doing the same thing.
>> 使咳嗽，讓我跑一次咳嗽 更多的，仍然在做同樣的事情。
But now, notice we have an ingredient for one final version.
但現在，看到我們有一個 成分為最後一個版本。
You know what?
你知道嗎？
I don't want to just cough, necessarily.
我不希望只是咳嗽，不一定。
I want to have something more general.
我希望有更多的東西一般。
So you know what?
所以，你知道嗎？
I want to do this.
我想這樣做。
I want to have, much like Scratch does, a say block, but not just
我想有，就像刮 確實，一說塊，但不只是
say something some number of times.
說些什麼的時候一定數目。
I want it to say a very specific string.
我希望它說一個非常具體的字符串。
And, therefore, I don't want it to just say cough.
，因此，我不知道 希望它只是說咳嗽。
I want it to say whatever string is passed in.
我希望它說什麼 字符串在通過。
>> So notice, I've generalized this so that now
>> 所以請注意，我全身 這讓現在
say feels like a good name for this, like Scratch,
比方說感覺就像一個好名字 對於這一點，喜歡從無到有，
takes two arguments, unlike Scratch.
有兩個參數，不像劃傷。
One is a string.
之一是一個字符串。
One is an int.
一個是一個int。
>> And I could switch them.
>> 我可以切換。
I just kind of like the idea of say the string first, and then
我只是有點像的想法 說字符串，然後再
how many times later.
多少次以後。
Void means it still doesn't return anything.
虛空意味著它仍然 不返回任何東西。
These are just visual side effects, like with [? Jordan, ?]
這些僅僅是視覺方面 效果，像[？喬丹？]
a verbal side effect of yelling.
大呼小叫的口頭副作用。
It still does something n times, 0 up to, but not equal to n.
它仍然做了n次， 0到，但不等於n。
This means n total times.
這意味著全部N次。
And then just print out whatever that string is.
然後只需打印出 無論是字符串。
So I've really generalized this line of code.
所以，我真的全身 這行代碼。
So now, how do I implement the cough function?
所以，現在，我該如何實現 咳嗽功能？
>> I can do void cough.
>> 我可以做無效咳嗽。
And I can still take in how many times you want to cough.
我仍然可以在如何 你想多次咳嗽。
But you know what?
但是，你知道嗎？
I can now punt to say.
現在我可以踢的話。
>> I can call say with the word cough, passing in n.
>> 我可以調用的說 字咳嗽，經過n的。
And if I want to also implement, just for fun, a sneeze function,
如果我想，也能實現， 只是為了好玩，一個噴嚏功能，
I can sneeze some number of times.
我打噴嚏的時候一定數目。
And I can keep reusing n, because notice that m in this context or scope
我可以繼續重用N，因為 注意到在這種情況下或範圍是m
only exists within this function.
只有在這個函數中存在。
>> And n in this context only exists within this function here.
>> 和N在這種情況下只 這裡這個函數中存在。
So we'll come back to these issues of scope.
因此，我們會回來的 範圍這些問題。
And here, I'm just going to say, achoo, and then n times, semi-colon.
而在這裡，我只是說， ACHOO，然後n倍，分號。
>> And now, I just need to borrow these function signatures up here.
>> 而現在，我只需要借用 這些功能在這裡簽名了。
So cough is correct.
所以咳嗽是正確的。
Void sneeze is correct now.
虛空噴嚏現在是正確的。
>> And I still just need say.
>> 我仍然只是需要說。
So I'm going to say, say string s, int n, semi-colon.
所以我要說，說 字符串s，詮釋N，分號。
So I've over-engineered the heck out of this program.
所以，我已經過度設計的 赫克出這個計劃。
>> And this doesn't necessarily mean this is
>> 這並不 一定意味著這是
what you should do when writing even the simplest of programs.
寫作時你應該做的 節目即使是最簡單。
Take something that's obviously really simple, really short,
就拿東西是很明顯 很簡單，真的很短，
and re-implement it using way too much code.
並重新實現它 使用太多的代碼。
But you'll actually see, and in time look back on these examples,
但是，你實際看到的，而在 時間回頭看這些例子，
and realize, oh, those are the steps we took to actually generalize,
與實現，哦，那些步驟 我們採取了實際一概而論，
to factor something out, until at the end of the day
要因素出來的東西， 直到在一天結束
my code is actually pretty reasonable.
我的代碼實際上是非常合理的。
Because if I want to cough three times then sneeze three times,
因為如果我想咳嗽3 次，然後打噴嚏三次，
I'm simply going to rerun this, program make cough, and run cough.
我只是要重新運行此， 計劃使咳嗽，並運行咳嗽。
And I have three coughs and three sneezes.
而且我有三個咳嗽 和三個噴嚏。
>> And so this is a basic paradigm, if you will,
>> 所以這是一個基本的 範例，如果你願意，
for how we might go about actually implementing a program.
對於我們如何去 實際執行的程序。
But let's just see now what it is we've been doing all of this time,
但是讓我們只看到現在是什麼 我們一直在做這一切的時候，
and what some of the final pieces are behind this simple command.
什麼一些最終件 這是簡單的命令後面。
At the end of the day, we've been using Clang as our compiler.
在一天結束的時候，我們已經 使用鏘作為我們編譯了。
We've been writing source code, converting it
我們一直在寫源 代碼，將其轉換
via Clang into machine code.
通過鏘成機器代碼。
>> And we've been using Make just to facilitate our keystrokes so
>> 而且我們一直在使用剛剛製作 以方便我們這樣的擊鍵
that we don't have to remember those incantations of Clang itself.
我們不必記住 鏘本身的咒語。
But what is Make actually doing?
但是，什麼是讓真正在做什麼？
And, in turn, what is Clang actually doing?
並且，反過來，是什麼 鏘實際上做？
>> It turns out, though we have simplified today's discussion by saying,
>> 事實證明，儘管我們已經簡化 說今天的討論，
you take source code, pass it as input to a compiler, which gives you
你把源代碼，把它作為 輸入一個編譯器，它給你
output of machine code, turns out there's
機的輸出 代碼，原來有
a few different steps inside there.
裡邊有幾個不同的步驟。
And compiling happens to be the umbrella term for a whole bunch of steps.
和編譯恰好是傘 術語一大堆的步驟。
But let's just tease this out really quickly.
但是，我們只是戲弄 這一點真的很快。
>> It turns out that we've been doing more things every time I run a program,
>> 事實證明，我們一直在做 更多的事情我每次運行一個程序的時候，
or every time I compile a program today.
或每次我今天編譯程序。
So preprocessing refers to this-- anything in a C program,
因此，預處理是指 在C程序this--什麼，
as we'll see again and again, that starts with this hash symbol,
如我們一次又一次地看到， 與此井號開始，
or the hashtag symbol here, means it's a preprocessor directive.
還是這裡的＃標籤符號，意味著 這是一個預處理指令。
That means, in this case, hey computer, do something with this file
這意味著，在這種情況下，餵 計算機，做一些與此文件
before you actually compile my own code.
在你真正編譯自己的代碼。
>> In this case, hash include is, essentially, C's way of saying,
>> 在此情況下，散列包括就是 本質上，C的說法方式，
hey computer, go get the contents of CS50.h and paste them here.
哎電腦，去獲得內容 CS50.h，並將其粘貼在這裡。
Hey computer, go get the contents of standard IO.h,
嘿電腦，去獲得的 標準IO.h的內容，
wherever that is on the hard drive, paste it here.
無論是在 硬盤驅動器，它貼在這裡。
So those things happen first during preprocessing.
因此，這些事情發生 預處理時先。
>> And Clang does all of this for us.
>> 而鏘做這一切對我們來說。
And it does it so darn fast, you don't even
並且實現起來這麼混賬 快，你甚至不
see four distinct things happening.
看到四個不同的事情發生。
But that's the first such step.
但是，這是第一個這樣的一步。
>> What actually happens next?
>> 其實什麼接下來會發生？
Well, the next official step is compiling.
好了，接下來的正式 一步是編譯。
And it turns out that compiling a program
而事實證明， 編譯程序
technically means going from source code, the stuff we've
技術上意味著從去 源代碼，我們已經東東
been writing today, to something called assembly code, something
今天一直在寫，東西 所謂的彙編代碼，東西
that looks a little different.
看起來有點不同。
>> And, in fact, we can see this real fast.
>> 而且，事實上，我們可以真正快速的看到這一點。
Let me actually go into my IDE.
讓我真正進入我的IDE。
Let me go ahead and open hello.c, which is the very first program with which we
讓我繼續前進，開放的hello.c，這 是第一個程序，使用它我們
began today.
今天開始了。
And let me go ahead and run Clang a little differently, Clang-s, hello.c,
讓我繼續運行鏘一 有點不同，鏘-S，hello.c中，
which is actually going to give me another file hello.s.
這實際上是要 給我另一個文件hello.s。
>> And we will probably never again see this kind of code.
>> 我們可能永遠不會 再次看到這種代碼。
If you take a lower level systems class like CS61,
如果你把一個較低的水平 系統類像CS61，
you will see a lot more of this kind of code.
你會看到更多 的這種代碼。
But this is assembly language.
但是，這是彙編語言。
This is X86 assembly language that the CPU that is underlying
這是X86彙編語言 這是基本的CPU
CS50 IDE actually understands.
CS50 IDE實際上理解。
>> And cryptic as it does look, it is something
>> 和隱蔽因為它 看，那是什麼
the computer understands pretty well.
計算機理解得很好。
Sub q, this is a subtract.
子Q，這是一個減法。
There's movements.
有動作。
>> There's calling of functions here, x oring, a movement, an add, a pop,
>> 還有的調用函數在這裡， 點¯xO形圈，一個動作，一個插件，彈出，
a return.
回報。
So there's some very low level instructions
因此，有一些非常 低級別的指令
that CPUs understand that I alluded to earlier.
該CPU的理解， 我前面提到。
That is what Intel Inside.
這就是英特爾內部。
>> There are patterns of zeros and ones that
>> 有模式 零和一其
map to these arcanely worded, but somewhat well-named, instructions,
映射到這些措辭arcanely，但 有些良好的命名，說明，
so to speak.
可以這麼說。
That is what happens when you compile your code.
那是發生在什麼 您編譯代碼。
You get assembly language out of it, which
你得到總成 語言出來，這
means the third step is to assemble that assembly code into, ultimately,
裝置的第三個步驟是組裝 該彙編代碼進入，最終，
machine code-- zeros and ones, not the text that we just saw a moment ago.
機代碼 - 零和一，而不是 文本剛才我們看到剛才。
>> So pre-processing does that find and replace, and a few other things.
>> 因此，預處理這是否找到 和替換，以及一些其他的東西。
Compiling takes your source code from C, source code
編譯把你的源代碼 從C代碼，源代碼
that we wrote, to assembly code that we just glanced at.
我們寫的，到組裝 代碼，我們只是看了一眼。
Assembling takes that assembly code to zeroes and ones
組裝需要該程序集 碼到零和一
that the CPU really will understand at the end of the day.
該CPU真的會 理解在一天結束。
And linking is the last step that happens for us-- again,
和鏈接是最後一步 出現這種情況的再次us--，
so fast we don't even notice-- that says,
如此之快，我們甚至不 notice--，上面寫著：
hey computer, take all of the zeros and ones that
哎電腦，採取所有的 在零和一的
resulted from compiling David's code, and his main function in this case.
源於編譯大衛的代碼， 和他在這種情況下，主要的功能。
>> And hey computer, go get all of the zeros and ones
>> 哎電腦，去獲得 所有的零和一
that the CS50 staff wrote inside the CS50 library.
該工作人員CS50寫道： 在CS50庫內。
Mix those in with David's.
混合那些與大衛的。
And hey computer, go get all the zeros and ones that someone else wrote years
哎電腦，去獲得所有的零 和那些別人寫了幾年
ago for printf.
以前像printf。
And add those into the whole thing, so that we've
而這些添加進 整個事情，讓我們已經
got my zeros and ones, the CS50 staff's zeros and ones,
得到了我的零和一的 CS50員工的零和的，
the printf zeros and ones, and anything else we're using.
printf的的零和一， 和我們使用其他任何東西。
>> They all get combined together into one program called, in this case, hello.
>> 它們都能夠結合在一起成一個 程序調用，在這種情況下，餵。
So henceforth, we will just use the word compiling.
所以，從今以後，我們將只 用這個詞編譯。
And we will take for granted that when we say, compile your program, it means,
我們會理所當然地認為，當 我們說，編譯你的程序，這意味著，
hey do the pre-processing, assembling, and linking.
哎做預處理， 彙編和連接。
But there's actually some juicy stuff going on there underneath the hood.
但實際上有一些多汁的東西 對那裡發生的引擎蓋下面。
And especially if you get curious some time,
特別是如果你 讓好奇的一段時間，
you can start poking around at this lower level.
你可以開始戳 圍繞在這個較低的水平。
But for now, realize that among the takeaways for today
但是現在，意識到 在外賣今天之一
are quite simply the beginning of a process,
是很簡單的 開始的過程中，
of getting comfortable with something like hello world.
越來越舒服的 類似的hello world。
Indeed, most of what we did today certainly won't sink in super fast.
事實上，大多數的我們今天做了 當然不會下沉超快。
And it will take some time, and some practice.
它會採取一些 時間，以及一些實踐。
And odds are, you will sort of want to hit your keyboard
賠率是，你將整理 的想打你的鍵盤
or yell at the screen.
或者在屏幕大喊大叫。
And all of that's OK.
而所有的這行。
Though, perhaps try not to do it in the library so much.
不過，也許是盡量不要 這樣做在圖書館這麼多。
>> And ultimately, you'll be able though, to start
>> 最終，你會 被能夠雖然，以啟動
seeing patterns, both in good code that you've written and in mistakes
眼看模式，無論是在好的代碼 你寫在錯誤
that you've made.
你所做的。
And much like the process of becoming a TF or a CA is like,
和很像的過程 成為一個TF或CA是什麼樣子，
you'll start to get better and better at seeing those patterns,
你會開始變得更好， 在看到這些模式比較好，
and just solving your own problems ultimately.
和公正的解決您的 自己的問題最終。
In the meantime, there will be plenty of us to lend you support, and get you
在此期間，將有大量 我們借給你們的支持，讓你
through this.
通過這個。
And in the write-ups for all of the problems
而在寫窗口 對於所有的問題
will you be guided through all of the commands
你會通過引導 所有的命令
that I certainly know from a lot of practice by now,
我當然知道，從 現在大量的實踐，
but might have flown over one's head for now.
但可能已飛過 在一個人的頭了。
And that's totally fine.
這是完全的罰款。
>> But, ultimately, you're going to start to see patterns emerge.
>> 但是，最終，你會 開始看到的模式出現。
And once you get past all of the stupid details, like parentheses,
而一旦你過去所有的 愚蠢的細節，比如括號，
and curly braces, and semi-colons, and the stuff, frankly,
和大括號和分號， 和東西，坦率地說，
that is not at all intellectually interesting.
這不是在所有的 智力有趣。
And it is not the objective of taking any introductory class.
它不是客觀 服用任何入門級。
It's the ideas that are going to matter.
它是將要事情的想法。
>> It's the loops, and the conditions, and the functions,
>> 它的循環，而 條件，以及功能，
and more powerfully the abstraction, and the factoring of code,
和更有力的抽象， 與上面的代碼保理，
and the good design, and the good style, and ultimately the correctness
和良好的設計，以及良好的 風格，最終的正確性
of your code, that's ultimately going to matter the most.
你的代碼，這是最終 事情影響最大。
So next week, we will take these ideas that we first saw in Scratch
所以下週，我們將採取以下 想法，我們第一次看到划痕
and have now translated to C. And we'll start
現在已經翻譯 到C.我們將開始
to introduce the first of the course's real world domains.
引進第一的 當然，真實世界的領域。
>> We'll focus on the world of security, and more specifically cryptography,
>> 我們將專注於安全領域， 更具體密碼學，
the art of scrambling information.
藝術擾碼信息。
And among the first problems you yourself
和第一批 你自己的問題，你
will get to write beyond playing with some of the syntax
將得到超越寫 與一些語法的打
and solving some logical problems, ultimately before long,
和解決一些邏輯 問題，最終沒多久，
is to actually scramble, or encrypt, and ultimately decrypt information.
是真正爭我奪，或加密， 並最終解密信息。
And everything we've done today, will fairly low
而我們所做的一切 今天，將相當低
level, is just going to allow us to take one, and one,
的水平，只是要允許 我們採取之一，和一，
and one more step above toward writing the most interesting code yet.
以上朝著一個步驟 寫作最有趣的代碼呢。
>> So more on that next week.
>> 因此，更多的是在下週。
>> [VIDEO PLAYBACK]
>> [視頻回放]
>> -What can you tell me about the last time you saw him?
>>  - 什麼，你能告訴我 您看見他是什麼時候？
-What can I say, really?
- 什麼我可以說，真的嗎？
I mean, it was like any other pre-production rehearsal,
我的意思是，它像任何其他 生產前的排練，
except there was something he said at the very end that stuck with me.
但有些事情，他說 在最後與我卡住了。
>> -This was CS50.
>>  - 這是CS50。
>> -That's a cut everyone, great job on rehearsal.
>>  - 那是一個切大家， 在排練偉大的工作。
>> -That's lunch?
>>  - 這就是午餐？
>> -Yeah, you and I can grab a sandwich in a bit.
>> 是啊，你和我可以 搶位三明治。
Let me just debrief with David really quickly.
我只是聽取匯報 大衛真的很快。
David?
大衛？
>> [END PLAYBACK]
>> [結束播放]